<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/4/2018 5:40:00 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Vermont</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_DESC">
			<Text>Vermont Republic</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SAS_VERMONT_TEXT">
			<Text>Your Boys salute you, Commandant Ethan Allen, hero of the Vermonters! When the land you and your compatriots called home, Vermont, was handed over to New York by the courts and your own land grants rendered void, you organized an armed resistance. Calling yourselves the Green Mountain Boys, you drove away encroaching settlers from New York to protect the lands which you knew to rightfully be your own. And when the first shots of the American Revolution were fired, you and  your Boys marched to Fort Ticonderoga alongside a band of patriots, taking the British garrison by complete surprise and seizing the fort without any casualties. As the war continued, you eventually lost command of the Boys, but continued fighting until your capture in 1775. Imprisoned for 3 years, you returned to find much had changed; your beloved Vermont had achieved independence, and she welcomed you back as a hero.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Commander Allen, Vermont needs you to rally the Boys once more, to secure freedom and unity. Will you bring peace and prosperity to Vermont, or shall you wield her military might against those who encroach upon you? Can you build a Civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Vermont</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_VERMONT_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_VERMONT_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Vermont Republic is a term used by historians to refer to the government of Vermont that existed from 1777 to 1791. In January 1777, delegates from 28 towns met and declared independence from the jurisdictions and land claims both of the British colony of Quebec and of the American states of New Hampshire and New York. They also abolished adult slavery within their boundaries. Many people in Vermont took part in the American Revolution, although the Continental Congress did not recognize the jurisdiction as independent. Because of vehement objections from New York, which had conflicting property claims, the Continental Congress declined to recognize Vermont, then known as the New Hampshire Grants. Vermont's overtures to join the British Province of Quebec failed. In 1791, Vermont officially joined the United States as the 14th state.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Leader-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN">
			<Text>Ethan Allen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Ethan Allen was born in Litchfield, Connecticut, the first-born child of Joseph and Mary Baker Allen, both descended from English Puritans. The family moved to the town of Cornwall shortly after his birth. The move to Cornwall grew out of Allen's father's quest for freedom of religion during a time of turmoil: the Great Awakening, when Puritans were separating into churches with differing dogmas, in particular about the proper form of conversion: by works or by grace. His lifelong interest in philosophy and ideas emerged against the backdrop of his father's involvement in these Puritan debates and his father's refusal to convert to the covenant by grace. As a boy, Allen already excelled at quoting the Bible and was known for disputing the meaning of passages.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Seven siblings, all of whom survived to adulthood, joined the family between Allen's birth in 1738 and 1751. Allen had five brothers (Heman, Heber, Levi, Zimri, and Ira) and two sisters (Lydia and Lucy). His brothers Ira and Heman would also become prominent figures in the early history of Vermont.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Although not very much is known about Allen's childhood, the town of Cornwall was frontier territory in the 1740s. By the time Allen reached his teens, the area, while still a difficult area in which to make a living, began to resemble a town, with wood-frame houses beginning to replace the rough cabins of the early settlers. Joseph Allen died in 1755; at the time of his death he was one of the wealthier landowners in the area, ran a successful farm, and had previously served as town selectman. Allen had, before his father's death, begun studies under a minister in the nearby town of Salisbury with the goal of gaining admission to Yale College. Allen's brother Ira recalled that, even at a young age, Allen was curious and interested in learning.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Allen was forced to end his studies upon his father's death. While he volunteered for militia service in 1757 in response to French movements resulting in the siege of Fort William Henry, his unit received word while en route that the fort had fallen, and turned back. Even though the French and Indian War continued over the next several years, Allen did not apparently participate in any further military activities, and is presumed to have tended his farm, at least until 1762. In that year, he became part owner of an iron furnace in Salisbury. He also married Mary Brownson, a woman five years his senior, from the nearby town of Roxbury, in July 1762. They first settled in Cornwall, but moved the following year to Salisbury with their infant daughter Loraine. Allen bought a small farm and proceeded to develop the iron works. The expansion of the iron works was apparently costly to Allen; he was forced to sell off portions of the Cornwall property to raise funds, and eventually sold half of his interest in the works to his brother Heman. The Allen brothers sold their interest in the iron works in October of 1765. By most accounts Allen's first marriage was an unhappy one. His wife was rigidly religious, prone to criticizing him, and barely able to read and write. In contrast, Allen's behavior was sometimes quite flamboyant; and he maintained an interest in learning. In spite of these differences the marriage survived until Mary's death in 1783. Allen and Mary had five children together (Loraine, Joseph, Lucy, Mary, and Pamela), only two of whom reached adulthood.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Allen's exploits in those years introduced him to the wrong side of the justice system, which would become a recurring feature of his life. In one incident, he and his brother Heman went to the farm of a neighbor, some of whose pigs had escaped onto their land, and seized the pigs. The neighbor sued to have the animals returned to him; Allen pleaded his own case, and lost. Allen and Heman were fined ten shillings, and the neighbor was awarded another five shillings in damages. He was also called to court in Salisbury for inoculating himself against smallpox, a procedure that at the time required the sanction of the town selectmen. When he moved to Salisbury, Allen met Thomas Young, a doctor living and practicing just across the provincial boundary in New York. The doctor, only five years older than Allen, taught the younger Allen a great deal about philosophy and political theory, while Allen was able to bring to Young his appreciation of nature and life on the frontier. Young and Allen eventually decided to collaborate on a book intended to be an attack on organized religion, as Young had convinced Allen to become a Deist. They worked on the manuscript until 1764, when Young moved away from the area, taking the manuscript with him.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It was not until many years later, after Young's death, that Allen was able to recover the manuscript. He expanded and reworked the material, and eventually published it as Reason: the Only Oracle of Man.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>The New Hampshire Grants</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>As early as 1749, Benning Wentworth, New Hampshire's governor, was selling land grants in the area west of the Connecticut River, to which New Hampshire had always laid somewhat dubious claim. Many of these grants were sold at relatively low prices to land speculators, with some land kicked back to Wentworth. In 1764, King George issued an order resolving the competing claims of New York and New Hampshire in favor of New York. New York, which had also issued land grants that overlapped some of those sold by Wentworth, insisted that holders of the Wentworth grants pay a fee to New York to have their grants validated. As this fee approached the original purchase price, and many of the holders were land-rich and cash-poor, there was a great deal of resistance to this demand. By 1769 the situation in the Grants had deteriorated to the point where surveyors and other figures of New York authority were being physically threatened and driven from the area.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]A few of the holders of Wentworth grants were originally from northwestern Connecticut; and some of them, including Remember Baker and Seth Warner, were relatives of Allen. In 1770, a group of Wentworth grant holders asked Allen to defend their case before New York's Supreme Court, a move that presented Allen with his first big stage. This move to leadership was not unusual; he was known among his contemporaries to be willing to step forward and take control. The trial, for which Allen hired Jared Ingersoll to represent the grantholder interest, began in July 1770, pitting Allen against politically powerful New York grant-holders, including New York's Lieutenant Governor Colden, James Duane (who was prosecuting the case), and Robert Livingston, the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court (who was presiding over the case). The trial was brief, and the outcome unsurprising, as the court, citing their fraudulently issued nature, refused to allow the introduction of Wentworth's grants as evidence. Before departing for Bennington with the news, Allen was visited by Duane, who offered Allen payments which Duane described in his diary as payment "for going among the people to quiet them". Allen denied taking any money; even if he did, none of his actions appeared to honor Duane's request. According to Allen's account he was outraged, and left his visitors with veiled threats, indicating that attempts to enforce the judgment would be met with resistance.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]While many historians have believed that Allen took these actions because he already held Wentworth grants of his own, there is no evidence that he was issued any such grants until after he had been asked to take up the defense of grants held by others. Between May 1770, when he first began working on the defense, and the trial in July, he acquired, for the price of $50, grants from Wentworth to about 1,000 acres of land in Poultney and Castleton.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Green Mountain Boys</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>On Allen's return to Bennington, the settlers met at the Catamount Tavern to discuss their options. These discussions resulted in the formation of the Green Mountain Boys in 1770, with local militia companies in each of the surrounding towns. Allen was named their Colonel Commandant, and cousins Seth Warner and Remember Baker were captains of two of the companies. Further meetings resulted in the creation of committees of safety, and laid down rules by which to resist attempts by the New York provincial government to establish its authority. These included denying surveyors sent by the province the ability to survey any land in the Grants, not just land owned through the Wentworth grants.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Friction with the provincial government rose notably when, in October 1771, Allen and a company of Boys drove off a group of Scottish settlers near Rupert. Allen detained two of the settlers and forced them to watch the torching of their newly constructed cabins. He then ordered them to leave, saying, "Go your way now, and complain to that damned scoundrel your Governor, God damn your Governor, Laws, King, Council, and Assembly". When the settlers protested his language Allen continued the tirade, threatening to send any troops from New York to Hell. In response, New York's governor, William Tryon, issued warrants for the arrests of those responsible, and eventually put a price of £20 on the heads of six participants, including Allen. Allen and his comrades countered by issuing offers of their own.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Over the next few years the situation deteriorated further. Governor Tryon and the Boys exchanged threats, truce offers, and other writings, which were frequently written by Allen in florid and didactic language, while the Boys continued to drive surveyors and incoming tenants on New York-granted lands away. Most of these incidents did not involve bloodshed, although individuals were at times manhandled, and the Boys sometimes did extensive property damage when driving tenants out. By March 1774, the harsh treatment of settlers and their property by Allen and the Boys prompted Tryon to increase some of the rewards to £100. Allen persisted with actions against the New York-issued grantholders and their tenants even though a number of the Wentworth proprietors were tiring of the business. In 1772 he, his cousin Remember Baker; and his brothers Ira, Heman, and Zimri formed the Onion River Company, which was basically a land-speculation organization devoted to purchasing land in and around the Winooski River (known then as the Onion River). The success of this business depended on the successful defense of the Wentworth grants. Early purchases of the company included about 40,000 acres of land from Edward Burling and his partners; land was sold at a profit to Thomas Chittenden among others, and the settlements on the company's land have grown to become the city of Burlington.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The outrage of the Wentworth proprietors was renewed in 1774 when Governor Tryon passed a law containing harsh provisions clearly targeted at the actions of the "Bennington Mob". Vermont historian Samuel Williams called it "an act which for its savage barbarity is probably without parallel in the legislation of any civilized country". Its provisions included the penalty of death for interfering with a magistrate, and the criminalization of meetings of more than three people "for unlawful purposes" in the Grants. The Boys countered with rules of their own, forbidding anyone in the Grants from holding "any office of honor or profit under the colony of N. York". Allen spent much of the summer of 1774 writing a "pamphlet" entitled A Brief Narrative of the Proceedings of the Government of New York Relative to Their Obtaining the Jurisdiction of that Large District of Land to the Westward of the Connecticut River. The length of the name was justified; it was a 200-page polemic arguing the position of the Wentworth proprietors. Allen had the work, which historian Charles Jellison describes as "rebellion in print", printed in Connecticut, and began selling and giving away copies in early 1775.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Allen traveled into the northern parts of the Grants early in 1775, as was his custom, for solitude and to hunt for game and land opportunities. A few days after his return, news came that blood had finally been shed over the land disputes. Most of the resistance activity had until then taken place on the west side of the Green Mountains; on March 13, a small riot in the shire town of Westminster, on the east side of the mountains, resulted in the death of two men. Allen and a troop of Boys traveled to Westminster where, under Allen's influence, the town's convention adopted a strongly worded resolution authorizing the drafting of a plea to the King to remove them "out of so oppressive a jurisdiction". The preparation of the petition was assigned to a committee which included Allen. Less than a week after the Westminster convention ended, while Allen and the committee worked on their petition, the American Revolutionary War began.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Capture of Fort Ticonderoga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>In late April, following the battles of Lexington and Concord, Allen received a message from members of an irregular Connecticut militia that they were planning to capture Fort Ticonderoga, requesting his assistance in the effort. Allen, whether motivated by patriotic impulses (as he describes in his account of the events), or by the realization that the action might improve the political position of his side in the grants disputes, agreed to help, and began rounding up the Green Mountain Boys. On May 2, 60 men from Massachusetts and Connecticut met with Allen in Bennington, where they discussed the logistics of the expedition. By May 7, these men joined Allen and 130 Boys at Castleton. The next morning, Allen was elected to lead the expedition, and a dawn raid was planned for May 10. Two small companies were detached to procure boats, and Allen took the main contingent north to Hand's Cove in Shoreham to prepare for the crossing. On the afternoon of May 9, Benedict Arnold quite unexpectedly arrived on the scene. Flourishing a commission from the Massachusetts Committee of Safety, he asserted his right to command the expedition. The assembled men refused to acknowledge his authority, insisting they would follow only Allen's lead. In a private discussion, Allen and Arnold reached an accommodation, the essence of which was that Arnold and Allen would both be at the front of the troops when the attack on the fort was made.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Around 2:00 a.m., a few boats were finally procured for the crossing. However, only 83 men made it to the other side of the lake before Allen and Arnold, concerned that dawn was approaching, decided to attack. In the early dawn, the small force marched on the fort, surprising the lone sentry. Allen went directly to the fort commander's quarters, seeking to force his surrender. Lieutenant Jocelyn Feltham, the assistant to the fort's commander, Captain William Delaplace, was awakened by the noise, and called to wake the captain. Stalling for time, he demanded to know by what authority the fort was being entered. Allen, who later claimed that he said it to Captain Delaplace, said, "In the name of the Great Jehovah and the Continental Congress!" Delaplace finally emerged from his chambers, fully dressed, and surrendered his sword. The rest of the fort's garrison surrendered without firing a shot. The only casualty had been a British soldier who became concussed after Allen hit the soldier with a cutlass, hitting the man's hair comb and saving his life. While Allen's claimed quote has become iconic, some historians dispute its accuracy. Other reports indicate that he initially declared: "Come out of there you sons of British whores, or I'll smoke you out!" According to historian and folklorist B.A. Botkin, one Israel Harris was present at the time, and later told his grandson (the late Professor James D. Butler of Madison, Wisconsin) that Allen's actual words were "Come out of there, you goddamn old rat!"[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]On the following day, a detachment of the Boys under Seth Warner's command went to nearby Fort Crown Point and captured the small garrison there. On May 14, following the arrival of 100 men recruited by Arnold's captains, and the arrival of a schooner and some bateaux that had been taken at Skenesboro, Arnold and 50 of his men sailed north to raid Fort St. John, on the Richelieu River downstream from the lake, where a small British warship was reported by the prisoners to be anchored. Arnold's raid was a success; he seized the sloop HMS Royal George, supplies, and a number of bateaux. Allen, shortly after Arnold's departure on the raid, decided, after his successes at the southern end of the lake, to take and hold Fort St. John himself. To that end, he and about 100 Boys climbed into four bateaux, and began rowing north. After two days without significant food (which they had forgotten to provision in the boats), Allen's small fleet met Arnold's on its way back to Ticonderoga near the foot of the lake. Arnold generously opened his stores to Allen's hungry men, and tried to dissuade Allen from his objective, noting that it was likely the alarm had been raised and troops were on their way to St. John. Allen, likely both stubborn in his determination, and envious of Arnold, persisted.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When Allen and his men landed above St. John and scouted the situation, they learned that a column of 200 or more regulars was approaching. Rather than attempt an ambush on those troops, which significantly outnumbered his tired company, Allen withdrew to the other side of the river, where the men collapsed with exhaustion and slept without sentries through the night. They were awakened when British sentries discovered them and began firing grapeshot at them from across the river. The Boys, in a panic, piled into their bateaux and rowed with all speed upriver. When the expedition returned to Ticonderoga two days later, some of the men were greatly disappointed that they had nothing to show for the effort and risks they took. The capture of Fort Ticonderoga and Crown Point proved to be crucial in the Revolutionary War because it secured protection from the British to the North and provided vital cannon for the colonial army; some even speculate that if the attempts to capture the two forts had been unsuccessful, the colonists might not have won the war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_LIVED">
			<Text>1738 - 1789 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_NAME">
			<Text>Ethan Allen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Vermont</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_ETHANALLEN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Colonel Commandant of the Green Mountain Boys</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Trait-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GREEN_MOUNTAINS_SHORT">
			<Text>These Green Mountains</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GREEN_MOUNTAINS">
			<Text>Forest tiles in or near your territory may spawn [ICON_RES_SAS_MAPLE] Maple, a unique bonus resource which yields [ICON_CULTURE] Culture. Cutting down a Forest tile with Maple provides extra [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to the nearest city, but removes the Maple.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_SAS_MAPLE">
			<Text>Maple</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_SAS_MAPLE_TEXT">
			<Text>Acer saccharum, also known as the Sugar Maple or Rock Maple, is a species of maple tree native to the hardwood forests of eastern Canada and the northern parts of the Central and Eastern United States. Sugar maple is best known for its bright fall foliage and for being the primary source of maple syrup, but it can also be used as timber. Bowling alleys and bowling pins are both commonly manufactured from sugar maple. Trees with wavy woodgrain, which can occur in curly, quilted, and "birdseye maple" forms, are especially valued. Maple is also the wood used for basketball courts, including the floors used by the NBA, and it is a popular wood for baseball bats, along with white ash. It is also widely used in the manufacture of musical instruments, such as the members of the violin family (sides and back), guitars (neck), and drum shells. The Sugar Maple is the official State Tree of Vermont.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_SAS_SYRUP">
			<Text>Syrup</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_SAS_SYRUP_TEXT">
			<Text>Maple syrup is a syrup usually made from the xylem sap of sugar maple, red maple, or black maple trees, although it can also be made from other maple species. In cold climates, these trees store starch in their trunks and roots before winter; the starch is then converted to sugar that rises in the sap in late winter and early spring. Maple trees are tapped by drilling holes into their trunks and collecting the exuded sap, which is processed by heating to evaporate much of the water, leaving the sweet, concentrated, syrup. Maple syrup is often used as a condiment for pancakes, waffles, French toast, oatmeal or porridge. It is also used as an ingredient in baking and as a sweetener or flavouring agent. Culinary experts have praised its unique flavour, although the chemistry responsible is not fully understood. Vermont is the largest maple syrup producer in the United States, and was formerly the largest producer in the world, until being surpassed by Canada in the 1990s.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Oplot-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_GREENMOUNTAINBOY">
			<Text>Green Mountain Boy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_SAS_GREENMOUNTAINBOY">
			<Text>Unique Musketman for Vermont which gains a 25% Combat Bonus against Fortified enemy units. Additionally, it will temporarily claim any Forts, Citadels, or neutral tiles it enters for Vermont.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_GREENMOUNTAINBOY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Replacing the Musketman, it is stronger when fighting Fortified units and claims any Forts, Citadels, or neutral tiles it enters. Use them to patrol unclaimed frontiers in times of peace and protect valuable land from foreign expansion. In times of war, use them to take control of the enemy's own fortifications and turn the tides of battle!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_GREENMOUNTAINBOY_TEXT">
			<Text>The Green Mountain Boys was a militia organization first established in the late 1760s in the territory known as the New Hampshire Grants, and later as the Vermont Republic. Headed by Ethan Allen and members of his extended family, it was instrumental in resisting New York's attempts to control the territory, over which it had won de jure control in a territorial dispute with New Hampshire. Some companies served in the American Revolutionary War, including notably when the Green Mountain Boys led by Ethan Allen captured Fort Ticonderoga on Lake Champlain on May 10, 1775; and invaded Canada later in 1775. In early June 1775, Ethan Allen and his then subordinate, Seth Warner, induced the Continental Congress at Philadelphia to create a Continental Army ranger regiment from the then New Hampshire Grants. Having no treasury, the Congress directed that New York's revolutionary Congress pay for the newly authorized regiment. In July 1775, Allen's militia was granted support from the New York revolutionary Congress. The remnants of the Green Mountain Boys militia were largely reconstituted as the Green Mountain Continental Rangers. Command of the newly-formed regiment passed from Allen to Seth Warner. Under Warner, the regiment fought at the battles of Hubbardton and Bennington in 1777. The regiment was disbanded in 1779. However, the Green Mountain Boys mustered again during the War of 1812, the Civil War, the Spanish–American War, the Vietnam War, the Afghanistan war and the Iraq War. Today, it is the informal name of the Vermont National Guard, which comprises both the Army and Air National Guards.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_JEHOVAH">
			<Text>Authority Of Jehovah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_JEHOVAH_HELP">
			<Text>Bonus vs Fortified Units (25%)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_CONGRESS">
			<Text>Authority of the Continental Congress</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_CONGRESS_HELP">
			<Text>Will temporarily claim Citadels, Forts, or any neutral tile for Vermont.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Maidan-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_TAPHOUSE">
			<Text>Tap House</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_TAPHOUSE_PEDIA">
			<Text>A Tap House, also known as a Tavern, is a place of business where people gather to drink alcoholic beverages and be served food, and in most cases, where travelers receive lodging. Taverns in Vermont and across colonial America served many important functions; as a place to trade or do business, and as meeting places, community centers, impromptu courthouses, and even mail stops or post offices. In particular, the Catamount Tavern in Bennington, Vermont, was where Ethan Allen's Green Mountain Boys first formed, and served as their headquarters. David Redding, a member of the Queen's Rangers, was tried and hung there for the crime of horse theft. And in Elijah West's Windsor Tavern, in Windsor, Vermont, the Constitution of Vermont was written and signed on July 8, 1777. The Windsor Tavern continued to function as a tavern until 1848 when it was converted into a storage space, but today, has been restored as the Old Constitution House, a museum which approximates a tavern with period-accurate rooms.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_TAPHOUSE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>A unique Windmill for Vermont, the Tap House grants the same [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production bonuses as the building it replaces. However, it also grants 1 copy of the unique [ICON_RES_SAS_SYRUP] Syrup luxury resource for each 2 [ICON_RES_SAS_MAPLE] Maple resources improved near this city, and each source of [ICON_RES_WINE] Wine or [ICON_RES_WHEAT] Wheat worked by this city yields an additional +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_SAS_SYRUP_SHORT">
			<Text>1 [ICON_RES_SAS_SYRUP] Syrup</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_9">
			<Text>Ira</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_8">
			<Text>Seth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_7">
			<Text>Remember</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_6">
			<Text>Jabez</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_5">
			<Text>Ebenezer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_4">
			<Text>Elishama</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_3">
			<Text>Rowley</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_2">
			<Text>Moses</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_1">
			<Text>Heman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_VERMONT_0">
			<Text>Chellis</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!--City Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_1">
			<Text>Windsor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_2">
			<Text>Montpelier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_3">
			<Text>Burlington</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_4">
			<Text>Rutland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_5">
			<Text>Colchester</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_6">
			<Text>Bennington</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_7">
			<Text>Brattleboro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_8">
			<Text>Castleton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_9">
			<Text>Essex</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_10">
			<Text>Milton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_11">
			<Text>Hartford</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_12">
			<Text>Barre</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_13">
			<Text>Williston</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_14">
			<Text>Winooski</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_15">
			<Text>Middlebury</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_16">
			<Text>Newport</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_17">
			<Text>St. Albans</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_18">
			<Text>St. Johnsbury</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_19">
			<Text>Shelburne</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_20">
			<Text>Vergennes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_21">
			<Text>Swanton</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_22">
			<Text>Springfield</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_23">
			<Text>Northfield</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_24">
			<Text>Lyndon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_25">
			<Text>Rockingham</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_26">
			<Text>Morristown</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_27">
			<Text>Waterbury</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_28">
			<Text>Randolph</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_29">
			<Text>Derby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_VERMONT_30">
			<Text>Bristol</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Dialogue -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_SAS_VERMONT_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now drenching their pancakes in maple syrup and eating your ice cream by the gallon. I worry the rest of the world will soon succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Welcome to Vermont, traveller. Would you care to join my Boys and I for a meeting at the local tavern later? I plan to read aloud some of my writings!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>If you're another settler from New York, prepare yourself for a beating before we throw you back over the border! If you're just visiting though... then welcome to Vermont!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>I say, a new leader on this diplomatic scene? I hope for all's sake that you are a friend of freedom and equality, lest you find yourself at odds with myself and the men around you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Ever since I arrived to a state of manhood, I have felt a sincere passion for liberty. The history of nations like yours, doomed to perpetual slavery, in consequence of yielding up to tyrants like you their natural born liberties, fills me with great horror. Hang me if you will, but I beg you to be merciful to my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>As long as man may live, no tyrant can ever crush the spirit of liberty. Do with me as you will, but your war shall never end, and you shall never win.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>It is bad policy to fear the resentment of an enemy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Absolutely not! We paid well for those land grants, and the land is rightfully ours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Very well, I suppose we can respect those claims if you'll respect ours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Welcome back, my friend. Here to listen to me read my new polemic aloud?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>Your lands rightfully belong to my countrymen. Prepare to have them liberated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>The gods of the valley are not the gods of the hills, and you shall understand that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_2">
			<Text>In the name of the Great Jehovah and the Continental Congress, surrender immediately!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>The gods of the valley are not the gods of the hills, and you shall understand that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_2">
			<Text>In the name of the Great Jehovah and the Continental Congress, surrender immediately!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>Although the task before me may be impossible, I am compelled to find a way to destroy you and all that you stand for. I will do so or die trying.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_DESPERATE_2">
			<Text>The gods of the valley are not the gods of the hills, and you shall understand that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_DESPERATE_3">
			<Text>You are a villain without equal. Within every fiber of my being, I know I must destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_DESPERATE_4">
			<Text>In the name of the Great Jehovah and the Continental Congress, surrender immediately!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_DESPERATE_5">
			<Text>The time to make a stand is now. The odds are not with me, but I find a way to destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>The gods of the valley are not the gods of the hills, and you shall understand that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_ETHANALLEN_DOW_BETRAYAL_2">
			<Text>In the name of the Great Jehovah and the Continental Congress, surrender immediately!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_SAS_ETHANALLEN">
			<Text>Ethan Allen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_SAS_REASON">
			<Text>Reason: The Only Oracle of Man</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_SAS_REASON">
			<Text>"An apology appears to me to be impertinent in welters who venture their works to public inspection, for this obvious reason, that if they need it, they should have been stifled in the birth, and not permitted a public existence. I therefore offer my composition to the candid judgment of the impartial world without it, taking it for granted that I have as good a natural right to expose myself to public censure, by endeavoring to subserve mankind, as any of the species who have published their productions since the creation; and I ask no favor at the hands of philosophers, divines or critics, but hope and expect they will severely chastise me for my errors and mistakes, least they may have a share in perverting the truth, which is very far from my intention."</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Decisions-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_VERMONT_SLAVERY">
			<Text>Abolish Slavery</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_VERMONT_SLAVERY_DESC">
			<Text>
				We enshrine the equality of men and their individual liberties in our society, yet there are those among us whose freedom is kept from them by their supposed masters. Slavery must not be allowed to exist in any nation that yearns to truly call itself free. We should Constitutionally abolish the tyranny of slavery, and put an end to this history of misery and injustice.
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Requirements:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Player must be Vermont
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must have enacted "Codify Laws" decision
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must have a Worker stationed in the Capital City
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May only be enacted once per game
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Costs:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]{2_Gold} [ICON_GOLD] Gold
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]2 [ICON_MAGISTRATES] Magistrates
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]All Workers stationed in cities are disbanded
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]All cities enter [ICON_RESISTANCE] Anarchy for 2 turns
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Rewards:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive {1_Culture} [ICON_CULTURE] and 100 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age Points per Worker disbanded by this decision
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]All Cultural Specialists and Unemployed Citizens yield +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture per turn
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_VERMONT_SLAVERY_ENACTED_DESC">
			<Text>
				We enshrine the equality of men and their individual liberties in our society, yet there are those among us whose freedom is kept from them by their supposed masters. Slavery must not be allowed to exist in any nation that yearns to truly call itself free. We should Constitutionally abolish the tyranny of slavery, and put an end to this history of misery and injustice.
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Rewards:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive {1_Culture} [ICON_CULTURE] and 100 [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age Points per Worker disbanded by this decision
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]All Cultural Specialists and Unemployed Citizens yield +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture per turn
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_VERMONT_BOOK">
			<Text>Publish a Philosophical Polemic</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_VERMONT_BOOK_DESC">
			<Text>
				Many years ago, when you were young, you worked on a manuscript with a friend of yours, whom passed away recently. The unfinished manuscript you worked on together targets the Church, the power of its priesthood, and organized religion as a whole, and promotes your beliefs in Deism and man's role as a free agent in the natural world. To finish and publish this work would surely attract controversy and ire from the faithful, but may inspire transcendental new schools of thought!
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Requirements:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Player must be Vermont
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must have researched Printing Press
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Your cities must follow a majority Religion
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May only be enacted once per game
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Costs:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]1 [ICON_MAGISTRATES] Magistrate
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]400 [ICON_GOLD] Gold
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]400 [ICON_PEACE] Faith
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Rewards:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive a free Great Writer
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]All [ICON_PEACE] Faith-providing buildings and buildings with Great Work of Writing slots yield +1 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_VERMONT_BOOK_ENACTED_DESC">
			<Text>
				Many years ago, when you were young, you worked on a manuscript with a friend of yours, whom passed away recently. The unfinished manuscript you worked on together targets the Church, the power of its priesthood, and organized religion as a whole, and promotes your beliefs in Deism and man's role as a free agent in the natural world. To finish and publish this work would surely attract controversy and ire from the faithful, but may inspire transcendental new schools of thought!
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Rewards:[ENDCOLOR]
				[NEWLINE]-------------------------
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive a free Great Writer
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]All [ICON_PEACE] Faith-providing buildings and buildings with Great Work of Writing slots yield +1 [ICON_RESEARCH] Science
			</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>