<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- City names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_1">
			<Text>Dublin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_2">
			<Text>Cork</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_3">
			<Text>Galway</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_4">
			<Text>Wexford</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_5">
			<Text>Kilkenny</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_6">
			<Text>Tralee</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_7">
			<Text>Limerick</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_8">
			<Text>Castlebar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_9">
			<Text>Lifford</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_10">
			<Text>Clonmel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_11">
			<Text>Ennis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_12">
			<Text>Roscommon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_13">
			<Text>Cavan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_14">
			<Text>Waterford</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_15">
			<Text>Nenagh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_16">
			<Text>Sligo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_17">
			<Text>Monaghan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_18">
			<Text>Naas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_19">
			<Text>Navan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_20">
			<Text>Dundalk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_21">
			<Text>Carrick-on-Shannon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_22">
			<Text>Wicklow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_23">
			<Text>Tullamore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_24">
			<Text>Mullingar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_25">
			<Text>Portlaoighise</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_26">
			<Text>Swords</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_27">
			<Text>Bray</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_28">
			<Text>Carlow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_29">
			<Text>Armagh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_30">
			<Text>Ballina</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_31">
			<Text>Letterkenny</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_32">
			<Text>Athlone</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_33">
			<Text>Celbridge</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_0">
			<Text>Patrick</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_1">
			<Text>James</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_2">
			<Text>Thomas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_3">
			<Text>Michael</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_4">
			<Text>William</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_5">
			<Text>Timothy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_6">
			<Text>Dennis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_7">
			<Text>Margaret</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_8">
			<Text>Bridget</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_IRELAND_9">
			<Text>Ann</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!-- Ireland -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND">
			<Text>Irish Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_SHORT">
			<Text>Ireland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_US_IRELAND_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Irish</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Ireland is an island in the North Atlantic. It is separated from Great Britain to its east by the North Channel, the Irish Sea, and St George's Channel. Ireland is the second-largest island of the British Isles, the third-largest in Europe, and the twentieth-largest on Earth. Irish culture has had a significant influence on other cultures, especially in the field of literature. Alongside mainstream Western culture, a strong indigenous culture exists, as expressed through Gaelic games, Irish music and the Irish language.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Geography and Climate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The geography of Ireland comprises relatively low-lying mountains surrounding a central plain, with several navigable rivers extending inland. Its lush vegetation is a product of its mild but changeable climate which is free of extremes in temperature. The Irish climate is influenced by the Atlantic Ocean and thus very moderate, and winters are milder than expected for such a northerly area, although summers are cooler than those in continental Europe. Rainfall and cloud cover are abundant.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Pre-Christian Era</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The pre-Christian era in Ireland is known chiefly through legend, although there is archaeological evidence of habitation during the Stone and Bronze ages. In about the 4th century bc, the tall, red-haired Celts from Gaul or Galicia arrived, bringing with them the Iron Age. They subdued the Picts in the north and the Érainn tribe in the south, then settled down to establish a Gaelic civilization, absorbing many of the traditions of the previous inhabitants. By the 3rd century ad, the Gaels had established five permanent kingdoms—Ulster, Connacht, Leinster, Meath (North Leinster), and Munster—with a high king, whose title was often little more than honorary, at Tara. After St. Patrick's arrival in ad 432, Christian Ireland rapidly became a center of Latin and Gaelic learning. Irish monasteries drew not only the pious but also the intellectuals of the day, and sent out missionaries to many parts of Europe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The English Crown</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Toward the end of the 8th century, the Vikings began their invasions, destroying monasteries and wreaking havoc on the land, but also intermarrying, adopting Irish customs, and establishing coastal settlements from which have grown Ireland's chief cities. Viking power was finally broken at the Battle of Clontarf in 1014. About 150 years later, the Anglo-Norman invasions began. Gradually, the invaders gained control of the whole country. Many of them intermarried, adopted the Irish language, customs, and traditions, and became more Irish than the Gaels. But the political attachment to the English crown instituted by the Norman invasion caused almost 800 years of strife, as successive English monarchs sought to subdue Gaels and Norman-Irish alike. Wholesale confiscations of land and large plantations of English colonists began under Mary I (Mary Tudor) and continued under Elizabeth I, Cromwell, and William III. Treatment of the Irish reached a brutal climax in the 18th century with the Penal Laws, which deprived Catholics and Dissenters (the majority of the population) of all legal rights.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Catholic Emancipation and the Great Famine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_5">
			<Text>By the end of the 18th century, many of the English colonists had come to regard themselves as Irish and, like the English colonists in America, resented the domination of London and their own lack of power to rule themselves. In 1783, they forced the establishment of an independent Irish parliament, but it was abolished by the Act of Union (1800), which gave Ireland direct representation in Westminster. Catholic emancipation was finally achieved in 1829 through the efforts of Daniel O'Connell, but the great famine of the 1840s, when millions died or emigrated for lack of potatoes while landlords continued to export other crops to England, emphasized the tragic condition of the Irish peasant and the great need for land reform.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Desire for Independence</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_6">
			<Text>A series of uprisings and the growth of various movements aimed at home rule or outright independence led gradually to many reforms, but the desire for complete independence continued to grow. After the bloodshed and political maneuvers that followed the Easter Uprising of 1916 and the proclamation of an Irish Republic by Irish members of Parliament in 1919, the Anglo-Irish Treaty was signed in 1921, establishing an Irish Free State with dominion status in the British Commonwealth. Violent opposition to dominion status and to a separate government in Protestant-dominated Northern Ireland precipitated a civil war lasting almost a year. The Free State was officially proclaimed and a new constitution adopted in 1922, but sentiment in favor of a reunified Irish Republic remained strong, represented at its extreme by the terrorist activities of the Irish Republican Army (IRA). Powerful at first, the IRA lost much of its popularity after Éamon de Valera, a disillusioned supporter, took over the government in 1932. During the civil violence that disrupted Northern Ireland from the late 1960s on, the Irish government attempted to curb the "provisional wing" of the IRA, a terrorist organization that used Ireland as a base for attacks in the north. Beginning in 1976, the government assumed emergency powers to cope with IRA activities, but the terrorist acts continued, most notably the assassination on 27 August 1979 of the British Earl Mountbatten.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Peace Negotiations and Northern Ireland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_7">
			<Text>The Irish government continued to favor union with Northern Ireland, but only by peaceful means. In November 1985, with the aim of promoting peace in Northern Ireland, Ireland and the United Kingdom ratified a treaty enabling Ireland to play a role in various aspects of Northern Ireland's affairs. On 10 April 1998 the Irish Republic jointly signed a peace agreement with the United Kingdom to resolve the Northern Ireland crisis. Ireland pledged to amend articles 2 and 3 of the Irish Constitution, which lay claim to the territory of the North, in return for the United Kingdom promising to amend the Government of Ireland Act. On 22 May 1998, 94.4% of the electorate voted in a referendum to drop Ireland's claim to Northern Ireland. A year after the agreement, several key provisions of the Good Friday Agreement had been implemented. The peace process has since then witnessed long moments of gloom in spite of the ongoing involvements of the British and Irish prime ministers to resolve the situation in Northern Ireland. One of the largest obstacles was the disarmament of the IRA and the reservations on the part of the Ulster Unionists to share power with Sinn Feìn, the political arm of the IRA. Finally, in May 2000, the IRA proposed that outside observers be shown the contents of arms dumps and reinspect them at regular intervals to ensure that weaponry had not been removed and was back in circulation. The Ulster Unionists agreed to power-sharing arrangements and to endorse devolution of Northern Ireland. Decommissioning of the IRA did not progress in early 2001, however, and David Trimble, the first minister of the power-sharing government, resigned in July 2001. Sinn Feìn's offices at Stormont, the Northern Ireland Assembly, were raided by the police in October 2002, due to spying allegations. On 14 October 2002, devolution was suspended and direct rule from London returned to Northern Ireland. Elections planned for the assembly in May 2003 were indefinitely postponed by British Prime Minister Tony Blair, due to a lack of evidence of peaceful intentions on the part of the IRA. Talks aimed at restoring devolved government in 2004 failed due to the continued IRA possession of illegal arms and its refusal to disband and pull out of illegal activities. Progress did not look eminent as of January 2005, when some IRA members were brutally murdered and the provisional government seemed to make attempts to protect those responsible for the murders from prosecution.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Irish factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_US_IRELAND_TEXT_8">
			<Text>[ICON_BULLET]The Irish consume in average 131.1 liters of beer per year - the 2nd highest per-capita consumption after the Czech Republic.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]88% of Irish citizens are nominally Roman Catholic. The Republic of Ireland has one of the highest rates of church attendance in the Western World (around 45% of regular Mass attendance).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Many Irish family names start with "Mac" or "O'...", which means respectively "son of ..." and "grandson of ..." in Gaelic.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Ireland has had its own Olympics since the Bronze Age. The Tailteann Games (Aonach Tailteann), as they were known, were athletic contests held in honor of the deceased goddess Tailtiu, Lugh's wife. Although historically attested games were held from the 6th to the 12th century CE, it is claimed that the origins of the Tailteann Games go back to 632 BCE, or even as far as 1600 BCE (against 776 BCE for the ancient Greek Olympic Games). Modern revival of the games have been held since 1924.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Michael Collins -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS">
			<Text>Michael Collins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS_TEXT_1">
			<Text></Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS_NAME">
			<Text>Míceál Ó Coileáin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Ireland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Chairman of the Provisional Government</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_MICHAEL_COLLINS_LIVED">
			<Text>1890 - 1922</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_US_IRELAND_TEXT">
			<Text>Few can boast your patriotism and commitment to the cause of a Free Ireland, Commander Collins. Though you came from the humblest of beginnings, you truly embodied the pride of Irishness. It was not long before you joined the struggle for Home Rule, and you began to build a reputation for yourself – one of dedication, devotion, and pride for Ireland. After the Easter Rising turned bloody, you managed to turn a beaten movement into a potent physical force: One that would successfully found an Irish nation, fight a war for liberation, and win independence. Some did not share your view, however, and soon this incomplete nation descended once more into war. And though you paid the ultimate cost in the subsequent civil war, you gave your life for a free state that was established soon after.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Michael Collins, Ireland looks to you again for guidance in a new time of hardship. Will you serve once more for your nation and your people? Will you overcome those that mean to shackle you? Will you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- August Destiny -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SHORT">
			<Text>August Destiny</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_US_AUGUST_DESTINY">
			<Text>Irish [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Works continue to grant half of their yields while in the Cities of other Civilizations, and bonus Defense while in Irish Cities. Cities with a garrison receive a free cultural Specialist, depending on the Unit's level.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Public House -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE">
			<Text>Public House</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_TEXT">
			<Text>INSERT_TEXT_HERE</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Irish Zoo replacement. INSERT_TEXT_HERE.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Yields no [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness, but has a free slot for a Great Work of Music, which grants +2 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness when filled and +2 [ICON_GREAT_MUSICIAN] Great Musician points if the City is working a source of Wheat or Wine. Pubs may appear in the Cities of Civilizations you are influencing culturally, yielding +1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness for Ireland and the City owner, and +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture and [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism for Ireland. Only the Irish may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Public House: Foreign Civ version -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HAPPINESS_FOREIGN_CIVS">
			<Text>Public House</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HAPPINESS_FOREIGN_CIVS_TEXT">
			<Text>INSERT_TEXT_HERE+Something about this being the Irish UB automatically constructed in this city due to its abilities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HAPPINESS_FOREIGN_CIVS_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Irish Zoo replacement that can appear in the Cities of Civilizations under Irish Influence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HAPPINESS_FOREIGN_CIVS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Yields +1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness, and cost has no Maintenance Cost. This Building may automatically be constructed in Cities over which Ireland is Influential.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Fenian -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_FENIAN">
			<Text>Fenian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_US_FENIAN_TEXT">
			<Text>Fenian is an umbrella term for the Fenian Brotherhood and Irish Reublican Brotherhood (IRB), fraternal organisations dedicated to the establishment of an independent Irish Republic in the 19th and early 20th centuries. Originating in Irish mythology with the Fianna, the term derives from groups of legendary warrior bands, known as the Fenian Cycle. The term "Fenian" today is seen as a derogatory sectarian term in Ireland to refer to Irish nationalists and/or Catholics, particularly in Northern Ireland. The term has been used similarly in Scotland as a slur to refer to Scottish Catholics or Scots with Irish ancestry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_FENIAN_HELP">
			<Text>Strong, front-line land Unit that gains [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength from Defensive Buildings in nearby Cities. Only the Irish may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_FENIAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Fenian is the Irish unique replacement for the Rifleman. The Fenian gains [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength from Defensive Buildings in nearby Irish Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Blood of the Martyrs -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS">
			<Text>Blood of the Martyrs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_HELP">
			<Text>Increased [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength for every Defensive Building in nearby Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_1">
			<Text>Blood of the Martyrs I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_1_HELP">
			<Text>+8% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength for Defensive Buildings in nearby Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_2">
			<Text>Blood of the Martyrs II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_2_HELP">
			<Text>+16% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength for Defensive Buildings in nearby Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_3">
			<Text>Blood of the Martyrs III</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_3_HELP">
			<Text>+24% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength for Defensive Buildings in nearby Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_4">
			<Text>Blood of the Martyrs IV</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_4_HELP">
			<Text>+32% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength for Defensive Buildings in nearby Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_5">
			<Text>Blood of the Martyrs V</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BLOOD_OF_THE_MARTYRS_5_HELP">
			<Text>+40% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength for Defensive Buildings in nearby Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- visible dummy buildings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SPECIALIST_MUSICIAN">
			<Text>August Destiny Specialist</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SPECIALIST_MUSICIAN_HELP">
			<Text>Cities with a garrisoned Unit receive a free cultural Specialist, depending on the Unit's level.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SPECIALIST_WRITER">
			<Text>August Destiny Specialist</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SPECIALIST_WRITER_HELP">
			<Text>Cities with a garrisoned Unit receive a free cultural Specialist, depending on the Unit's level.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SPECIALIST_ARTIST">
			<Text>August Destiny Specialist</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_SPECIALIST_ARTIST_HELP">
			<Text>Cities with a garrisoned Unit receive a free cultural Specialist, depending on the Unit's level.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- invisible dummy buildings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_TOURISM">
			<Text>US: Ireland - August Destiny Great Work Yields</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_TOURISM_HELP">
			<Text>Irish Great Works provide half their yields when in foreign Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_DEFENSE">
			<Text>US: Ireland - August Destiny Defense</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_AUGUST_DESTINY_DEFENSE_HELP">
			<Text>Irish Great Works provide Defense in Irish Cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_GREAT_WORK_HAPPINESS">
			<Text>US: Ireland - Public House Great Works Happiness</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_GREAT_WORK_HAPPINESS_HELP">
			<Text>Public Houses provide +1 Happiness when filled with a Great Work of Music.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HAPPINESS_IRELAND">
			<Text>US: Ireland - Public House Foreign Civs Happiness and Culture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_HAPPINESS_IRELAND_HELP">
			<Text>Pubs appearing in foreign Cities provide +1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness and +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture and [ICON_TOURISM] Tourism for Ireland.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_US_PUBLIC_HOUSE_TOURISM_FOREIGN_CIVS">
			<Text>US: Ireland - Public House Foreign Civs Tourism</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Sukritact's MCIS -->
		<!-- JFD's DTP -->
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>