<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--MOD-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM">
			<Text>William III</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<!--ANGLO-DUTCH-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SPLATDAY_DUTCH_DESC">
			<Text>The Anglo-Dutch Union</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SPLATDAY_DUTCH_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>The Anglo-Dutch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SPLATDAY_DUTCH_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Anglo-Dutch</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Cities-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_01">
			<Text>The Hague</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_02">
			<Text>London</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_03">
			<Text>Amsterdam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_04">
			<Text>Rotterdam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_05">
			<Text>Utrecht</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_06">
			<Text>Dublin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_07">
			<Text>Edinburgh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_08">
			<Text>Oxford</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_09">
			<Text>Dover</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_10">
			<Text>Cambridge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_11">
			<Text>Middelburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_12">
			<Text>Brixham</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_13">
			<Text>Geldern</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_14">
			<Text>Bangor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_15">
			<Text>Zwolle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_16">
			<Text>Exeter</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_17">
			<Text>Deventer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_18">
			<Text>Danby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_19">
			<Text>Scarborough</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_20">
			<Text>Groningen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_21">
			<Text>York</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_22">
			<Text>Liverpool</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_23">
			<Text>Shrewsbury</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_24">
			<Text>Perth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_25">
			<Text>Sheffield</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_26">
			<Text>Glasgow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_27">
			<Text>Plymoth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_28">
			<Text>Drogheda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_29">
			<Text>Leeuwarden</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_30">
			<Text>Cork</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_31">
			<Text>Assen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_32">
			<Text>Denbigh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_33">
			<Text>Norwich</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_34">
			<Text>Armagh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_35">
			<Text>Newcastle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_36">
			<Text>Limerick</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_37">
			<Text>Bristol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_38">
			<Text>Derby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_39">
			<Text>Chester</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_40">
			<Text>Muggleswick</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_0">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_1">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_2">
			<Text> </Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_3">
			<Text> </Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_4">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_5">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_6">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_7">
			<Text> </Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_8">
			<Text> </Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_9">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--WILLIAM III-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM">
			<Text>William III</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_PEDIA">
			<Text>William III</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_TEXT_1">
			<Text>William III, also widely known as William of Orange, was sovereign Prince of Orange from birth, Stadtholder of Holland, Zeeland, Utrecht, Guelders and Overijssel in the Dutch Republic from the 1670s and King of England, Ireland and Scotland from 1689 until his death. As King of Scotland, he is known as William II. As perhaps the pivotal European figure of the late 17th century, William of Orange remains most noted for having fought France, the dominant power in Europe, to a standstill in three wars. In this process he reunited his native Netherlands and became king of England. In his English role William fostered the legal bulwarks of the Glorious Revolution of 1688: religious toleration for Protestant dissenters, a prescribed monarchy, and parliamentary partnership with the Crown concerning legislation. As William drew England into his wars against France, he concluded more than a century's isolation for England and initiated a series of victories that later yielded Great Britain a worldwide empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Years and Education</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Eight days before William was born at The Hague on Nov. 4, 1650, his father, William II, Prince of Orange and Stadholder of the United Netherlands, died, bequeathing a divided Netherlands to his son. William's mother was Mary, the oldest daughter of Charles I of England. The De Witt brothers, Jan and Cornelius, heads of an urban and commercial coalition, assumed power and pursued a policy of autonomy for the seven provinces of the Netherlands. The house of Orange, aristocratic leader of the landed interests, had stood for unity as the only means of protection against foreign interests. Despite the De Witts' control over his education, William nurtured plans to restore the stadholdership. In the meantime, the young prince prepared himself, mastering four languages, studying politics and war, and exercising the Spartan self-control and taciturnity for which he became famous.
				In 1667 the prince's popularity rose dramatically when Louis XIV of France made the first of his many attempts to conquer the Dutch. Public exasperation greeted the De Witts' inactivity while Louis's armies occupied neighboring Flanders. When the southern Dutch provinces were invaded in 1672, William was advanced quickly from captain general in February to stadholder in July. In August a panicked mob murdered the De Witts, and a year later William's office was made hereditary.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Stadholder Of The United Provinces</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The war with France raged from 1672 to 1678, and while William battled against armies that were sometimes five times the size of his own, he built an alliance with Spain, Denmark, and Brandenburg. He fought the Great Condé—Louis II de Bourbon, Prince de Condé—to a draw at the Battle of Seneff in August 1674. Despite a near-fatal bout with smallpox in 1675 and a severe arm wound in 1676, William wrung from the French a recognition of Dutch independence in the Treaty of Nijmegen in 1678.
				Toward the end of the French war, William married— in 1677 — Mary, the Protestant elder daughter of James, Duke of York, later King James II of England. With England as the Netherlands' partner there could be no doubt about maintaining Dutch independence. The match was advanced by the pro-Dutch English minister, the Earl of Danby, and after the marriage William slowly intruded himself into English politics. He ostensibly visited Charles II in 1681 to seek aid against renewed French hostilities, but he actually came to observe the increasing antagonism of the Whigs to the proposed succession of York, whose autocracy and Roman Catholicism displeased many Englishmen. William quietly let it be known that if Charles should die without issue, he would be willing to be named regent over his father-in-law in case James should be excluded from the throne.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Glorious Revolution of 1688</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_TEXT_4">
			<Text>During the War of the League of Augsburg, William brought to the alliance the overwhelming support of England in 1689. James II's precipitate illegalities in favor of his Roman Catholic subjects after he became king in 1685 alienated most English leaders, who in turn sought the alternative earlier suggested by William. William invaded England in November 1688 with a force of 15,000. Met by many of England's important men, he proceeded under such careful circumstances that not one shot was fired. James's flight to France in December cleared the path for William and Mary to assume the vacated throne. Their reign became the only jointly held monarchy in English history. In May 1689 England declared war on France.
				Between 1689 and 1693 William, equipped with an army often numbering 90,000, remained mostly in the field, leaving duties at home in Mary's hands. In Ireland, William defeated an attempt by French and Irish troops to dethrone him, nearly being killed in the Battle of the Boyne in July 1690. At sea the English repelled an invasion at La Hogue in May 1692; but on the Continent, William barely held his own. William's defeat at Neerwinden in July 1693 cost the French so many lives that Louis XIV began peace overtures. Sporadic campaigning continued until lengthy negotiations finally resulted in the Treaty of Ryswick (September 1697), in which Louis XIV recognized William as the legitimate ruler of England (Mary had died in 1694).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Last Years</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_TEXT_5">
			<Text>
				William's domestic relations in England were intermittently strained because he understood little of the compromise required under the parliamentary system of broad-based consultation and administration. He was the last English king to use the veto extensively, although he usually yielded to Parliament's wishes rather than risk losing support for his wars. William fostered the Toleration Act of 1689 and the establishment of the Bank of England to fund the war debt in 1694. He assented to the Declaration of Right and to the Triennial Act.
				William's frequent absences from England and his reliance upon Dutch counselors accounted for his general unpopularity. However, the discovery of the Turnham Green Plot against his life in 1696 prompted a personal loyalty lasting until the end of his reign. In 1702 William fell from his horse, seriously undermining his fragile health. He died on March 8, 1702, as he was constructing a new alliance against France for the War of the Spanish Succession.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_NAME">
			<Text>William III</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of the Anglo-Dutch Union</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Stadtholder of Holland, Zeeland, Utrecht, Guelders and Overijssel, Prince of Orange, King of England, Scotland and Ireland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SPLATDAY_WILLIAM_LIVED">
			<Text>1650 - 1702 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SPLATDAY_DUTCH">
			<Text>The Anglo-Dutch Union</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SPLATDAY_DUTCH_TEXT_1">
			<Text>AngloDutchers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPLATDAY_DUTCH_DOM">
			<Text>
				Sovereign William, you were born stadtholder -- the leader of the Dutch people. English machinations blocked you from taking this office, because Oliver Cromwell feared the power of your family. Despite a fractured Dutch people occupied by a Catholic coalition of English and the French nations, you were determined to fulfill your royal destiny. You united the Dutch factions under your banner, and created a Protestant power base by marrying the daughter of the Catholic King of Scotland, then deposing him after he became King of England. With the unified Protestant power of England and the unified Netherlands, you were able to secure your people's independence from the French.
				[NEWLINE]
				Glorious William of Orange, your people look to you. With your gritty determination and shrewd ambition, raise our heads above those of our enemies and unite with our allies to forge a civilization that will stand the test of time!
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--GLORIOUS REVOLUTION-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SPLATDAY_DUTCH_SHORT">
			<Text>Glorious Revolution</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SPLATDAY_DUTCH">
			<Text>
				Enemy cities of your Religion do not enter Resistance [ICON_RESISTANCE] or lose Citizens [ICON_CITIZEN] when captured. Upon the outbreak of War, enemy units near cities of your Religion may defect to your empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MAN-OF-WAR-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_MAN_OF_WAR">
			<Text>Man-of-War</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_MAN_OF_WAR_HELP">
			<Text>The Man-of-War is an Anglo-Dutch Unique Unit, replacing the Frigate. The Man-of-War is stronger in coast. Along with abilities of the Frigate, it puts enemy cities into resistance [ICON_RESISTANCE] when blockading [ICON_BLOCKADED] them. The Man-of-War also increases the effect of the Glorious Revolution on nearby units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_MAN_OF_WAR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Use the Man-of-War to help launch your invasions turning your enemy's units and cities against them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_MAN_OF_WAR_TEXT">
			<Text>The man-of-war was an expression for a powerful warship or frigate from the 16th to the 19th century. Although the term never acquired a specific meaning, it was usually reserved for a ship armed with cannon and propelled primarily by sails, as opposed to a galley which is propelled primarily by oars. The man-of-war was developed in Portugal in the early 15th century from earlier roundships with the addition of a second mast to form the carrack. The 16th century saw the carrack evolve into the galleon and then the ship of the line. During the 17th century, Dutch wealth and maritime expansion were the source of much envy across Europe, with them yielding the largest fleet in the world, and contained several men-of-war. In 1688, when a new Anglo-French alliance seemed imminent; the Dutch stadtholder William III took a desperate gamble by sailing to England with a large fleet that landed in Brixham in Devon. He marched to London and toppled his father in law James II, who was in a very weak position then. William had himself proclaimed King of England, effectively making his greatest maritime rival an ally and taking the fight to the French.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--BLUE GUARD-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_BLUE_GUARD">
			<Text>Blue Guards</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_BLUE_GUARD_HELP">
			<Text>The Blue Guards are an Anglo-Dutch Unique Unit, replacing the Rifleman. The Blue Guards are more expensive to produce however start with the Blitz promotion allowing them to attack twice. The Blue Guards gain a 15% combat bonus [ICON_WAR] when starting adjacent to a friendly unit from a Civilisation or City State following your religion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_BLUE_GUARD_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Blue Guards should form the backbone of a mid to late game army. When used in coordinated attacks with allied city states or other civilisation they are even more effective.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_VANA_BLUE_GUARD_TEXT">
			<Text>The Dutch Guards, nicknamed the Blue Guards in the late 17th century, were an elite infantry unit of the army of the United Provinces of the Netherlands, also known as the Dutch Republic. From 1688 to 1699 it served as William III of Orange's Guards regiment. Under King William III, the regiment served in England as his personal guard. During this time, it was also known as the Blue Guards, because of the Nassau blue coats with yellow/orange cuffs and lining. After William III died in 1702, the regiment was renamed the Dutch Guards. Notable campaigns in which the guards fought included the Nine Years' War, the War of the Spanish Succession, in which they were the backbone of the Dutch army, the second largest in Europe; and the War of Austrian Succession. The Dutch pioneered the development of platoon fire, which allowed infantry formations to fire continuously, which gave the Dutch an advantage in firepower over armies not using the platoon fire system.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Naval Restoration-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_VANA_BLUE_GUARD_BONUS">
			<Text>Glorious Revolution</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_VANA_BLUE_GUARD_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_VANA_MAN_OF_WAR_BONUS">
			<Text>Glorious Revolution</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_VANA_MAN_OF_WAR_BONUS_HELP">
			<Text> </Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>