<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--MOD-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_TRANQ_NORMANS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>
				The Normans (Robert Guiscard)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE TRAIT: Men of the North Wind[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Excess [ICON_RES_HORSE]Horses provide [ICON_GREAT_GENERAL]Great General points. The first City on each Landmass provides the [ICON_CAPITAL]Capital with [ICON_RES_HORSE]Horses, and [ICON_GOLD]Gold and [ICON_PEACE]Faith if it was conquered[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: EQUITES (KNIGHT)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Expensive Mounted Unit that has additional [ICON_STRENGTH]Combat Strength when on foreign continents, and begins with additional XP for each source of [ICON_RES_HORSE]Horses in the Empire[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: CONQUEROR (GENERAL)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Adjacent Units receive temporary [ICON_ARROW_RIGHT]Movement and [ICON_STRENGTH]Combat Strength after disembarking. May be expended in [ICON_OCCUPIED]conquered cities to construct a Citadel and Courthouse, making the city count for the purpose of the UA.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--The Normans-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TRANQ_NORMANS_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Norman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TRANQ_NORMANS_DESC">
			<Text>Norman Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_TRANQ_NORMANS_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>The Normans</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Cities-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_01">
			<Text>Salerno</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_02">
			<Text>Melfi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_03">
			<Text>Benevento</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_04">
			<Text>Messina</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_05">
			<Text>Palermo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_06">
			<Text>Bari</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_07">
			<Text>Capua</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_08">
			<Text>Catania</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_09">
			<Text>Taranto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_10">
			<Text>Regio</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_11">
			<Text>Tripoli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_12">
			<Text>Amalfi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_13">
			<Text>Syracuse</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_14">
			<Text>Brindisi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_15">
			<Text>Cariati</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_16">
			<Text>Naples</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_17">
			<Text>Otranto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_18">
			<Text>Cerami</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_19">
			<Text>Castrogiovanni</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_20">
			<Text>Tunis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_21">
			<Text>Sfax</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_22">
			<Text>Valleta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_23">
			<Text>Pantelleria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_24">
			<Text>Dyrrhacium</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_25">
			<Text>Civitate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_26">
			<Text>Rossano</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_27">
			<Text>Trani</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_28">
			<Text>Troina</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_29">
			<Text>Avlona</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_30">
			<Text>Gallipoli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_31">
			<Text>Siponto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_32">
			<Text>Antioch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_33">
			<Text>Conza</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_34">
			<Text>Aquila</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_35">
			<Text>Potenza</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_36">
			<Text>Laodicea</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_0">
			<Text>Drogo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_1">
			<Text>Roger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_2">
			<Text>Bohemond</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_3">
			<Text>Sikelgaita</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_4">
			<Text>Tancred</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_5">
			<Text>Guy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_6">
			<Text>Humphrey</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_7">
			<Text>Mauger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_8">
			<Text>Jordan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_TRANQ_NORMANS_9">
			<Text>Simon</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Robert Guiscard-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS">
			<Text>Robert Guiscard</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Robert, byname Robert Guiscard or Robert de Hauteville, Italian Roberto Guiscardo or Roberto d’Altavilla, (born c. 1015, Normandy [France]—died July 17, 1085, near Cephalonia, Greece, Byzantine Empire), Norman adventurer who settled in Apulia, in southern Italy, about 1047 and became duke of Apulia (1059). He eventually extended Norman rule over Naples, Calabria, and Sicily and laid the foundations of the kingdom of Sicily.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Arrival in Apulia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				Robert was born into a family of knights. Arriving in Apulia, in southern Italy, around 1047 to join his half brother Drogo, he found that it and Campania, though they were southern Italy’s most-flourishing regions, were plagued by political disturbances. These regions attracted hordes of fortune-seeking Norman immigrants, who were to transform the political role of both regions in the following decades.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In Campania, the Lombards of Capua were launching wars against the Byzantine dukes of Naples in order to gain possession of that important seaport. In Apulia, William (“Iron Arm”) de Hauteville, Robert’s eldest half brother, having successfully defeated the Byzantine Greeks who controlled that region, had been elected count of Apulia in 1042. In 1046 he had been succeeded by his brother Drogo.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When Robert joined his brothers, they sent him to Calabria to attack Byzantine territory. He began his campaign by pillaging the countryside and ransoming its people. In 1053, at the head of the combined forces of Normans from Apulia and Campania, he defeated the haphazardly led forces of the Byzantines, the Lombards, and the papacy at Civitate. Because of the deaths of William and Drogo and of his third half brother, Count Humphrey, in 1057, Robert returned to Apulia to seize control from Humphrey’s sons and save the region from disgregating internal conflicts. After becoming the recognized leader of the Apulian Normans, Robert resumed his campaign in Calabria. His brother Roger’s arrival from Normandy enabled him to extend and solidify his conquests in Apulia.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In his progression from gang leader to commander of mercenary troops to conqueror, Robert emerged as a shrewd and perspicacious political figure. In 1059 he entered into a concordat at Melfi with Pope Nicholas II. Until that time the papacy had been hostile toward the Normans, considering them to be an anarchist force that upset the political structure in southern Italy—a structure based on a balance of power between the Byzantines and the Lombards of northern Italy. The schism that took place between the Greek and Latin churches in 1054 temporarily worsened the relations between the Byzantine emperors and the papacy, and eventually the papacy realized that Norman conquests over the Byzantines could work to its advantage. Robert’s plan to expel the Arabs from Sicily and restore Christianity to the island also found favour in Nicholas’s eyes. This expedition into Sicily got under way in 1060, as soon as the conquest of Calabria was completed. Robert entrusted the command of the expedition to his brother Roger, but on particularly difficult occasions—e.g., the siege of Palermo in 1071—he came to his brother’s aid.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Until this time, Robert’s relations with Roger had not always been amicable, since Roger, aware of both his own talent and Robert’s dependency on him, would not settle for the subordinate role allotted him. Their differences were resolved when Robert invested Roger, after he had recognized Robert’s supreme authority, with “the County of Sicily and Calabria” along with the right to govern and tax both counties.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Expansion of the Duchy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Robert continued to expand the small county left by Humphrey into a duchy, extending from the Adriatic to the Tyrrhenian sea. The capture of Bari in April 1071 resulted in the end of Byzantine rule in southern Italy. Robert turned next to the neighbouring territories of Salerno, controlled by the Lombards. Instead of fighting them, he dissolved his first marriage and in 1058 married the sister of Salerno’s last Lombard prince, Gisulf II. Hostilities broke out between the two rulers, however, and Gisulf naively tried to bring about a Byzantine counteroffensive against Robert. Fearing that the Norman advances into Campania, Molise, and Abruzzi would threaten the papal dominions, Pope Gregory VII excommunicated Robert and gave Gisulf considerable military aid. The struggle came to a head when Gisulf, determined to display his power, advanced toward the prosperous city of Amalfi. Robert responded to the city’s plea for help in 1073 and successfully defended it; in December 1076 he took Salerno from Gisulf and made it the capital of his duchy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Robert was now at the height of his power. During his rise he repressed with an iron hand not only the claims of Humphrey’s sons but also the uprisings of towns and lords that were fretting under the restraints imposed upon them. The harshness with which Robert chose to deal with these rebels was intended to transform a heterogeneous population into a strong state.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When, in 1080, the conflict between church and state over the right to control ecclesiastical personnel and property had become more intense, Robert chose to reconcile himself with Gregory VII, entering into the Concordat of Ceprano, which confirmed the commitments of the earlier Council of Melfi. Even the Byzantine court drew closer to him and went as far as trying to establish a familial relationship with Robert. The Byzantine emperor Michael VII, in need of Robert’s help to uphold his unstable throne, married his son, Constantine, to one of Robert’s daughters, Helen. The opposition party, however, deposed Michael and confined Helen in a monastery. To guarantee Apulia against attack from the new rulers of Byzantium, Robert wanted the territories on the Adriatic coast of the Balkan Peninsula, and he began to build a large navy. Michael’s expulsion and Helen’s confinement reawakened his unappeased spirit of adventure and hastened his long-considered expedition. Now his goal was even more ambitious: to march to Byzantium and crown himself emperor in place of the deposed Michael.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1083 Robert landed in Epirus with a well-trained army and immediately succeeded in defeating the Byzantines and their Venetian allies. The pope, however, suddenly recalled him to Italy to help him expel the German king Henry IV, who was marching on Rome en route to claiming southern Italy for the Holy Roman Empire. Having returned home and suppressed the revolts of the lords hostile to himself and to Pope Gregory VII, Robert moved toward Rome, defeated the pope’s enemies, and escorted him to Salerno in the summer of 1084. Following this success, he returned to his campaign on the Adriatic coast. He died during the siege of Cephalonia on July 17, 1085.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Achievements</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_TEXT_4">
			<Text>
				Physically attractive, endowed with an acute and unscrupulous intelligence, a brilliant strategist and competent statesman, Robert had begun to organize a state composed of diverse ethnic and civil groups: Latin and Germanic in Lombard territories and Greek in Byzantine domains. The new political structure was built on a monarchial-feudal framework characteristic of the time, but it was controlled by the energetic and uncompromising Robert, who tried to use his ducal power to create a powerful and prosperous state. The other base on which he built was Latin Christianity, the religion of the conquerors and most of the conquered, which he used to reconcile the subjected peoples. An extremely religious man, Robert was distrustful of the Greek clergy because of their ties with Byzantium. On the other hand, his generosity toward the Latin church was bountiful. He endowed it with territories and clerical immunities in order to tie it firmly to himself. Splendid cathedrals and Benedictine abbeys were built in the hope that they would consolidate and diffuse Latin language and culture among the heterogeneous people and tie them into a new, unified state.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_LIVED">
			<Text> 1015 - 1085 AD </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_NAME">
			<Text>Robert Guiscard</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Duke of Sicily</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_TRANQ_NORMANS_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Duke of Apulia and Calabria, Prince of Benevento </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DOM_TRANQ_ROBERTGUISCARD_TEXT">
			<Text>God be with you, Robert Guiscard, leader of the Normans in southern Italy and Duke of Sicily! Born into a house of lower nobility in Normandy, you followed your brothers and many more of your countrymen - just as your ancestors had done - in search of wealth, fame, glory, and conquests. Your people ranged all across the Mediterranen Sea, becoming involved in all manner of battles and building many castles and states, with the Kingdom of Sicily being one of the most long lived of these. You even dreamed of deposing the Byzantine Emperor and establishing a Norman aristocracy in its place! [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Oh wily Robert the Fox, your people are have need of your cunning and strength of arms once more. They chafe at the bounds of their current realm and dream of new lands and cultures to interact with. Will you lead them astride your mighty steeds of the sea in search of greener pastures? Will you subjugate your foes and build a realm of tolerance and intrigue? Can you build a Civilisation to stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Responses-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Hmmm, another arrival on our shores is it? See that you don't bring trouble with you while perusing our realm.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>It seems at last I have been vanquished, I may now fall but my people, and our culture, will remain!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You're ambitious I'll give you that - ambitious and stupid, certainly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>We can conquer more together than either of us could apart, what say you to a Declaration of Friendship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You are worthless, unlike your lands. Someone should really take them off your hands.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I didn't get this nickname for nothing, I've grown tired of this farce.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>Your lands will soon be under new management, emphasis on the soon part</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_TRANQ_NORMANS_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Did that make you feel better?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Men of the North Wind-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TRANQ_NORMANS_SHORT">
			<Text>Men of the North Wind</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TRANQ_NORMANS">
			<Text>Excess [ICON_RES_HORSE]Horses provide [ICON_GREAT_GENERAL]Great General points. The first City on each Landmass provides the [ICON_CAPITAL]Capital with [ICON_RES_HORSE]Horses, and [ICON_GOLD]Gold and [ICON_PEACE]Faith if it was conquered</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--EQUITES-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_EQUITES">
			<Text>Equites</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_EQUITES_HELP">
			<Text> Expensive Mounted Unit that has additional [ICON_STRENGTH]Combat Strength when on foreign continents, and begins with additional XP for each source of [ICON_RES_HORSE]Horses in the Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_EQUITES_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Equites is stronger and more expensive than the unit it replaces, especially when on foreign continents and begibs with additional XP if there are additional sources of Horses in your realms, use them to form the core of your counquering armies. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_EQUITES_TEXT">
			<Text>
				The Normans were at first novices and imitators in the practice of fighting on horseback, they soon became masters of cavalry warfare as it was then practiced in continental Europe. Mounted on much the same breed of war horse as his Frankish, Angevin, or Breton opponent, wearing the heavy mail hauberk that was standard among the warriors of northwestern Europe, protected by a conical helmet and a kite-shaped shield, and armed with a long, broad-bladed sword and a slender lance, the Norman cavalryman proved on countless occasions that he could outfight and overwhelm the most powerful forces brought against him. To some extent, no doubt, this was due to the importance which the Norman knightly class attached to the training of young warriors. They eagerly adopted the carefully fostered cult of knighthood which had grown up in the old Carolingian empire in the 10th and 11th centuries. But Norman knights were also fierce and brutal soldiers who had received an arduous training that left little room for the feelings of humanity and mercy with which Christian teaching was later to endow the concept of chivalry.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Destrier Charge-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TRANQ_EQUITES">
			<Text>Destrier Charge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TRANQ_EQUITES_HELP">
			<Text>This Unit has additional [ICON_STRENGTH]Combat Strength when on foreign continents</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--CONQUEROR-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_CONQUEROR">
			<Text>Conqueror</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_HELP">
			<Text>Adjacent Units receive temporary [ICON_ARROW_RIGHT]Movement and [ICON_STRENGTH]Combat Strength after disembarking. May be expended in [ICON_OCCUPIED]conquered cities to construct a Citadel and Courthouse, making the city count for the purpose of the UA.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Conqueror is the Norman replacement for the Great General, facilitating the conquest and assimilation of foreign territories. Expend them in peace time to instantly secure your new expanded realm.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_TEXT">
			<Text> The Conqueror epitomises that greatest of Norman figures, the Adventurer. Whether across the North Sea, or the Mediterranean, Norman warriors adventured all across Europe, becoming involved in all manner of conflicts and establishing multiple fiefdoms. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TRANQ_CONQUEROR">
			<Text>Conquests of the North Men</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_HELP">
			<Text>Adjacent Units receive temporary [ICON_ARROW_RIGHT]Movement and [ICON_STRENGTH]Combat Strength after disembarking.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TS_CONQUEROR_DOMTM">
			<Text>[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Perform a Fortification[ENDCOLOR][NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Expend this unit to construct a Citadel and a Courthouse in the city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MISSION_TS_CONQUEROR_DOMTM">
			<Text>[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Perform a Fortification[ENDCOLOR]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MISSION_TS_CONQUEROR_DOMTM_HELP">
			<Text>Expend this unit to construct a Citadel and a Courthouse in city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MISSION_TS_CONQUEROR_DOMTM_DISABLED">
			<Text>Must be adjacent to an owned city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Unique Names-->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_01">
             <Text>Robert Guiscard</Text>
         </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_02">
			<Text>William Iron Arm</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_03">
			<Text>Drogo of Hauteville</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_04">
			<Text>Tancred of Hautville</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_05">
			<Text>Gilbert Buatere</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_06">
			<Text>Rainulf Drengot</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_07">
			<Text>Roger Bosso</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_TRANQ_CONQUEROR_08">
			<Text>William of the Principate</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Mod Support-->



		-<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_TRANQ_NORMANS_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">

			<Text>Our people are now quarreling with their neighbours and demolishing walls to resolve arguments. I worry that the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>

		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>