<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 10/31/2021 1:25:02 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Greetings to you, fellow warrior. I am Mori Motonari, of Aki. What will history say of our meeting?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>I am Motonari, of the Mori Clan. I will lead my family out of Aki Province, across Honshu, and soon all of Japan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Divided, you will perish. Learn the lesson that I failed to understand.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>We are always pleased to see our allies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Welcome back to Aki Province.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Without allies you are little more than a single arrow.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I was once surrounded by enemy lords. Ask yourself, where are they now?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>It seems our destinies may cross sooner than I anticipated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>It is with a heavy heart that I must ask this of you. Know that the Mori always repay such generosity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>Sometimes, it is not enough to simply know history. One has to make it, too.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_HUMAN_DOFED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Three arrows are far harder to break than one alone. {1_CivName} and the Mori are pleased to have you as an ally.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Three arrows are far harder to break than one alone. We have requested to join your alliance with {1_CivName}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Player is influential on the AI (Our people are wearing your blue jeans...) -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now visiting your sacred isle and drinking tea from your pottery. I worry the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI is influential on the player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_PB_MORI_MOTONARI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>We are glad to see that your people are visiting our sacred isle and drinking tea from our pottery. The amazing works of our civilization are truly inspiring!</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>