<GameData>
    <Language_en_US>
        <!--Cities-->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_1">
            <Text>Tigwaxsti</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_2">
            <Text>Tsaxis</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_3">
            <Text>Mimkumlis</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_4">
            <Text>Xwalkw</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_5">
            <Text>Kalugwis</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_6">
            <Text>Dzawadi</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_7">
            <Text>Tzatsisnukomi</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_8">
            <Text>Itsikan</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_9">
            <Text>Gwa'yi</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_10">
            <Text>Gwa'yasdams</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_11">
            <Text>Hegam's</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_12">
            <Text>Ba'a's</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_13">
            <Text>Kitamaat</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_14">
            <Text>Takus</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_15">
            <Text>Quatsino</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_16">
            <Text>Xwamdasbe'</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_17">
            <Text>Ceqweiuten</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_18">
            <Text>Yamataxw</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_19">
            <Text>Wiwekam</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_20">
            <Text>Nahwitti</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_21">
            <Text>Tsala Adi</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_22">
            <Text>Metap</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_23">
            <Text>Ni'nalkinuxw</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_24">
            <Text>Madilbe</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_25">
            <Text>Nimpkish</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_26">
            <Text>Mamalilikala</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_27">
            <Text>Gusgimukw</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_28">
            <Text>Tlatlasikwala</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_29">
            <Text>Nakamgalisala</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_URD_KWAK_30">
            <Text>Da'naxda'xw</Text>
        </Row>
        
        <!--Spies-->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_0">
            <Text>Quesilad</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_1">
            <Text>O'waxalagalis </Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_2">
            <Text>Sisiutl</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_3">
            <Text>Mungothar</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_4">
            <Text>Dzunukwa</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_5">
            <Text>Kumugwe</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_6">
            <Text>Qaniqilak</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_7">
            <Text>Kolus</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_8">
            <Text>U'Melth</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_URD_KWAK_9">
            <Text>Bakwas</Text>
        </Row>
        
        <!--Basic Info-->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED">
            <Text>Willie Seaweed</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_URD_KWAK_ADJECTIVE">
            <Text>Kwakwaka'wakw</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_URD_KWAK_DESC">
            <Text>Kwakwaka'wakw Empire</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_URD_KWAK_SHORT_DESC">
            <Text>The Kwakwaka'wakw</Text>
            <Plurality>2</Plurality>
        </Row>
        
        <!--Civilopedia-->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_1">
            <Text>Overview</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_1">
            <Text>The Kwakwaka'wakw, also known as the Kwakiutl, are Indigenous peoples of the Pacific Northwest Coast. Their traditional territory is northern Vancouver Island, nearby smaller islands including the Discovery Islands, and the adjacent British Columbia mainland. They are politically organized into 13 band governments. Their language consists of four dialects of what is commonly referred to as Kwak'wala.</Text>
        </Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_2">
			<Text>From the Land, Sea and Underground</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Kwakwaka'wakw oral history says their ancestors came in the forms of animals by way of land, sea, or underground. When one of these ancestral animals arrived at a given spot, it discarded its animal appearance and became human. Animals that figure in these origin myths include the Thunderbird, his brother Kolas, the seagull, orca, grizzly bear, or chief ghost. Some ancestors have human origins and are said to come from distant places. Historically, the Kwakwa̱ka̱'wakw economy was based primarily on fishing, with the men also engaging in some hunting, and the women gathering wild fruits and berries. Ornate weaving and woodwork were important crafts, and wealth, defined by slaves and material goods, was prominently displayed and traded at potlatch ceremonies. In contrast to most non-native societies, wealth and status were not determined by how much you had, but by how much you had to give away. This act of giving away your wealth was one of the main acts in a potlatch.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Contact with the Europeans</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The first documented contact was with Captain George Vancouver in 1792. Disease, which developed as a result of direct contact with European settlers along the West Coast of Canada, drastically reduced the Indigenous Kwakwaka'wakw population during the late 19th-early 20th century, dropping by 75 percent from 1830 to 1880, much of which can be attributed to smallpox. Much like other Canadian aboriginals, they were subject to the residential school system.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The Potlach and its Banning</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_4">
			<Text>When the Canadian government was focused on assimilation of First Nations, it made the potlatch a target of activities to be suppressed. In 1885, the Indian Act was revised to include clauses banning the potlatch and making it illegal to practise. Eventually the Act was amended, expanded to prohibit guests from participating in the potlatch ceremony. The Kwakwaka'wakw were too numerous to police, and the government could not enforce the law. Duncan Campbell Scott convinced Parliament to change the offence from criminal to summary. The ban was eventually overturned. Sustaining the customs and culture of their ancestors, in the 21st century the Kwakwaka'wakw openly hold potlatches to commit to the revival of their ancestors' ways. The frequency of potlatches has increased as occur frequently and increasingly more over the years as families reclaim their birthright.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_5">
			<Text>A Modern Revival</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Restoring their ties to their land, culture and rights, the Kwakwaka'wakw undertaken much in bringing back their customs, beliefs and language. Potlatches occur more frequently as families reconnect to their birthright, and the community uses language programs, classes and social events to restore the language. Artists in the 19th and 20th centuries, such as Mungo Martin, Ellen Neel and Willie Seaweed have taken efforts to revive Kwakwaka'wakw art and culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Intricacy of Society </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Kwakwaka'wakw kinship is based on a bilinear structure, with loose characteristics of a patrilineal culture. It has large extended families and interconnected community life. The Kwakwaka'wakw are made up of numerous communities or bands. Within those communities they are organized into extended family units or na’mima, which means of one kind. Each na’mima had positions that carried particular responsibilities and privileges. Each community had around four na’mima. A head chief who, through primogeniture, could trace his origins to that 'na'mima's ancestors delineated the roles throughout the rest of his family. Every clan had several sub-chiefs, who gained their titles and position through their own family's primogeniture. These chiefs organized their people to harvest the communal lands that belonged to their family. Kwakwaka'wakw society was organized into four classes: the nobility, attained through birthright and connection in lineage to ancestors, the aristocracy who attained status through connection to wealth, resources or spiritual powers displayed or distributed in the potlatch, commoners, and slaves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_7">
			<Text>The Trade of Proud Peoples</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_7">
			<Text>A trade and barter subsistence economy formed the early stages of the Kwakwaka'wakw Trade was carried out between internal Kwakwaka'wakw nations, as well as surrounding Indigenous nations such as the Tsimshian, Tlingit, the Nuu-chah-nulth and Coast Salish peoples. Over time, the potlatch tradition created a demand for stored surpluses, as such a display of wealth had social implications. By the time of European colonialism, it was noted that wool blankets had become a form of common currency. In the potlatch tradition, hosts of the potlatch were expected to provide enough gifts for all the guests invited. This practice created a system of loan and interest, using wool blankets as currency. As with other Pacific Northwest nations, the Kwakwaka'wakw highly valued copper in their economy and used it for ornament and precious goods. Scholars have proposed that prior to trade with Europeans, the people acquired copper from natural copper veins along riverbeds, but this has not been proven. Contact with European settlers, particularly through the Hudson's Bay Company, brought an influx of copper to their territories. Individual pieces of copper were sometimes given names based on their value. The value of any given piece was defined by the number of wool blankets last traded for them.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Communication and Language</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_8">
			<Text>The Kwak'wala language is a part of the Wakashan languages group. Word lists and some documentation of Kwak'wala were created from the early period of contact with Europeans in the 18th century, but a systematic attempt to record the language did not occur before the work of Franz Boas in the late 19th and early 20th century. The use of Kwak'wala declined significantly in the 19th and 20th centuries, mainly due to the assimilationist policies of the Canadian government. As a result of these pressures, there are relatively few Kwak'wala speakers today. Most remaining speakers are past the age of child-rearing, which is considered a crucial stage for language transmission. As with many other Indigenous languages, there are significant barriers to language revitalization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Art and Music</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_9">
			<Text>Kwakwaka'wakw arts consist of a diverse range of crafts, including totems, masks, textiles, jewellery and carved objects, ranging in size from transformation masks to totem poles. Cedar wood was the preferred medium for sculpting and carving projects as it was readily available in the native Kwakwaka'wakw regions. Totems were carved with bold cuts, a relative degree of realism, and an emphatic use of paints. Masks make up a large portion of art as masks are important in the portrayal of the characters central to dance ceremonies. Music is used primarily for ceremony and ritual, and is based around percussive instrumentation, especially log, box, and hide drums, as well as rattles and whistles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_HEADING_10">
			<Text>Housing and Clothing</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT_10">
			<Text>Kwakwaka'wakw built their houses from cedar planks, which could usually house about 50 people, usually families from the same clan. At the entrance, there was usually a totem pole carved with different animals, mythological figures and family crests. In summer, men wore no clothing except jewellery. In the winter, they usually rubbed fat on themselves to keep warm. In battle the men wore red cedar armour and helmets, and breech clouts made from cedar. During ceremonies they wore circles of cedar bark on their ankles as well as cedar breech clouts. The women wore skirts of softened cedar, and a cedar or wool blanket on top during the winter.</Text>
		</Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_NAME">
            <Text>Wille Seaweed</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_SUBTITLE">
            <Text>Kwakwaka'wakw Chief</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TITLES_1">
            <Text>Chief</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_LIVED">
            <Text>1873 - 1967</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_HEADING_1">
            <Text>Overview</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TEXT_1">
            <Text>Willie Seaweed, also known as Hilamas, was a Kwakwaka'wakw chief and wood carver from Canada. Considered a master indigenous artist who is remembered for his technical artistic style and protection of traditional native ceremonies during the Canadian potlatch ceremony ban. Today, Seaweed's work can be found in cultural centers and corporations, art museums, natural history museums, and private collections. Some pieces are still in use by the Nak'waxda'xw tribe.</Text>
        </Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Willie Seaweed was born around 1873 in the village of Tigwaxsti. He grew up in Blunden Harbour, British Columbia, known natively as Ba'a's, where he lived until his death in 1967. Both Seaweed's parents came from chiefly lines, and his father was head chief of the Gixsam sect of the Nak'waxda'xw tribe in the Kwakwaka'wakw region. Seaweed's father died before he was born, leading Seaweed to inherit the title of Hilamas, head chief, at a young age. This ensured leadership was safeguarded within the family.  Seaweed was born into a native reservation at a time of significant exposure to white settlers following the fur trade, gold rush, and colonization along the Canadian coast. Because of this, contact between white settlers and Canadian tribes was common.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Traditionally Raised</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Although contemporary practice was for First Nations youth to attend a residential school, Seaweed was not sent to boarding school. Instead, he was raised to speak the traditional Kwak'wala language, which he maintained during his lifetime. Part of Kwakwaka'wakw education included an apprenticeship to learn traditional carving practices. He followed in the tradition of Charles James, Mungo Martin, and Charles Edenshaw. He created traditional objects in the Kwakwaka'wakw style. Seaweed's implementation of traditional artistic methods in a refined, technical way is what deemed him a master Kwakwaka'wakw artist. He carved totem poles, coppers, headdresses, drums, rattles, whistles, and masks as well as painting house fronts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Life as a Chief</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Willie Seaweed was his official Canadian name, as First Nations peoples were required to have a legal name recognized by the government. He was known informally as Kwaghitola or Smoky Top, with Hilamas, or right maker, being his Indigenous name. Due to his chiefly ancestry, Seaweed was considered one of the highest-ranking leaders in the Nak'waxda'xw tribe. The position of chief rendered Seaweed a source of historical knowledge, a ceremonial leader, and a distributor of wealth. As was tradition, Seaweed married multiple times to the daughters of past chiefs. These marriages allowed Seaweed to inherit privileged information restricted to kin groups, including legends, dances, songs, and ancestral information. Seaweed had one surviving child, son Joe Seaweed, whom he also awarded the Hilamas title at a young age. Artists were commonly high-rank members of a tribe, like Seaweed, due to their possession of cultural knowledge. Seaweed's artwork was made primarily for use during Native potlatch ceremonies, which he also participated in as a singer, composer, dancer, and comedic performer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_HEADING_5">
			<Text>The Potlatch Ban</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Seaweed's professional artistic career coincided with the 1876 Canadian ban on the potlatch ceremony, which was later repealed in 1951. Christian missionaries and the Canadian government believed potlatch ceremonies to be immoral and dangerous to Western assimilation efforts. Punishment for engaging in potlatch practice could entail two to six months in prison. The Nak'waxda'xw openly resisted the ban and continued to practice the potlatch ceremony. The mountainous region allowed the tribe to protect their traditions, leading to them being considered masters of the potlatch ceremonies. Art played a key role in these performances as a method to pass down knowledge to younger generations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_HEADING_6">
			<Text>The Illegality of Art</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_URD_SEAWEED_PEDIA_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Seaweed's art was considered illegal because of its ceremonial nature to coincide with potlatch ceremonies. Seaweed's masks acted as visual aids to tell a narrative, some containing moveable jaws or hidden wooden hair tendrils that allowed the masks to transform throughout the performance. The Kwakwaka'wakw's winter Hamatsa ceremony was especially elaborate, and the majority of native artwork, including Seaweed's, was meant to be displayed as an active part of the particular ceremony. Seaweed's personal effort to continue making artwork during the potlatch ban was a major factor in preserving traditional Kwakwaka'wakw culture.</Text>
		</Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_URD_KWAK_TEXT">
            <Text>The time has come to freely practice the Potlach, Willie Seaweed, Hilamas, Kwakwaka'wakw chief and revered artist among your people. Defying the authorities, you were taught in your people’s ways of culture, art and language. As the chief of your tribe, you were a source of historical knowledge, a ceremonial leader, and a distributor of wealth. Your career was hampered by a ban on the potlatch ceremony by the Canadian government, however, you continued anyway, despite your art being considered illegal. A pillar of the community, your actions in continuing to practice your customs saved them from being forgotten in history, as you continued to carry the torch of preserving traditional Kwakwaka'wakw culture.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Willie Seaweed, the time has come again to be the torchbearer for the customs of the Kwakwaka'wakw. It is a time of great distress for you people, and they desire another creative spirit such as yourself to aid in carrying the old ways into the future. So open up your copper houses and join your people for another Potlach. Can you expand upon your cultural and artistic legacy? Will you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_URD_KWAK_SHORT">
            <Text>Lands of Supernatural Treasure</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_URD_KWAK">
            <Text>Great Works reduce the [ICON_GOLD] cost of purchasing in all cities, and provide [ICON_FOOD]Food equal to their theming bonus. While below 100 [ICON_GOLD]Gold, animal resources increase the generation of Great Artists, Writers and Musicians. </Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_URD_HAMATSA">
            <Text>Hamatsa Dancer</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_URD_HAMATSA_HELP">
            <Text>Unique Scout for the Kwakwaka'wakw. May remove animal resources in exchange for XP. If destroyed, provides Great Artist points based on its level.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_URD_HAMATSA_STRATEGY">
            <Text></Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_URD_HAMATSA_TEXT">
            <Text>Hamatsa, or the cannibal society, was one of the four Kwakwaka'wakw secret societies. It was the most important secret society, replacing the earlier feminine dance hamshamtses of ancient times. Hamatsas receive their food and gifts before any other potlatch attendee. Only the sons of chiefs are eligible to become a hamatsa. The Man Eater Spirit, Baxbakualanuxsiwae, makes a whistling sound causing the spirit to possess the novice. The novice disappears into the woods, and returns crying and biting members of the audience. The musicians change tempo to match the possessed spirit. Eventually the dancers calm the spirit. The ritual concludes when the new initiate sings his newly-acquired hamatsa song. The novice performs a trick on the final day after a potlatch is held in his honour. The Kwakwaka'wakw of Fort Rupert, the largest of the Kwakwaka'wakw villages at the time of European contact, raided a Heiltsuk canoe in 1835 and stole Hamatsa whistles. The nation subsequently adopted hamatsa dance traditions. Contemporary historians argue that hamatsa initiates were not real cannibals, rather they used fake or real flesh as props of which they did not actually consume.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BLDG_URD_COPPERHOUSE">
            <Text>Copper House</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BLDG_URD_COPPERHOUSE_HELP">
            <Text>May only be bought, though may be bought multiple times. Provides a random animal resource when built the first time, but distributes your gold to all met civs. After this, the cost of future Potlach's increases, while the chance of receiving a resource decreases. </Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BLDG_URD_COPPERHOUSE_STRATEGY">
            <Text></Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BLDG_URD_COPPERHOUSE_TEXT">
            <Text>Copper, or in the language of the Kwakwaka'wakw people, tlakwa, is highly valuable. For the Kwakwaka'wakw, copper symbolises wealth. Each copper has its own name, history and value. Coppers were used along the Northwest Pacific Coast. They were originally made from native copper, or placer copper, which was obtained from Alaska and the Nass River. After contact with Europeans, coppers were made from smelted copper which was considered inferior. Sometimes a Chief would break a copper to show that he was so wealthy that he could afford to damage such a valuable object. The value of a copper rises each time the copper changes hands. The purchase of a copper, its sale or destruction, are all events that occur at a potlatch. The seven coppers were T’lakwadzi, or great copper; T’lakwak’alaga, or copper noise woman; T’lakwagadakw, or copper bodied; T’lakwal’angalis, or long copper in the world; T’lakwagila, or copper maker; Galgatu, or long top; and Max’inuxdzi, or Great Killer Whale Copper. Only chiefs can own coppers and owning a copper is required to conduct certain types of potlatch business.</Text>
        </Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_URD_KWAK">
			<Text>Harvest For Potlatch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_URD_KWAK_HELP">
			<Text>Harvest the animals on this tile, removing them in exchange for XP.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_URD_KWAK_TEXT">
			<Text>you aren't reading this</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_URD_KWAK_REC">
			<Text>Harvest the animals on this tile, removing them in exchange for XP.</Text>
		</Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_URD_HAMATSA">
            <Text>Secret Society</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_URD_HAMATSA_HELP">
            <Text>May remove Animal resources in exchange for XP. If destroyed, provides [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Artist points.</Text>
        </Row>
        <!--Mod Support-->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_URD_KWAK_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
            <Text>Our people are now making copper goods and joining the Hamatsa. I worry that the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
        </Row>
    </Language_en_US>
</GameData>
