<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 6/2/2021 12:13:55 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Mohave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_DESC">
			<Text>Mohave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_DAWN_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings of the Mojave be upon you, Irataba of the Mohave, Aha macave yaltanack and leader of the Colorado River Reservation until your death. Your large size and skill made you a great warrior, but as you aged, your contact among Anglo-Americans and weariness for war led you to become a man of peace, advocating more for diplomacy than frantic action. An adventurer, you led many explorers through the Mohave area and down the Colorado River, forging bonds with those who followed. These bonds helped you become trusted amongst those in Washington D.C., leading you to negotiate terms for the Colorado River Reservation, which you led your people to without armed conflict. Ever the adventurer, you were the first South Western Native leader to meet with a President, Abraham Lincoln, on which journey you were showered with gifts.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Irataba, the Mohave grow restless. They call for a leader who is strong but firm, who can negotiate with adversaries and be trusted to keep the Mohave’s best interests. They call for your might, your wisdom, your courage, and your compassion. They need another old desert giant to lead them to a new age of prosperity. Can you stand tall and broker peace in the desert once more? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>The Mohave</Text>
			<Plurality>2</Plurality>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>The Modern Mohave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Mohave are a Native American people indigenous to the Colorado River in the Mojave Desert. The Fort Mojave Indian Reservation includes territory within the borders of California, Arizona, and Nevada. The Colorado River Indian Reservation includes parts of California and Arizona and is shared by members of the Chemehuevi, Hopi, and Navajo peoples. The original Colorado River and Fort Mojave reservations were established in 1865 and 1870, respectively. Both reservations include substantial senior water rights in the Colorado River; water is drawn for use in irrigated farming. The four combined tribes sharing the Colorado River Indian Reservation function today as one geo-political unit known as the federally recognized Colorado River Indian Tribes; each tribe also continues to maintain and observe its individual traditions, distinct religions, and culturally unique identities. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Culture and Religion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>In religion the Mojave believed in a supreme creator and attached great significance to dreams, which were considered the source of special powers. Public ceremonies included the singing of cycles of dreamed songs that recited myths; usually the narrative retold a mythic or legendary journey, and some cycles consisted of hundreds of songs. The Mohave creator is Matevilya, who gave the people their names and their commandments. His son is Mastamho, who gave them the River and taught them how to plant. Historically this was an agrarian culture; they planted in the fertile floodplain of the untamed river, following the age-old customs of the Aha cave. They have traditionally used the indigenous plant Datura as a deliriant hallucinogen in a religious sacrament. A Mohave who is coming of age must consume the plant in a rite of passage, in order to enter a new state of consciousness.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Mojave language belongs to the River Yuman branch of the Yuman language family. In 1994 approximately 75 people in total on the Colorado River and Fort Mojave reservations spoke the language, according to linguist Leanne Hinton. The tribe has published language materials, and there are new efforts to teach the language to their children.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Oral History and Ancestral Lands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Much of early Mojave history remains unrecorded in writing, since the Mojave language was not written in precolonial times. They depended on oral communication to transmit their history and culture from one generation to the next. Disease, outside cultures and encroachment on their territory disrupted their social organization. Together with having to adapt to a majority culture of another language, this resulted in interrupting the Mojave transmission of their stories and songs to the following generations. The Mojave held lands along the river that stretched from Black Canyon, where the tall pillars of First House of Mutavilya loomed above the river, past Avi kwame or Spirit Mountain, the center of spiritual things, to the Quechan Valley, where the lands of other tribes began. As related to contemporary landmarks, their lands began in the north at Hoover Dam and ended about one hundred miles below Parker Dam on the Colorado River, or aha kwahwat in Mojave.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Increasing Contact with the United States</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The most famous incident in the nineteenth center was the adoption of Olive Oatman after her family was massacred by another tribe, all prior to them living on the reservation. From this point, contact with the United States and Anglo-American settlers became ever more common.  In mid-April 1859, United States troops, led by Lieutenant Colonel William Hoffman, on the Expedition of the Colorado, moved upriver into Mojave country with the well-publicized objective of establishing a military post. By this time, white immigrants and settlers had begun to encroach on Mojave lands and the post was intended to protect east-west European-American emigrants from attack by the Mojave. Hoffman sent couriers among the tribes, warning that the post would be gained by force if they or their allies chose to resist. During this period, several members of the Rose party were massacred by the Mojave. The Mojave warriors withdrew as Hoffman's armada approached and the army, without conflict, occupied land near the future Fort Mojave. Hoffman ordered the Mojave men to assemble on April 23, 1859 at the armed stockade adjacent to his headquarters, to hear Hoffman' terms of peace. Hoffman gave them the choice of submission or extermination and the Mojave chose submission. At that time the Mojave population was estimated to be about 4,000, which composed 22 clans identified by totems. Under American law the Mohave were to live on the Colorado River Reservation after its establishment in 1865. However, many refused to leave their ancestral homes in the Mojave Valley. At this time, under jurisdiction of the War Department, officials declined to try to force them onto the reservation and the Mojave in the area were relatively free to follow their tribal ways. Beginning in August 1890, the Office of Indian Affairs began an intensive program of assimilation where Mohave, and other native children living on reservations, were forced into boarding schools in which they learned to speak, write, and read English. Fort Mojave was converted into a boarding school for local children and other "non-reservation" Indians. Until 1931, forty-one years later, all Fort Mojave boys and girls between the ages of six and eighteen were compelled to live at this school or to attend an advanced Indian boarding school far removed from Fort Mojave. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_HEADING_5">
			<Text>The Breakup of Tribal Culture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT_5">
			<Text>The assimilation helped to break up tribal culture and governments. In addition to English, schools taught American culture and customs and insisted that the children follow them; students were required to adopt European-American hairstyles (which included hair cutting), clothing, habits of eating, sleeping, toiletry, manners, industry, and language. Use of their own language or customs was a punishable offense; at Fort Mojave five lashes of the whip were issued for the first offense. Such corporal punishment of children scandalized the Mojave, who did not discipline their children in that way. As part of the assimilation the administrators assigned English names to the children and registered as members of one of two tribes, the Mojave Tribe on the Colorado River Reservation and the Fort Mojave Indian Tribe on the Fort Mojave Indian Reservation. These divisions did not reflect the traditional Mojave clan and kinship system. By the late 1960s, thirty years after the end of the assimilation program 18 of the 22 traditional clans had survived.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_HEADING_6">
			<Text>The Modern Mohave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_MOHAVE_TEXT_6">
			<Text>This experience was not a positive one for the Mohave, who were known to suffer Hi-wa itck, a tradition describing separation, and typically experienced by men. Symptoms including insomnia, depression, loss of appetite, and possibly suicide. However, the Mohave persist into modernity. Today, the Colorado River Indian Tribes headquarters, library and museum are in Parker, Arizona. The Colorado River Indian Tribes Native American Days Fair and Expo is held annually in Parker.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Leader-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA">
			<Text>Irataba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Origins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Irataba's name derives from the Mohave language phrase eecheeyara tav, which means "beautiful bird". He was born into the Neolge, or Sun Fire clan of the Mohave Nation in around 1814. He lived near a rock formation that gave its name to Needles, south of where the Grand Canyon empties into the Mohave Canyon in present-day Arizona, near the Nevada and California border. In the mid-19th century, the Mohave were composed of three geographical groups; Irataba was the hereditary leader of the Huttoh Pah group, who lived near the east bank of the Colorado River and occupied the central portion of the Mohave Valley. Mohave government consisted of a loose system of hereditary clan leaders with a head of the entire nation. Irataba was a member of the Mohave warrior society called kwanami, who led groups of warriors in battle and were dedicated to defending their lands and people. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Familial relations</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Little is known of Irataba's family relations, except for the name of his son Tekse thume, and his nephews Qolho qorau (Irataba's sister's son who succeeded him as leader) and Aspamekelyeho. Olive Oatman, who lived with the Mohave for five years, later stated that Irataba was the brother of the former chief, presumably Cairook, with whom Irataba clearly had a close relation. One anecdotal description states that Irataba had several wives, among them a Hualapai woman who had been taken as a captive and who is also described as having a young son. He also had at least one daughter, the mother of his granddaughter Tcatc.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Style</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>In contemporary accounts Irataba was described as an eloquent speaker, and linguist Leanne Hinton suggests that he was among the first Mohave people to become fluent in English, which he learned through his many interactions with Anglo-Americans. Like many Mohave men, Irataba was very tall, particularly by 19th-century standards; the United States Army estimated his height at 6 feet 4 inches (193 cm) in 1861, leading to the nickname “the old desert giant”. Edward Carlson, a soldier based at Fort Mohave who knew Irataba well in the 1860s, described him as having a powerful frame, but also a "very gentle" and "kind ... demeanor".</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>His times</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Irataba lived through a tumultuous period of Mohave history where the people went from being a politically independent nation to coming under the political control of the United States, and the events surrounding his role in these encounters are well documented. Most historical sources for the life of Irataba come from descriptions by white explorers or government agents with whom he interacted, or from contemporary newspapers that reported on his visits to the East Coast and California, and on the conflicts in Arizona territory. Some Mohave versions of the events also exist, with many interviews in the 20th Century spreading light on this ponderous man.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Irataba’s adventures; the Colorado, Whipple Expedition</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Irataba assisted Captain Lorenzo Sitgreaves during his 1851 exploration of the Colorado. During this time, the Mohave adopted two kidnapped children into the Oach clan, where they lived with a friend of Irataba. This is possibly where Irataba learned of Anglo-American culture and may account for his friendly disposition toward them. On February 23, 1854, Irataba, Cairook, and other Mohave people encountered an expedition led by military officers Amiel Whipple and J.C. Ives, as the group approached the Colorado en route to California. Whipple and his men counted six hundred Mohave gathered near their camp, trading corn, beans, squash (plant), and wheat for beads and calico. When the expedition had difficulty crossing the Colorado on February 27, several Mohave jumped into the water and helped salvage the supplies. Irataba and Cairook agreed to escort the group across the territory of the Paiute to the Old Spanish Trail that would take them to southern California. German artist Balduin Möllhausen accompanied the Whipple expedition, and made drawings of several Mohave, including Irataba. Möllhausen's drawings were featured in Ives' 1861 congressional report, making Irataba "among the first named likenesses of California Indians ever published".</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Down the River, the Ives Expedition</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_6">
			<Text>In February 1858, Ives returned to the area in a paddle steamer named Explorer. He was leading an expedition up the Colorado from the south, and he wanted Irataba to guide them. The Mohave gave permission to navigate the river, and Cairook, Irataba, and a 16-year-old Mohave boy named Nahvahroopa joined them. Möllhausen again accompanied the expedition, and was impressed with the Mohave guides, later noting Irataba's enthusiastic handshake and lamenting that their only form of communication was sign language. He also noted that Irataba and the Mohave readily began wearing European clothes given to them by members of the expedition, and showed great interest in smoking tobacco. Irataba guided the party into the Mohave Canyon, indicating the location of rapids and advising the Explorer's pilot of convenient places to anchor while camping for the night. When they reached the entrance to the Black Canyon of the Colorado, the ship crashed against a submerged rock, throwing several men overboard, dislodging the boiler, and damaging the wheelhouse. Using their skiff, the crew towed the Explorer to the shore, where they camped for three days while repairing the vessel. The expedition had relied on beans and corn provided by the Mohave during the previous weeks; as their supplies dwindled they grew increasingly anxious about the arrival of a resupply pack train from Fort Yuma. Irataba volunteered to hike towards the Mohave Valley to try to locate the supplies that had been requested several days earlier. He also warned that the expedition was being watched by Paiutes. When Irataba returned he informed Ives that he would not venture any deeper into the territory of the Hualapais, but agreed to help them locate friendly guides in the region before parting company. Irataba was reluctant to venture into the canyon because he feared the party would be ambushed by Paiutes aligned with Mormons, who were in conflict with the United States. After enlisting three Hualapai guides, Irataba prepared to take his leave from the expedition and return to the Mohave community. On April 4, the Mohave received payment for their services; Möllhausen described the exchange: "Lieutenant Ives informed Irataba that he had been authorized by the 'Great Grandfather in Washington' to give him two mules ... for his loyalty and his trustworthiness so that he could take his possessions and those of his companions more conveniently to his home valley." The next morning, as they were preparing to leave: "Irataba was visibly moved ... and in his sincere eyes expressed so much honesty and loyalty as can only be found in an unspoiled nature ... I maintain that there was not one in our expedition who did not feel a certain sadness to see this huge man with ... a harmless soul leave."</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Death in the Mohave </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_7">
			<Text>The Mohave were aware that whites were immigrating to the region in increasing numbers. This was, of course, a concern. It was difficult for the Mohave to predict the behavior of the arriving whites, some of whom, like Whipple, were amiably disposed towards them, whereas others such as the Mormons were hostile. The kwanami were divided on how the situation should be approached; some advocated an aggressive posture, denying whites all passage through their territory, but others, including Irataba, preferred a peaceful approach, or even an alliance with them that could put the Mohave in a stronger position relative to their traditional enemies the Paiute, Chemehuevi, and Walapai. On September 1, 1857, a joint force of Mohave and Quechan warriors launched a major attack with hundreds of warriors on a Maricopa village close to Maricopa Wells, Arizona, on the Gila River. The Battle of Pima Butte was described by a group of white mail carriers who witnessed it. They stated that the battle was fought mostly with clubs, as well as bows and arrows, and that probably more than 100 warriors died, most of them from the attacking party. It is unknown whether Irataba participated in the attack, but given his status as kwanami, it is likely that he did. The battle has been described as the last major battle involving only Native American nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_8">
			<Text>The Mohave Wars</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_8">
			<Text>In 1858, the Rose-Baley Party comprising at least a hundred settlers with wagons and a large herd of cattle, was the first emigrant train to venture onto Beale's Wagon Road, a road established not a year before. Upon entering Mohave territory, the settlers started cutting down cottonwood trees, which were an important resource for the Mohave. The most warlike of the kwanamis organized an attack on the party and drove away and slaughtered many of the party's cattle. On August 30, three hundred Mohave warriors attacked the emigrants but were repelled, with one member of the party killed in battle and eleven wounded. Another family who was not with the main party during the attack were killed in an event that has often been blamed on the Mohave, but which in Colonel William Hoffman's opinion was more likely carried out by a band of Walapai, along with seven renegade Mohave. Irataba was away at Fort Yuma during the attack on the settlers, and upon hearing of it he scolded the Mohave. Chooksa homar participated in the events and reported that Irataba told the warriors, "I hear you fought, though I told you not to. And you will have war again: I know it. You used to fight the Maricopa. I want to go [to Phoenix] to see the Maricopa and tell them: 'The Mohave will not come any more to attack you'." Irataba, weary of the constant fighting and worried that further conflicts with neighboring tribes would draw more attention from the US soldiers, organized a peace expedition to the Maricopa, settling the ancient disputes between the two peoples.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When news of the attack reached California, the US War Department decided to establish a military fort at Beale's Crossing to keep the Mohave under control and secure white travelers safe passage through Mohave lands. Irataba attempted to arrange a peaceful meeting, but Hoffman ordered his troops to fire on the warriors, who counterattacked and repelled the force. On April 23, at Hoffman's request, he and his officers met with several hundred Mohave warriors and their leaders. Hoffman gave the Mohave a choice between war and peace, and he demanded that they agree to never again harm white settlers along the wagon trail. He also declared that, as punishment, the Mohave were required to surrender as hostages a member of each clan and three warriors who had taken part in the attack. He also demanded the chief who ordered the attack to offer himself as hostahe. According to Chooksa homar, the chief who had ordered the attack was Homoseh quahote, who was reluctant to give himself up. Cairook offered himself in his place, along with eight others, including Tokwatha, Irataba's son Tekse thume, and Irataba's nephews Qolho qorau, and Aspamekelyeho. After Hoffman left, many U.S. soldiers to begin construction on the Beale's Crossing fort, which was named Fort Mohave.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In July 1861, the commander of Fort Mohave, Major Lewis Armistead, ordered soldiers to fire into a group of Mohave who he suspected of having attacked a mail carrier and slaughtered his mule. The Mohave did not respond violently to the attack, but Armistead decided to punish them for harassing the mail party. He arrived at Irataba's ranch where a group of Mohave boys were planting beans, and from a hidden position he shot one of the planters, killing him. The attack on Irataba's ranch is remembered by the Mohave as "the first and last battle with the Federal Troops."</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Rise to Aha macave yaltanack</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_9">
			<Text>After Cairook's death, whites living near the Colorado River began to view Irataba as the main leader of the Mohave. He had become Aha macave yaltanack (leader of the Mohave Nation) or hochoch (leader elected by the people). By the mid-1860s a deep rift had developed between Irataba, who was proactive in cooperating with white settlers, and Homoseh quahote, who passively tolerated but did not approve of white encroachment on Mohave lands. Irataba was Aha macave yaltanack of the Mohave from 1861 to 1866, but from 1867 to 1869 opinions differ, and by 1870 US government correspondence suggests that Homoseh quahote had succeeded him as leader of the Fort Mohave group.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The completion of Fort Mohave began the process of military subjugation of the Mohave, and the next step was the establishment of reservations. In 1863, Charles Debrille Poston, the first Superintendent of Indian Affairs of the Arizona Territory, called a conference between the Chemehuevi and Irataba's faction of the Mohave, in which he convinced them to form an alliance with the US against the Apache. The treaty was never ratified by the US Congress but formed an important step in establishing friendly relations between the Mohave and the US government following the military campaigns and the establishment of Fort Mohave. Poston promoted the idea of establishing a reservation in the southern portion of Mohave country. Many Mohave opposed the proposed location and instead argued for a smaller parcel further north in the Mohave Valley, which had more fertile land. With Irataba and an engineer, Poston traveled down the Colorado River to survey a location. In August 1864 the post commander at Fort Mohave, Captain Charles Atchisson, stated that Irataba was against the proposed location. Faced with Irataba's disagreement, Poston promised that the US government would assist the Mohave with installing an irrigation system at the Colorado that would make most of the reservation arable. This apparently convinced Irataba, who traveled to the Colorado River Valley with about 800 people, almost a fifth of the entire Mohave Nation. Most of the Mohave refused to leave their ancestral homelands for the reservation, but Irataba's conviction that the reservation was their best option marked the beginning of a rift between his group and those who stayed behind to follow Homoseh quahote, the nation's hereditary leader.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_10">
			<Text>Mining and adventuring</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_10">
			<Text>As related above, during the early 1860s, Irataba befriended prospectors as a guide. One of them was John Moss, whom Irataba had shown the location of a gold mine in the Mojave Desert, which Moss later sold. Moss suggested Irataba be invited to Washington so that he could see firsthand the United States' military might. In November 1863, Irataba traveled with Moss to San Pedro, Los Angeles, where they boarded the steamship Senator, bound for San Francisco. In San Francisco, he stayed at the Occidental Hotel and created a storm as he walked down Jackson Street, dressed in clothing typical of European Americans, which Irataba soon preferred to traditional Mohave clothing. The press documented his every movement and wrote extensively about his physical size and strong features. In January 1864 they sailed for the Isthmus of Panama on board the Orizaba, then traveled onwards to New York City. Upon Irataba's arrival in New York, Harper's Weekly described him as "the finest specimen of unadulterated aboriginal on this continent". Here Irataba exchanged his suit and sombrero for the uniform and regalia of a major general, including a bright yellow sash, a gold badge encrusted with precious stones, and a medal with the inscription, "Irataba, Chief of the Mohaves, Arizona Territory". Irataba moved on to Philadelphia and Washington, D.C., where he earned great acclaim; government officials and military officers lavished him with gifts of medals, swords, and photographs. In Washington he met with President Abraham Lincoln, who gave him a silver-headed cane. He was the first Native American from the Southwest to meet an American president. The tour ended in April, when he and Moss sailed to California, again by way of Panama, and made their way back to Beale's Crossing from Los Angeles by wagon. Upon Irataba's return from Washington D.C., he met with the Mohave while dressed in his major general's uniform, with medals. He wore a European-style hat and carried a long Japanese sword, and he told the Mohave about all the things he had seen. He tried to convince them that peace with the United States was in their best interests, and that war against them was futile, stressing their dominant military capabilities. Many Mohave were skeptical of his reports and reacted with disbelief.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_HEADING_11">
			<Text>Later years and legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TEXT_11">
			<Text>Irataba continued to lead the Colorado River band of Mohave during the 1860s. He pursued peaceful relations with the surrounding tribes and cooperated actively with US authorities. He also helped the Yavapai and Walapai in ongoing conflicts with Paiutes and Chemehuevi. In March 1865, Irataba and the Mohave defeated the Chemehuevi after their allies, the Paiutes, killed two Mohave women. During a subsequent battle with the Chemehuevi in October 1865, Irataba was taken prisoner while wearing his major general's uniform. According to a contemporary news report based on secondhand accounts from white travelers, the captors feared that killing him would invite repercussions from the soldiers stationed at Fort Mohave, so they instead stripped him naked and sent him home badly beaten. In the Mohave account of the events as told by Chooksa homar, Irataba surrendered in an effort to make peace with the Chemehuevi and offered his uniform to their chief as a gesture of peace. In 1867, a treaty signed by Irataba and the Chemehuevi leader Pan Coyer restored peaceful relations between the two nations. Irataba also welcomed bands of Yavapai onto the reservation after they had been subject to massacres by US troops or suffered starvation due to having been driven from their lands. The meager resources of the reservation proved unable to sustain the additional population and eventually the Yavapai had to leave. Irataba frequently served as a mediator between Yavapai and Walapai who had become embroiled in conflicts with the US army and participated in peace parlays. The Colorado River band of Mohave never replaced Irataba; he was their leader when he died at their reservation on May 3 or 4, 1874. His cause of death is unknown, but smallpox and natural causes are both cited. The Mohave grieved deeply; Irataba's cremation and the rituals of mourning were reported in newspapers as far away as Omaha, Nebraska. Irataba was succeeded as leader on the Colorado Reservation by his nephew, Qolho qorau of the Vemacka clan, who upheld his uncle's policies.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Among the Mohave, to some, he is a hero, to others a white collaborator. But in his work for peace, He undeniably left his mark. Former CRIT Museum Director Dr. Michael Tsosie stated, "Irataba understood the Mohave people would need to keep fighting to keep what they had." He noted that the Colorado River Indian Reservation "is unique in American history in that they have not lost any land".</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_LIVED">
			<Text>1814 - 1874 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_NAME">
			<Text>Irataba/Yara Tav</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of The Mohave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Aha Macave Yaltanack</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_IRATABA_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Hochoch</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Trait-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SAS_IRATABA_SHORT">
			<Text>The Old Desert Giant</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SAS_IRATABA">
			<Text>When a city is founded, the locations of all nearby Oases and Luxury Resources in Desert are revealed. Receive [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness from exchanged Embassies. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Kwanami-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_KWANAMI">
			<Text>Kwanami</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_KWANAMI_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Longswordsman for the Mohave that does not require [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron and begins with the Amphibious promotion. During Peace, garrisoned Kwanami may extend the length of We Love The King Days. During War, promoting a Kwanami starts a short We Love The King Day in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_KWANAMI_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Irataba's unique Longswordsman, these units do not require [ICON_RES_IRON] Iron and begin with the Amphibious promotion. While at Peace, garrisoned Kwanami may extend the length of WLTKD in their city, and while at War, promoting a Kwanami starts a short WLTKD in all cities. Keep Kwanami close to home if you're at Peace, or send them into the frontlines during War, particularly for cross-river or naval assaults!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_KWANAMI_TEXT">
			<Text>The Kwanami, roughly translated to "brave men", were the group responsible for battle among the Mohave. According to Stewart, the Kwanami acted as essentially a different class among the Mohave, of which there was very little effective control, and which were set apart from their tribesfellows' pacifistic ways by an "obsession" for war. The wasauwic, roughly translated as "all the warriors" was an informal association of the kwanamis. There were roughly forty or fifty in the tribe, and they were all men of prestige who had received the the proper dreams (sumach ahot) for power in war. As they operated as a rough warrior class, they could sometime be even be considered to outrank the tribal chief in the respect of war. Although not the only ones to war, they often led it. The dreams of a kwanami began at birth, or even while the unborn child was still in his mother's womb. In his dreams spirits appeared to him, conferring power, instructing him in proper modes of fighting, and teaching him how to avoid injury in combat. The kwanami dreamed of the hawk, of fighting and killing ferocious animals. They were unlike any other Mohave, they lived in strict conditions, did not farm, thought little of carnal pleasures, and were often aloof from other tribe members.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_KWANAMI_PROMO">
			<Text>Sumach Ahot</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_KWANAMI_PROMO_HELP">
			<Text>During Peacetime, may extend the length of We Love The King Day in its garrisoned city. During War, earning Promotions starts a short We Love The King Day in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Kutinyam-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_KUTINYAM">
			<Text>Kutinyam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_KUTINYAM_PEDIA">
			<Text>In Mohave religion and society, nothing is more important than dreaming. It was not lineage or qualification that ordained the roles of society's most powerful political, military, and spiritual leaders, but dreams. If a man did not learn a hereditary song or story through his dreams alone, he was ostracized and considered a fraud. A man may admit under duress that he had been taught it by a relative, but assure that his dreams taught him that he'd never forget it. Most dreams (called 'Sumach' in Mohave) are believed to have at least some significance in the waking world to the dreamer, serving sometimes as premonitions. If a hunter or military leader had an unlucky dream, the hunt or the raid would be called off that day. Extremely rare dreams, called 'Sumach Ahot' or 'great dreams', are those that determine the roles of society's most powerful men. A sumach ahot was the single most important event of any Mohave man's life, and could occur to anyone at any time. However, those determined to raise the odds and attempt to sus out a sumach ahot could take certain measures. Performing certain rituals, imbibing Datura or other psychoactives, fasting, and spending time in a special Kutinyam (or 'dark house') were among the options available in this endeavor. Kutinyams are not to be confused with Ava Kutinyam, the 'Great Dark House', which is the site of Creation itself that the souls of dreamers travel to during a sumach ahot. More specifically, the Mohave believed that sumach ahot were actually pre-natal memories, retained from when their human soul was first created by Mastamho in the Great Dark House, at the dawn of time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_KUTINYAM_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Temple for the Mohave. Provides less [ICON_PEACE] Faith than the building it replaces, but provides +1 [ICON_PEACE] Faith per worked River tile. While this city is in We Love The King Day, River tiles will also yield +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food if at Peace, or +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold if at War. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_KUTINYAM_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Temple for the Mohave. Provides less [ICON_PEACE] Faith than the building it replaces, but provides +1 [ICON_PEACE] Faith per worked River tile. While this city is in We Love The King Day, River tiles will also yield +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food if at Peace, or +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold if at War. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_9">
			<Text>Hanyeh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_8">
			<Text>Maiman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_7">
			<Text>Hobelia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_6">
			<Text>Cairook</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_5">
			<Text>Aespaneo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_4">
			<Text>Homoseh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_3">
			<Text>Spantsa Oach</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_2">
			<Text>Tokwatha</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_1">
			<Text>Charley-Arri-Wa-Wa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_MOHAVE_0">
			<Text>Aspamekelyeho</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_1">
			<Text>Avi Kwa Ame</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_2">
			<Text>Hokusave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_3">
			<Text>Aha Kwahwat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_4">
			<Text>Kwaparvete</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_5">
			<Text>Huukyámpve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_6">
			<Text>Avi Mota</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_7">
			<Text>Selye'aya-ita</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_8">
			<Text>Aha Kwi Nyamasave</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_9">
			<Text>Miakwa'orve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_10">
			<Text>Avi Halywa'ampa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_11">
			<Text>Ioo-kuva'ire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_12">
			<Text>Kamahnulya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_13">
			<Text>Avi Hamoka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_14">
			<Text>Qapotaq-iv'auve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_15">
			<Text>Hukoara-ts-huerve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_16">
			<Text>Avi Veskwi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_17">
			<Text>Aqwaqa-have</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_18">
			<Text>Avi Melyehweke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_19">
			<Text>Amat-kusaye</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_20">
			<Text>Mukiampeve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_21">
			<Text>Selye'aya-kumitse</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_22">
			<Text>Ha'avulypo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_23">
			<Text>Hoturveve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_24">
			<Text>Avi Tsierqe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_25">
			<Text>Qara'erve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_26">
			<Text>Mukiampeve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_27">
			<Text>Hakwinyava</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_28">
			<Text>Oyats-ukyulve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_29">
			<Text>Ahtsye-'aksamta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_30">
			<Text>Hakutsyepa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_MOHAVE_31">
			<Text>Avi Kwi Nyamaoave</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: VANILLA -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_SAS_MOHAVE_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now practicing dream diviation and eating hominy. I worry the rest of the world will soon succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Come cool yourself and your party in the waters of the river, weary traveler. I give you my promise that you may safely rest and be fed here, as well, for I am Aha Macave Yaltanack, Yara Tav.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome, honored dignitary. Please, rest yourself by the cool water of the river. I am Irataba, Aha Macave Yaltanack who has seen my people through many battles and achieved peace. As you can see, I am adorned with the gifts of tribes far and wide. ...Do you have something for me, too?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I am so weary of the bloodshed. Dark and cheerless are my skies... Please... make it stop. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>There must be some other way... but if you want war, then there shall be war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>I feel there is much we may learn from your nation, and I would love to tour your cities. It would please me greatly if you would join me in a public declaration of friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I cannot deal peaceably with you any longer.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I wish it had not come to this.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>I have tried to hold back our warriors for so many years, but I now see things the way they do. The time of freedom for my people has come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_IRATABA_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>I hope you will reconsider.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>