<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
	<!-- Civilization -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_ANGOLA_TITLE">
			<Text>Angola</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JWW_ANGOLA_DESC">
			<Text>Democratic People's Republic of Angola</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JWW_ANGOLA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Angola</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JWW_ANGOLA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Angolan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_JWW_ANGOLA_TEXT">
			<Text>Your journey to victory has begun, oh glorious Jonas Savimbi! Death to the MPLA! Born in a small town in Portuguese controlled Angola, after obtaining a scholarship in Portugal, you climbed in student circles for Angolan independence, seeking a leadership position in the MPLA by joining the MPLA Youth. Rebuffed, you founded UNITA and began your career as an anti-Portuguese guerrilla fighter. Fighting Portugal, the FNLA and MPLA, you eventually drew the attention of powerful international actors, and were trained in Maoist guerilla practices, which led to one of the most effective guerrilla leaders of the 20th century. Renouncing the support of communism, you sought U.S. backing, using your skills as a leader and talent in speaking seven languages to become one of the most vocal anti-communists of the Third World. But after surviving more than a dozen assassination attempts, your luck would finally run out, dieing in battle in the province of your birth.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Commander Savimbi, your resoluteness and intellect is needed in Angola, more than ever. Its people cry out as humanitarian crises grip the nation you loved. Can you stand and fulfil the promise of Angola, not repeating past mistakes? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Trait -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JWW_THREE_DAY_HALLOWEEN">
			<Text>Defeating enemy units on their mines will pillage the mine and grant a free [ICON_RES_JWW_BLOOD_DIAMONDS] Blood Diamonds luxury resource until the war is over. For every newly acquired luxury resource connected to Angola, you get a free random land unit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JWW_THREE_DAY_HALLOWEEN_SHORT">
			<Text>Three-Day Halloween</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Leader -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI">
			<Text>Jonas Savimbi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_LIVED">
			<Text>1934 - 2002 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NAME">
			<Text>Jonas Malheiro Savimbi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>President and Supreme Commander of UNITA</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Founder of UNITA</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Building -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_DIAMANG_MINE">
			<Text>Diamang Mine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_DIAMANG_MINE_HELP">
			<Text>Can only Be built by Jonas Savimbi's Angola. Replaces the Stoneworks, but does not need the requirements of the Stoneworks. Trade Deals involving luxuries in city limits have a chance to grant extra [ICON GOLD]gold, [ICON_PRODUCTION]production, workers, or combat units. Units are trained faster for each luxury in this city that is traded away.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_DIAMANG_MINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unlike the Stoneworks it replaces, it does not need any of the requirements for Stoneworks. Trade deals involving luxuries worked by this city will train units faster, and have a chance to grant [ICON_GOLD], [ICON_PRODUCTION], workers, or combat units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JWW_DIAMANG_TRAIN_UNITS">
			<Text>Diamang Mine Dummy</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Unit -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JWW_T55">
			<Text>T-55</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JWW_T55_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Can only be built by Jonas Savimbi's Angola. Replaces the Tank. Instead of dying, T-55s are instead captured by the enemy. Angolan units will have a combat bonus in territories of Civs that have a captured T-55. Recapturing T-55s grant Golden Age Points. T-55s can only be reclaimed by Angola once, next time a T-55 runs out of health, they will die.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_JWW_T55">
			<Text>Replaces the Tank. When T55s are defeated, they are captured by the enemy, giving Angolan units a combat boost against civilizations with a T55. These T55s can be reclaimed by Angola, but only once.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JWW_T55_RECLAIMED">
			<Text>T-55 Reclaimed!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JWW_T55_RECLAIMED_HELP">
			<Text>This T-55 has already been reclaimed once by Angola, so the next time it is defeated, it will die.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JWW_T55_CAPTURED">
			<Text>T-55 Captured!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JWW_T55_CAPTURED_HELP">
			<Text>The Enemy has captured our tanks! Fight to take them back! Death to the MPLA! (+25% Combat Strength)</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Resource -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_JWW_BLOOD_DIAMONDS">
			<Text>Blood Diamonds</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_JWW_BLOOD_DIAMONDS_HELP">
			<Text>Luxury Resource unique to Angola. Gained when Angola defeats enemy units on their mine plots.</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Civilopedia -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_UNIT_JWW_T55_TEXT">
			<Text>A mainstay of Soviet-aligned armies throughout the Cold War, the T-55 is a powerful battle tank which became the most produced armour unit in history. The tank was an evolution of those seen across the battlefields of World War Two, and had both a dependability and ruggedness which made it perfect for the post-colonial conflicts of the Cold War. Following support from the Soviets, the tanks became a frequent feature in both Angola and Mozambique during the 1970s, where the Marxist governments of these states used them with deadly efficiency in conflicts across southern Africa. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Jonas Savimbi, in full Jonas Malheiro Savimbi was an Angolan revolutionary politician and military leader who founded and led the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola (UNITA). UNITA waged a guerrilla war against Portuguese colonial rule from 1966 to 1974 then confronted the People's Movement for the Liberation of Angola during the Angolan Civil War.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The son of a railroad stationmaster, Savimbi was educated in mission schools and won a scholarship to study abroad. He studied medicine at the University of Lisbon in Portugal and then obtained a doctorate in political science at the University of Lausanne, Switzerland, in 1965. In 1961 Savimbi joined the Angolan independence leader Holden Roberto’s Popular Union of Angola (UPA), the rival of the Popular Movement for the Liberation of Angola (MPLA). He broke with the UPA’s leader in 1966 and formed the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola (UNITA), which fought against Portuguese colonial rule.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>The Angolan Civil War</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Savimbi was the only Angolan guerrilla leader who continued fighting within Angola until the nation reached independence from Portugal in 1975; by this time he had expanded his initially small band of supporters into a guerrilla army numbering in the thousands. UNITA was based in southeastern Angola and relied for its support on the Ovimbundu people, the largest ethnic group in the country. At various times, Savimbi obtained support from China, South Africa, and the United States as a counter to the Marxist, Soviet-supported MPLA, which controlled the central government. Savimbi continued to wage a disruptive guerrilla war against the MPLA throughout the 1970s and ’80s. In 1991 he signed a peace agreement with the MPLA-led Angolan government that halted the civil war and resulted in free, multiparty national elections in 1992. After losing these elections, Savimbi and UNITA resumed their military struggle for control of the country, with UNITA dominating most of the countryside. Talks were held again, leading to the Lusaka Accord of 1994: hostilities were to cease and forces were to be disengaged. José Eduardo dos Santos, president of Angola, offered Savimbi one of two vice-presidential positions, and UNITA was also to be part of the government. Savimbi subsequently rejected the position and was officially designated leader of the opposition in 1997, a position that was rescinded in 1998. In 1996 Savimbi indicated that he would retain control of the lucrative diamond regions in northeastern Angola, although some were transferred to the government in 1998.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Final years and death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Savimbi faced opposition from within UNITA in September 1998 when a group calling itself UNITA-R suspended him and became the self-declared leadership. From that point UNITA was split into three factions. The Angolan government and the Southern African Development Community recognized UNITA-R as the official representative of UNITA. Nevertheless, Savimbi requested the renewal of negotiations in March 2001, and he further indicated a willingness to accept the terms of the Lusaka Accord. While the government demanded a cease-fire as a condition for initiating new talks and Savimbi called for the Roman Catholic Church to mediate the dispute, fighting continued throughout 2001 and spilled into the neighbouring countries of Zambia and Namibia. After surviving more than a dozen assassination attempts, and having been reported dead at least 15 times, Savimbi was killed on 22 February 2002, in a battle with Angolan government troops along riverbanks in the province of Moxico, his birthplace. In the firefight, Savimbi sustained 15 gunshot wounds to his head, throat, upper body and legs. While Savimbi returned fire, his wounds proved fatal; he died almost instantly. Savimbi’s somewhat mystical reputation for eluding the Angolan military and their Soviet and Cuban military advisors led many Angolans to question the validity of reports of his 2002 death. Not until pictures of his bloodied and bullet-riddled body appeared on Angolan state television did the reports of Savimbi’s death in combat gain credence in the country. After Savimbi’s death, a peace agreement between UNITA and the Angolan government was signed in April 2002.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_JWW_DIAMANG_MINE_TEXT">
			<Text>The mineral wealth of southern Africa made the region a prime target for the colonial powers of Europe, who reaped the wealth of the land with no benefit to those who lived locally. In Angola, there was no representation of this exploitation more than the mines of the Diamang company - owned by the West to profit off of Angola's natural wealth. Following independence, the mines were nationalised with the wealth to return to Angola and usher in new prosperity for the fledgling nation. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_RESOURCE_JWW_BLOOD_DIAMONDS_TEXT">
			<Text>For those facing the rising costs of insurgency, a region's mineral wealth can be a useful means to support their cause. Throughout the African continent, diamonds are frequently mined by warring factions and sold internationally (increasingly on the black market) to finance the faction's war effort. Blood diamonds first came to prominence in Angola, where an estimated 21% of all diamonds produced in the 1980s were sold to support illegal or unethical purposes. This continued despite efforts by the UN to eliminate the illegal diamond trade, and remained a stain on the collective consciences of the global diamond industry for decades to come.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_JWW_ANGOLA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVILIZATIONS_JWW_ANGOLA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>A large country, Angola takes in a broad variety of landscapes, including the semidesert Atlantic littoral bordering Namibia’s “Skeleton Coast,” the sparsely populated rainforest interior, the rugged highlands of the south, the Cabinda exclave in the north, and the densely settled towns and cities of the northern coast and north-central river valleys. The capital and commercial centre is Luanda, a large port city on the northern coast that blends Portuguese-style colonial landmarks with traditional African housing styles and modern industrial complexes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Angola at the beginning of the 21st century was a country ravaged by war and the related effects of land mines and malnutrition, and it was often dependent on the international community for the basics of survival. It is a country that is nevertheless rich in natural resources, including precious gems, metals, and petroleum; indeed, it ranks among the highest of the oil-producing countries in sub-Saharan Africa. It is the largest and wealthiest of the Portuguese-speaking African states, and Portuguese influences have been felt for some 500 years, although Angola acquired its present boundaries only in 1891. An anticolonial struggle that began in 1961 finally led to independence in 1975.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In “We Must Return,” a poem he wrote from prison in 1956, the Angolan poet Agostinho Neto, who was also the country’s first president, described Angola as “red with coffee / white with cotton / green with maize” and as “our land, our mother.” Unfortunately, Neto’s happiness with a “liberated Angola—Angola independent” did not last long, and a civil war that went on 27 years left much of the country in ruins. Beginning in 2002, however, with the ending of the war, Angola had more hope for a peaceful future than it had in the previous quarter century.</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Diplomacy Responses -->
		<!-- First Greeting -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I'm Jonas Savimbi, and I'm fighting to make Angola a true democratic nation. Are you here to join me in arms, brother?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NETO_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Agostinho Neto! So we meet again. Just so you know, I, Jonas Savimbi, and my brothers will not hesitate to fight against you and the MPLA's non-democratic ways!</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Defeated -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Even when all seems hopeless, I will continue to fight for Angola's freedom. You'll have to shoot me dead to stop me from fighting you, even if I'm the last brother standing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NETO_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I fear for the future of my brothers. I cannot rest with the MPLA in power. You will be the death of our country.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Diplomacy: Wars, Denunciations, and DoF -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_ATTACKED_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>Brothers, take up your arms. We will not submit to them!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>We need to join in arms fight the terrors of communism. Are you with me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Do you not wish for the individual freedoms of not just your people, but the people of mankind who so deserve it?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NETO_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Neto, you believe in God... Do you think your cause is blessed by God?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>Our journey to victory has begun! Death to all who oppose us!!!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NETO_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>Neto, I can't overlook the wrongdoings of the MPLA any longer. Death to the MPLA!!!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>With you controlling territory so close, UNITA may need to move out and reclaim these lands.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>We will not back down. Fight on, my brothers!!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Weclome back, brother. Need another shipment of Diamonds?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>It's not often we speak. Care to join our cause?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>You believe in God... Do you believe your cause is blessed by God?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NETO_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Finally decide to submit to UNITA?</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Misc -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I hope those guns you have nearby are for me. But if that's not that case, my brothers are itching for another victory...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_LETS_HEAR_IT_1">
			<Text>And this is a worthy deal how?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_LOSEWAR_1">
			<Text>The fire of war finished some of us. However, we must press on, before we join our brothers in death.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>We have many luxuries that may suit your liking.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>You are weak!!! Come my brothers, we must finish them!!!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE">
			<Text>The quickest way to battle may be through our lands. Let us fight together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_REPEAT_NO_1">
			<Text>You realize that with an awful deal such as this, I would benefit from nothing?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>I need aid for my cause. Help me fight on!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Nothing can stop us on our path to victory. If you're in our way, we will finish you as well.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Our journey to victory has only just begun!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>Rejoice, my brothers! We are victorious!</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Cultural Influence -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now mining diamonds and hating communism. I worry the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_JONAS_SAVIMBI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>We are glad to see that your people are now mining diamonds and hating communism. The amazing works of our civilization are truly inspiring!</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- City Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_0">
			<Text>Huambo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_1">
			<Text>Ambriz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_2">
			<Text>Luanda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_3">
			<Text>Cabinda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_4">
			<Text>Lubango</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_5">
			<Text>Kuito</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_6">
			<Text>Malanje</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_7">
			<Text>Lobito</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_8">
			<Text>Benguela</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_9">
			<Text>Moçâmedes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_10">
			<Text>Luena</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_11">
			<Text>Saurimo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_12">
			<Text>Soyo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_13">
			<Text>Sumbe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_14">
			<Text>N'dalatando</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_15">
			<Text>Caála</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_16">
			<Text>Cubal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_17">
			<Text>Dundo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_18">
			<Text>Negage</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_19">
			<Text>M'banza-Kongo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_20">
			<Text>Bailundo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_21">
			<Text>Menongue</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_22">
			<Text>Dondo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_23">
			<Text>Uku</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_24">
			<Text>Lucapa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_25">
			<Text>Waku Kungo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_26">
			<Text>Andulo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_27">
			<Text>Ganga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_28">
			<Text>Caluquembe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_29">
			<Text>Cafunfo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_30">
			<Text>Nzagi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_31">
			<Text>Catabola</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_32">
			<Text>Ondijiva</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_33">
			<Text>Dombe Grande</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_34">
			<Text>Lândana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_35">
			<Text>Quimavongo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_36">
			<Text>Catchiungo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_37">
			<Text>Baia Farta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_38">
			<Text>Dongo</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_0">
			<Text>António</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_1">
			<Text>Jeremias</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_2">
			<Text>Isaías</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_3">
			<Text>Samwimbila</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_4">
			<Text>Jorge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_5">
			<Text>Kafundanga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_6">
			<Text>Paulo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_7">
			<Text>Dinho</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_8">
			<Text>Adalberto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_ANGOLA_9">
			<Text>Arlete</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>