<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 10/23/2021 1:00:32 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Ugandan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_DESC">
			<Text>Ugandan Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_DAWN_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT">
			<Text>Hail, His Excellency, President for Life, Field Marshal Al Hadji Doctor Idi Amin Dada, VC, DSO, MC, CBE, Lord of All the Beasts of the Earth and Fishes of the Seas and Conqueror of the British Empire in Africa in General and Uganda in Particular. Rising from the King’s African Rifles to become Uganda’s top military commander, your brutal military dictatorship earned you the nicknames Butcher of Uganda, Butcher of Kampala, and Black Hitler. Initially promising to hold elections, your regime became increasing tied to the Second World, along with increasingly brutal tactics. Ethnic and political minorities disappeared, and you bragged of having their heads in your freezer. But you didn’t care. You ruled by decree, treating the Ugandan government apparatuses like a military chain of command. You took over the businesses of others and gave it to your cronies. You had your 2-million-pound weddings and your palace near Lake Victoria. Your life was good.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]President Amin, you now have the opportunity to bring back your brutal regime. Your eccentricities have the opportunity to be reintroduced to the world stage. Can you avoid being invaded and deposed by your neighbours this time? Can you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Uganda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Overview</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Uganda is a landlocked country in East Africa. It is bordered to the east by Kenya, to the north by South Sudan, formerly just Sudan, to the west by the Democratic Republic of the Congo, to the south-west by Rwanda, and to the south by Tanzania. Uganda is in the African Great Lakes region. Uganda also lies within the Nile basin and has a varied but generally a modified equatorial climate. Uganda is named after the Buganda kingdom, which encompasses a large portion of the south of the country, including the capital Kampala. The official languages are English and Swahili, as it was colonised by the United Kingdom.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Before with the Bantu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The residents of Uganda were hunter-gatherers until 1,700–2,300 years ago. Bantu-speaking populations, who were probably from central Africa, migrated to the southern parts of the country. According to oral tradition and archaeological studies, the Empire of Kitara covered an important part of the great lakes area. Some Luo invaded the area of Bunyoro and assimilated with the Bantu society there, establishing the Babiito dynasty. Arab traders moved inland from the Indian Ocean coast of East Africa in the 1830s for trade and commerce. In the late 1860s, Bunyoro in Mid-Western Uganda found itself threatened from the north by Egyptian-sponsored agents. In the 1860s, while Arabs sought influence from the north, British explorers searching for the source of the Nile arrived in Uganda. They were followed by British Anglican missionaries who arrived in the kingdom of Buganda in 1877 and French Catholic missionaries in 1879. This situation gave rise to the death of the Uganda Martyrs in 1885.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Another Protectorate in the British Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The British government chartered the Imperial British East Africa Company to negotiate trade agreements in the region beginning in 1888. The Protectorate of Uganda was a protectorate of the British Empire from 1894 to 1962. In 1893, the Imperial British East Africa Company transferred its administration rights of territory consisting mainly of the Kingdom of Buganda to the British government. The IBEAC relinquished its control over Uganda after Ugandan internal religious wars had driven it into bankruptcy. Uganda retained a degree of self-government that would have otherwise been limited under a full colonial administration. From 1900 to 1920, a sleeping sickness epidemic in the southern part of Uganda, along the north shores of Lake Victoria, killed more than 250,000 people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Freedom and Independence</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Uganda gained independence from the UK on 9 October 1962 with Queen Elizabeth II as head of state and Queen of Uganda. In October 1963, Uganda became a republic but maintained its membership in the Commonwealth of Nations. The first post-independence election, held in 1962, was won by an alliance between the Uganda People's Congress and Kabaka Yekka. UPC and KY formed the first post-independence government with Milton Obote as executive prime minister, with the Buganda Kabaka, meaning king, Edward Muteesa II holding the largely ceremonial position of president. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_5">
			<Text>A Fractured Government</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Uganda's immediate post-independence years were dominated by the relationship between the central government and the largest regional kingdom, Buganda. From the moment the British created the Uganda protectorate, the issue of how to manage the largest monarchy within the framework of a unitary state had always been a problem. Within Buganda, there were divisions between those who wanted the Kabaka to remain a dominant monarch and those who wanted to join with the rest of Uganda to create a modern secular state. The tribal nature of Ugandan politics was also manifesting itself in government. The UPC which had previously been a national party began to break along tribal lines when Ibingira challenged Obote in the UPC. In 1966, following a power struggle between the Obote-led government and King Muteesa, Obote suspended the constitution and removed the ceremonial president and vice-president. In 1967, a new constitution proclaimed Uganda a republic and abolished the traditional kingdoms. Obote was declared the president.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Rise of Amin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_6">
			<Text>By January 1971, Milton Obote, then President of Uganda, was prepared to rid himself of the potential threat posed by Idi Amin. Various versions emerged of the way this news was leaked to Amin. In any case, Amin decided to forestall Obote and strike first. In the early morning hours of 25 January 1971, mechanized army units loyal to him attacked strategic targets in Kampala and the airport at Entebbe. Amin almost immediately initiated mass executions of Acholi and Langi troops, whom he believed to be pro-Obote. The Amin coup was warmly welcomed by most of the people of the Buganda kingdom, which Obote had attempted to dismantle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_7">
			<Text>A Terror</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_7">
			<Text>Amin's military experience, which was virtually his only experience, determined the character of his rule. He renamed Government House the Command Post, instituted an advisory defence council composed of military commanders, placed military tribunals above the system of civil law, appointed soldiers to top government posts and parastatal agencies, and even informed the newly inducted civilian cabinet ministers that they would be subject to military discipline. Uganda then became a military dictatorship which was, in effect, governed from a collection of military barracks scattered across the country, where battalion commanders, acting like local warlords, represented the coercive arm of the government. Amin's government was arguably more consumed with rivalries, regional divisions, and ethnic politics than the Uganda People's Congress that it had replaced. Amin never forgot the source of his power. He spent much of his time rewarding, promoting, and manipulating the officers and soldiers of the Ugandan army. Another near obsession for Amin was the threat of a counterattack by former president Obote.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_8">
			<Text>A Neighborly War</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_8">
			<Text>The Uganda–Tanzania War was fought between Uganda and Tanzania from October 1978 until June 1979 and led to the overthrow of Ugandan President Idi Amin. The war was preceded by a deterioration of relations between Uganda and Tanzania. The circumstances surrounding the outbreak of the war are not clear, and differing accounts of the events exist. In October 1978 Ugandan forces began making incursions into Tanzania. Later that month the Uganda Army launched an invasion, looting property and killing civilians. On 10 April a combined TPDF-UNLF force attacked Kampala and secured it the following day. Amin fled into exile while a UNLF government was established. In the following months, the TPDF occupied Uganda, facing only scattered resistance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_HEADING_9">
			<Text>After Amin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_SAS_UGANDA_TEXT_9">
			<Text>Yoweri Museveni has been president since his forces toppled the previous regime in January 1986. This was after a five-year period where Obote returned as president and military government of General Tito Okello ruled from July 1985 to January 1986 with no explicit policy except the natural goal of self-preservation. Political parties in Uganda were restricted in their activities beginning that year, in a measure ostensibly designed to reduce sectarian violence. Transparency International has rated Uganda's public sector as one of the most corrupt in the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Leader-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_AMIN">
			<Text>Idi Amin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Overview</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Idi Amin Dada Oumee was the 3rd President of Uganda, a former member of the Ugandan military and a member of the King's African Rifles. He is known as one of the most brutal despots in world history. During his years in power, Amin shifted from being a pro-Western ruler enjoying considerable support from Israel to being backed by Libya's Muammar Gaddafi, Zaire's Mobutu Sese Seko, the Soviet Union, and East Germany. When UK broke diplomatic relations with Uganda in 1977, Amin declared that he had defeated the British and added CBE to his title for Conqueror of the British Empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Much of Amin’s life is muddled, as he did not write an autobiography, and he did not authorize an official written account of his life. There are discrepancies regarding when and where he was born. Most biographical sources claim that he was born in either Koboko or Kampala around 1925. Abandoned by his father at a young age, Idi Amin grew up with his mother's family in a rural farming town in north-western Uganda. Amin joined an Islamic school in Bombo in 1941. After a few years, he left school with only a fourth-grade English-language education and did odd jobs before being recruited to the army by a British colonial army officer.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>A Cog in the King's African Rifles</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Amin joined the King's African Rifles of the British Colonial Army in 1946 as an assistant cook, while at the same time receiving military training until 1947. In later life he falsely claimed to have served in the Burma Campaign of World War II. His unit was deployed to northern Kenya to fight against Somali rebels in the Shifta War. In 1952, his brigade was deployed against the Mau Mau rebels in Kenya. In 1959, Amin was made afande class 2, the highest rank possible for a black African in the colonial British Army of that time. Amin returned to Uganda the same year and received a short-service commission as a lieutenant on 15 July 1961, becoming one of the first two Ugandans to become commissioned officers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>An Independent Army</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>In 1962, following Uganda's independence from the United Kingdom, Amin was promoted to captain and then, in 1963, to major. He was appointed Deputy Commander of the Army in 1964 and, the following year, to Commander of the Army. In 1970, he was promoted to commander of all the armed forces. Amin led an attack on the Kabaka's palace and forced Mutesa II into exile to the United Kingdom, where he remained until his death in 1969. Amin began recruiting members of Kakwa, Lugbara, South Sudanese, and other ethnic groups from the West Nile area bordering South Sudan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_5">
			<Text>A Coup</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Eventually a rift developed between Amin and President Milton Obote, exacerbated by the support Amin had built within the Uganda Army by recruiting from the West Nile region, his involvement in operations to support the rebellion in southern Sudan and an attempt on Obote's life in 1969. Having learned that Obote was planning to arrest him for misappropriating army funds, Amin seized power in a military coup on 25 January 1971, while Obote was attending a Commonwealth summit meeting in Singapore. Troops loyal to Amin sealed off Entebbe International Airport and took Kampala. Soldiers surrounded Obote's residence and blocked major roads. A broadcast on Radio Uganda accused Obote's government of corruption and preferential treatment of the Lango region. Cheering crowds were reported in the streets of Kampala after the radio broadcast. Amin declared that the military government would remain only as a caretaker regime until new elections, which would be held when the situation was normalised. He promised to release all political prisoners.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_6">
			<Text>GSUs, SRBs and PSUs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_6">
			<Text>On 2 February 1971, one week after the coup, Amin declared himself President of Uganda, Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces, Uganda Army Chief of Staff, and Chief of Air Staff. He suspended certain provisions of the Ugandan constitution, and soon instituted an Advisory Defence Council composed of military officers with himself as the chairman. Amin placed military tribunals above the system of civil law, appointed soldiers to top government post. Amin ruled by decree. Amin renamed the presidential lodge in Kampala from Government House to the Command Post. He disbanded the General Service Unit, replaced it with the State Research Bureau.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_7">
			<Text>A Brutal Regime</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_7">
			<Text>Amin retaliated against the attempted invasion by Ugandan exiles in 1972, by purging the Uganda Army of Obote supporters, predominantly those from the Acholi and Lango ethnic groups. By early 1972, some 5,000 Acholi and Lango soldiers, and at least twice as many civilians, had disappeared. The killings, motivated by ethnic, political, and financial factors, continued throughout Amin's eight years in control. The exact number of people killed is unknown. The International Commission of Jurists estimated the death toll at no fewer than 80,000 and more likely around 300,000.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Cold War Context</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_8">
			<Text>Initially, Amin was supported by Western powers such as Israel, West Germany, and, in particular, Great Britain. Amin, who had served with the King's African Rifles and taken part in Britain's suppression of the Mau Mau uprising prior to Ugandan independence, was known by the British as "intensely loyal to Britain". Following the expulsion of Ugandan Asians in 1972, most of whom were of Indian descent, India severed diplomatic relations with Uganda. The same year, as part of his "economic war", Amin broke diplomatic ties with the UK and nationalised all British-owned businesses. That year, relations with Israel soured. Although Israel had previously supplied Uganda with arms, in 1972 Amin expelled Israeli military advisers and turned to Muammar Gaddafi of Libya and the Soviet Union for support. The Soviet Union became Amin's largest arms supplier.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Perks of Being a Presidentk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_9">
			<Text>A polygamist, Idi Amin married at least six women, three of whom he divorced. As the years progressed, Amin's behaviour became more erratic, unpredictable, and strident. After the United Kingdom broke off all diplomatic relations with his regime in 1977, Amin declared that he had defeated the British, and he conferred on himself the decoration of CBE, or Conqueror of the British Empire. his full self-bestowed title ultimately became: His Excellency, President for Life, Field Marshal Al Hadji Doctor Idi Amin Dada, VC, DSO, MC, CBE, Lord of All the Beasts of the Earth and Fishes of the Seas and Conqueror of the British Empire in Africa in General and Uganda in Particular. This was in addition to his officially stated claim of being the uncrowned king of Scotland. Amin became the subject of rumours, including a widespread belief that he was a cannibal. Amin reportedly also boasted that he kept the decapitated heads of political enemies in his freezer, although he said that human flesh was generally too salty for his taste.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_HEADING_10">
			<Text>A War to Depose The Butcherer of Kampala</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TEXT_10">
			<Text>By 1978, the number of Amin's supporters and close associates had shrunk significantly, and he faced increasing dissent from the populace within Uganda as the economy and infrastructure collapsed as a result of the years of neglect and abuse. In January 1979, President of Tanzinia Nyerere mobilised the Tanzania People's Defence Force and counterattacked, joined by several groups of Ugandan exiles who had united as the Uganda National Liberation Army. Amin's army retreated steadily. After a short-lived attempt to rally some remnants of the Uganda Army in eastern Uganda which reportedly included Amin proclaiming the city of Jinja his country's new capital, he fled into exile. Amin first escaped to Libya, where he stayed until 1980, and ultimately settled in Saudi Arabia, where the Saudi royal family allowed him sanctuary and paid him a generous subsidy in return for staying out of politics. Following years of exile in multiple African and Middle Eastern countries and a reported fruitarian diet, Amin died on 16 August 2003.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_LIVED">
			<Text>1925 - 2003 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_NAME">
			<Text>Idi Amin Dada Oumee</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Uganda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_AMIN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>His Excellency, President for Life, Field Marshal Al Hadji Doctor Idi Amin Dada, VC, DSO, MC, CBE, Lord of All the Beasts of the Earth and Fishes of the Seas and Conqueror of the British Empire in Africa in General and Uganda in Particular</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Trait-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SAS_AMIN_SHORT">
			<Text>Lord Of All Beasts</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_SAS_AMIN">
			<Text>Friendship increases Unit [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production speed by 10% for both players, to a maximum of +50% for Uganda. Declaring War hurries [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production in the Capital, or in all cities when against a declared Friend.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Kwanami-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_RSR">
			<Text>Revolutionary Suicide Regiment</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_RSR_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Marine for Idi Amin's Uganda that is cheaper but weaker than the unit it replaces. However, it receives a +10% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Bonus per player who denounces Uganda (to a maximum of +50%), and if garrisoned in a city when purging [ICON_CITIZEN] Population with the State Research Bureau, gains XP.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_RSR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Marine for Idi Amin's Uganda that is cheaper but weaker than the unit it replaces. However, it receives a +10% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Bonus per player who denounces Uganda (to a maximum of +50%), and if garrisoned in a city when purging [ICON_CITIZEN] Population with the State Research Bureau, gains XP.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_RSR_TEXT">
			<Text>The Revolutionary Suicide Regiment was an elite formation of the Ugandan Army. Based in Masaka, the unit was formally known as the Masaka Mechanized Specialist Reconnaissance Regiment. It functioned as one of the spearheads of the Ugandan army and was one of the several mechanized reconnaissance regiment in the Ugandan Army. In the Uganda-Tanzania War of 1978, the Revolutionary Suicide Regiment was used to invade Tanzania. Attached was also a jazz band, through which Idi Amin met his fifth and last surviving wife, Sarah Kyolaba.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_PROMO">
			<Text>Honor Among Butchers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_PROMO_HELP">
			<Text>Gains +10% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength per Civilization denouncing Uganda. If garrisoned in a city while purging [ICON_CITIZEN] Population with the State Research Bureau there, gains XP.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_1">
			<Text>International Fury I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_1_HELP">
			<Text>+10% [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength from Denunciations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_2">
			<Text>International Fury II</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_2_HELP">
			<Text>+20% [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength from Denunciations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_3">
			<Text>International Fury III</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_3_HELP">
			<Text>+30% [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength from Denunciations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_4">
			<Text>International Fury IV</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_4_HELP">
			<Text>+40% [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength from Denunciations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_5">
			<Text>International Fury V</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_RSR_5_HELP">
			<Text>+50% [ICON_STRENGTH] Strength from Denunciations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Kutinyam-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_SRB">
			<Text>State Research Bureau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_SRB_PEDIA">
			<Text>The State Research Bureau, initially known as the State Research Centre was a Ugandan intelligence agency, active from 1971 to 1979. It served as a secret police organisation for President Idi Amin's regime. Its responsibilities were to gather military intelligence and conduct counterintelligence. The headquarters was located in a building on Nakasero hill in Kampala, next to the State Lodge Annex. Male SRB agents commonly wore dark sunglasses, Kaunda suits, floral-print shirts, and bell-bottoms. The SRB recruited a substantial number of Rwandan immigrants, both men and women. The SRB came to be known as the State Research Butchery, as the SRB tortured and executed many suspected dissidents.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_SRB_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Police Station for Uganda that does not require a Constabulary. The State Research Bureau unlocks the ability to Purge 1 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen in its city in exchange for a lump sum of [ICON_GOLD] Gold, and to kill a hostile unit in Ugandan territory. If no hostile units are present in Ugandan territory, it will instead grant additional [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAS_SRB_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Police Station for Uganda that does not require a Constabulary. The State Research Bureau unlocks the ability to Purge 1 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen in its city in exchange for a lump sum of [ICON_GOLD] Gold, and to kill a hostile unit in Ugandan territory. If no hostile units are present in Ugandan territory, it will instead grant additional [ICON_GOLD] Gold. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_9">
			<Text>Captain Alex</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_8">
			<Text>Malyamu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_7">
			<Text>Kyolaba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_6">
			<Text>Mustafa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_5">
			<Text>Juma</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_4">
			<Text>Amin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_3">
			<Text>Faruk</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_2">
			<Text>Salim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_1">
			<Text>Bad Black</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_UGANDA_0">
			<Text>Bruce U</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_1">
			<Text>Kampala</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_2">
			<Text>Entebbe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_3">
			<Text>Mbarara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_4">
			<Text>Masaka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_5">
			<Text>Gulu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_6">
			<Text>Hoima</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_7">
			<Text>Lira</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_8">
			<Text>Jinja</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_9">
			<Text>Mbale</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_10">
			<Text>Mpigi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_11">
			<Text>Lukaya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_12">
			<Text>Kitgum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_13">
			<Text>Lugazi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_14">
			<Text>Nansana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_15">
			<Text>Kira</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_16">
			<Text>Ssabagabo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_17">
			<Text>Mukono</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_18">
			<Text>Njeru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_19">
			<Text>Kasese</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_20">
			<Text>Kabarole</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_21">
			<Text>Kabale</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_22">
			<Text>Tororo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_23">
			<Text>Soroti</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_24">
			<Text>Mityana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_25">
			<Text>Mubende</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_26">
			<Text>Masindi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_27">
			<Text>Moroto</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_28">
			<Text>Bushenyi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_29">
			<Text>Sembabule</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_30">
			<Text>Bombo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_31">
			<Text>Nakasongola</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_32">
			<Text>Kalapata</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_33">
			<Text>Kyebando</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_34">
			<Text>Pakwach</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_35">
			<Text>Karuma Falls</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_UGANDA_36">
			<Text>Wakaliga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SAS_SRB">
			<Text>Purge Population</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SAS_SRB_TT">
			<Text>Purge 1 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen from this city. Doing so yields {1_Num} [ICON_GOLD] Gold and kills one enemy unit within Ugandan borders.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SAS_SRB_DISABLED_TT">
			<Text>Purge 1 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen from this city. Doing so yields {1_Num} [ICON_GOLD] Gold and kills one enemy unit within Ugandan borders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]City must have at least 2 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizens.[ENDCOLOR]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SAS_SRB_CONFIRM">
			<Text>Are you sure you want to purge {1_Desc} of 1 [ICON_CITIZEN] Citizen?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: VANILLA -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_SAS_UGANDA_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now claiming Scottish heritage and feeding their enemies to crocodiles. I worry the rest of the world will soon succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_AMIN_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I do not intend to let any foreigner impose his will on my nation. I, myself, consider myself the most powerful figure in the world, and I will not let you control me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_AMIN_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome to glorious Uganda, foreigner! It is only by the grace of His Excellency, President for Life, Field Marshal Al Hadji Doctor Idi Amin Dada, VC, DSO, MC, Lord of All the Beasts of the Earth and Fishes of the Seas and Conqueror of the British Empire in Africa in General and Uganda in Particular that you may visit us. That's me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_AMIN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I am the hero of Africa! You cannot defeat me! I am a great man and a great conqueror, and I will not be forgotten! </Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>