<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--MOD-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>BRAZIL (PEDRO I)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE TRAIT: INDEPENDENCE, OR DEATH[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great General Points based upon [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Excess Happiness whenever a war breaks out. Enemy units beginning their turn adjacent to a Great General begin with only half their normal [ICON_MOVES] Movement.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: CANHONEIRA (IRONCLAD)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The unique Ironclad replacement for Brazil, the Canhoneira fights best when bombarding Land Units and Cities, but less effectively when attacking other Naval Units. Unlike the Ironclad, the Canhoneira is a Ranged Unit, meaning it is able to attack at a distance. Deploy Canhoneira carefully to take advantage of their siege capabilities, but keep them out of open conflict with enemy navies.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: INDEPENDENCE DRAGOON (CAVALRY)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Independence Dragoon is the unique Cavalry replacement for Brazil. This unit fights 15% more effectively when stacked with a Great General. In addition, an Independence Dragoon is spawned alongside any Great General that you earn. Keeping your Independence Dragoons with your Great Generals will make them a formidable force to contend with.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--BRAZIL-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Brazilian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DESC">
			<Text>Brazilian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Brazil</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Cities-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_01">
			<Text>Rio de Janeiro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_02">
			<Text>São Salvador</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_03">
			<Text>Recife</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_04">
			<Text>Olinda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_05">
			<Text>Nictheroy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_06">
			<Text>Fortaleza</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_07">
			<Text>Belém</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_08">
			<Text>Vila Rica</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_09">
			<Text>Montevideo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_10">
			<Text>Campos dos Goytacazes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_11">
			<Text>Queluz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_12">
			<Text>São Luiz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_13">
			<Text>Minas do Rio das Contas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_14">
			<Text>Sabará</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_15">
			<Text>Minas Novas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_16">
			<Text>Caruaru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_17">
			<Text>Ytu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_18">
			<Text>Sorocaba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_19">
			<Text>Campinas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_20">
			<Text>São Paulo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_21">
			<Text>Grão Mogol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_22">
			<Text>Feira de Sant’Anna</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_23">
			<Text>Taubaté</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_24">
			<Text>Goyaz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_25">
			<Text>Parahyba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_26">
			<Text>Mariana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_27">
			<Text>São João d'El-Rei</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_28">
			<Text>Santo Amaro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_29">
			<Text>Cuyabá</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_30">
			<Text>São Vicente</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_31">
			<Text>Santa Bárbara</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_32">
			<Text>Colônia do Sacramento</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_33">
			<Text>Oeiras</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_34">
			<Text>Porto Alegre</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_35">
			<Text>Ponte Nova</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_36">
			<Text>Paraty</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_37">
			<Text>Desterro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_38">
			<Text>Maceió</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_39">
			<Text>Santos</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_40">
			<Text>Barra do Rio Negro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_41">
			<Text>Natal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_42">
			<Text>São Francisco</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_43">
			<Text>Sobral</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_44">
			<Text>Rio Pardo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_45">
			<Text>São Fidélis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_46">
			<Text>Sabará</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_47">
			<Text>Pindamonhangaba</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_0">
			<Text>Luis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_1">
			<Text>Afonso</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_2">
			<Text>Joao</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_3">
			<Text>Filipe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_4">
			<Text>Jose</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_5">
			<Text>Sebastiao</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_6">
			<Text>Henrique</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_7">
			<Text>Maria</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_8">
			<Text>Paula</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_9">
			<Text>Francisca</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_10">
			<Text>Teodósio</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_11">
			<Text>Carlos</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--PEDRO I-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I">
			<Text>Pedro I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Pedro was born on Oct. 12, 1798, at the Queluz Palace in Lisbon, the son of the prince regent of Portugal (later João VI) and his wife, Carlota Joaquina, the daughter of the Spanish Bourbon king Charles IV. In 1807 the royal family fled to Brazil to escape Napoleon's invading armies. Pedro adapted well to the Brazilian milieu. He was an excellent horseman, enjoyed the military life, and could compete with common soldiers and officers equally. Also, he early demonstrated musical talents and later composed some music of creditable amateur quality. He was considered to be handsome, and women found him attractive.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1817 Pedro married Carolina Josefa Leopoldina, the daughter of Francis I of Austria. Her intelligence, consideration, and personality quickly earned her the respect and admiration of the Portuguese and Brazilians, as well as of her husband, but she was unable to distract him from his amorous affairs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1816 Pedro's father became João VI, King of Portugal and Brazil, which had been elevated from the status of a colony to a kingdom in 1815. In 1821 João VI was forced to return to Portugal and leave Pedro as the prince regent. Recognizing the independence sentiments in Brazil, and observing what was occurring in the Spanish colonies of the New world, the King advised his son to declare Brazil independent and take the throne for himself rather than allow an adventurer to take over the country. On Sept. 7, 1822, supported by Brazilians who feared that the Portuguese would reduce the country to colonial status again, and following the advice of his wife and his chief counselor, José Bonifácio de Andrada e Silva, Pedro declared the independence of Brazil and established the Empire of Brazil with himself as emperor.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1823 Pedro I called a constituent assembly to formulate a constitution but dissolved the body later that year. He promulgated a constitution on March 24, 1824, which remained Brazil's charter until 1889. The period was disturbed by dissension between native-born Brazilians and those born in Portugal. Pedro I was Portuguese and thus suspect to Brazilians, especially after he signed a treaty of peace with Portugal which left unresolved some basic issues concerning future relations between the two countries. When João VI died in 1826, Pedro I inherited the Portuguese crown, but the ruling of both countries by the Emperor was unacceptable to the Brazilians. Pedro I abdicated the Portuguese throne in favor of his daughter Maria da Glória, who was betrothed to her uncle Miguel.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Although he accepted constitutional monarchy, Pedro I was an absolutist in his approach to government. With difficulty he accepted advice from the legislative branch of the government, and his attitudes led to conflict with liberal Brazilians.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Pedro's long-standing affair with Domitilia de Castro, upon whom he bestowed the title of Marquêsa de Santos, was a cause of much criticism and provoked opposition. The Empress, Leopoldina, had widespread public support when the Emperor moved his mistress into the palace. Leopoldina died in 1827, and Pedro I continued his relationship with the Marquêsa de Santos until 1829, when he married Amélia Augusta Eugénia Napoleona, daughter of Eugene of Litchenberg.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In April 1831 Pedro I unexpectedly abdicated in favor of his 5-year-old son, who became Pedro II. Returning to Portugal, Pedro took up the cause of his daughter Maria da Glória, whose position as Maria II of Portugal was being challenged by her uncle Miguel. Dom Pedro directed the political and military campaign which defeated his brother and, acting as regent, had his daughter declared of age, although she was less than 18 years old. A few days later, on Sept. 24, 1834, he died in the Queluz Palace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_NAME">
			<Text>Pedro I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Brazil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Emperor of Brazil</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_LIVED">
			<Text>1798 - 1834</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_TEXT">
			<Text>Pedro I, Emperor of Brazil, the fight for independence has begun. Young were you when the Liberal Revolution compelled your father to return to Portugal, leaving you as Brazil's regent. But though plagued by military rebellion and dissent, you quickly won the favour of the Brazilian people; declaring their freedom from Portugal in 1822 and rising to the title of Emperor. Guided by your firm and wise hand, Brazil's dissenters could do little to oppose you, and the dawn of a glorious and fondly remembered empire would begin.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Great Emperor Pedro, the choice to side with Brazil has been made. Now, the time has come to ensure her independence. Can you lead your people into battle and repel your foes? Can you earn the respect and love of your nation and become worthy of the title of Emperor? Can you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Responses-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Dom Pedro I. I fight at the backs of Brazil's finest soldiers. Have you come to me as an ally, or as an enemy?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I shall abdicate without protest, asking only that you keep the freedom of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>I will fight for the independence of my people to the death.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>For all that is good, I must ask you this favour. Would you agree to a public Declaration of Friendship with me?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You have threatened the liberty of my nation for long enough.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>You have betrayed my trust and your own honour.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>I will fight on as I must to keep my people free, even if I must be the one to drawn first blood.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Then we have little more to say until we are at the peace table.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--INDEPENDENCE, OR DEATH-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_SHORT">
			<Text>Independence, or Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I">
			<Text>Receive [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great General Points based upon [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Excess Happiness whenever a war breaks out. Enemy units beginning their turn adjacent to a Great General begin with only half their normal [ICON_MOVES] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_BRAZIL_PEDRO_I_MESSAGE">
			<Text>[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]+{1_Num}[ENDCOLOR] [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great General Points from Declaration of War!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--CANHONEIRA-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_CANHONEIRA">
			<Text>Canhoneira</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_CANHONEIRA_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Ironclad replacement that fights best against Land Units and Cities, but poorly against other Naval Units. Possesses a Ranged Attack.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_CANHONEIRA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The unique Ironclad replacement for Brazil, the Canhoneira fights best when bombarding Land Units and Cities, but less effectively when attacking other Naval Units. Unlike the Ironclad, the Canhoneira is a Ranged Unit, meaning it is able to attack at a distance. Deploy Canhoneira carefully to take advantage of their siege capabilities, but keep them out of open conflict with enemy navies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_CANHONEIRA_TEXT">
			<Text>The Brazilian ironclad Rio de Janeiro was an armored gunboat built for the Brazilian Navy during the Paraguayan War in the mid-1860s. Like the other two gunboats she was built in Brazil and was designed as a casemate ironclad. Commissioned in April 1866, the ship did not enter combat until September, when she bombarded Paraguayan fortifications at Curuzu. Rio de Janeiro hit two mines on 2 September and rapidly sank, taking 53 of her crew with her. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Armoured Hull-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_CANHONEIRA">
			<Text>Battle of Curuzu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_CANHONEIRA_HELP">
			<Text>+25% Combat versus cities and Land Units. -25% Combat versus Naval Units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--INDEPENDENCE DRAGOON-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON">
			<Text>Independence Dragoon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON_HELP">
			<Text>Industrial Era Mounted Unit that fights best when stacked with a Great General. A free Independence Dragoon and [ICON_RES_HORSE] Horse resource is spawned with each Great General. Only Brazil can train it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Independence Dragoon is the unique Cavalry replacement for Brazil. This unit fights 15% more effectively when stacked with a Great General. In addition, an Independence Dragoon is spawned alongside any Great General that you earn. Keeping your Independence Dragoons with your Great Generals will make them a formidable force to contend with.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON_TEXT">
			<Text>After Portugal's Crown Prince Pedro had proclaimed the independence of Brazil from Portugal, on September 7, 1822, some troops remained loyal to Portugal. To guarantee national independence, these troops had to be defeated. To fight the troops in Bahia, Pedro established in 1823 the Emperor’s Battalion. In 1825, the Emperor's Battalion was sent to Montevideo to fight at Cisplatine War. After Pedro's abdication, the Emperor's Battalion was disbanded, as all other troops directly subordinated to them. On April 7, 1933, President Getúlio Vargas established the Guards Battalion to protect the government's palaces. The decree determined that this battalion was the heir to Emperor’s Battalion and its traditions and would use its uniforms - blue polo and white pants with a shako, boots and a brown belt - at special ceremonies and celebrations. On April 6, 1960, with the transfer of the national capital from Rio de Janeiro to Brasília, the unit changed its name to today's Presidential Guard Battalion. The most important officer of the Presidential Guard Battalion was the 2nd Lieutenant Luís Alves de Lima e Silva, the Duke of Caxias and the Patron of the Army. Thus, its nickname is Battalion of the Duke of Caxias in his honor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Emperor's Battalion-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON">
			<Text>Emperor's Battalion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON_HELP">
			<Text>15% combat bonus with Great General in same tile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Independence Dragoon-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON_GREAT_GENERAL">
			<Text>Independence Dragoon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_INDEPENDENCE_DRAGOON_GREAT_GENERAL_HELP">
			<Text>This unit spawned with an Independence Dragoon.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>