<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--KAYAPO-->
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO">
			<Text>Kayapó</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Kayapó</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_ADJ">
			<Text>Kayapó</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Kayapó people are the indigenous people in Brazil who inhabit a vast area spreading across the states of Pará and Mato Grosso, south of the Amazon River and along Xingu River and its tributaries. This pattern has given rise to the nickname the Xingu tribe. They are one of the various subgroups of the great Mebêngôkre nation (people from the water’s source). The term "Kayapó" is used by neighbouring groups rather than the Kayapó themselves. They refer to outsiders as "Poanjos".</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Location and Homeland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				When the Portuguese conquerors first arrived in Brazil, there were about 5 million Amerindians, but today there are only about 200,000, of which a few thousand are Kayapós, living along the Xingu River in the eastern part of the Amazon rain-forest, in several scattered villages. Their lands consist of tropical rain forest and savanna. The Amazon basin, which includes the Amazon River and its tributaries, such as the Xingu, is sometimes referred to as Amazonia and includes parts of Venezuela, Colombia, Ecuador, and Peru. In Brazil it covers about 7.8 million sq km (3 million sq mi).
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_HEADING_3">
			<Text>First Contacts</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_TEXT_3">
			<Text>
				Their first steady contact with Europeans did not occur until the 20th century, in the 1950s. Since then, because of contact with squatters, loggers, miners, and eventually Brazilian government officials, the Kayapós evolved some new customs and have had to struggle to maintain their way of life. Logging and mining, particularly for gold, as well as some agricultural activities and cattle-ranching in cleared-out sections of the jungle have posed threats to the Kayapós' traditional way of life. Increasing destruction of the rain forest, as well as river pollution caused by chemicals used in gold-mining activities, threatens the delicate balance between humans, plants, and animals successfully maintained for thousands of years by Amazon Indians, such as the Kayapós.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Land Control and Environmental Issues</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TEXT_KEY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_TEXT_4">
			<Text>
				The Kayapó have incorporated a great deal of traditional myth, ritual and cosmology into their practices honouring the importance of the earth's relationship with the people. Threats to the forest home of the Kayapó have been an area of extreme concern in the last 30 years, beginning with mining and logging enterprises which threatened to destroy the rainforest, and thus the Kayapós' way of life. In the village of Gorotire, the Kayapó made a deal with prospectors that mining could take place as long as they received a percentage of the mining proceeds and had their territory demarcated. The gold mining operation was initially seen as a positive development, which brought money into the local economy. With money filtering into the economy, better housing, improved education and a resulting level of health were achieved. However, the initial benefits of mining also resulted in high levels of pollution in the area which seeped into water ways and nearby river banks and decimated local fish populations with high quantities of mercury. In addition to striking environmental threats, social habits began to change with the introduction of outside influences in the area. Men began to spend more time in town drinking, and engaging in "conspicuous consumption and womanising." This increased interaction with outside groups elevated the levels of disease, which posed an imminent threat to the people because of their relative seclusion and limited access to medical care. In addition, the diminishing resource base caused conflicts between the Kayapó and neighbouring villages which often resulted in explosive and long standing disputes. The Kayapó people used forceful tactics to banish loggers and miners in some areas, as well as to establish themselves as an economic force. Developers ranging from gold miners to soy farmers and cattle ranchers were often killed. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1987, new land issues arose when the government proposed a series of hydroelectric dams to be built in the Xingu River area, namely the Belo Monte Dam. These dams were an imminent threat to the Kayapó with the potential to displace upwards of 20,000 people from their lands. Under the leadership of Paulinho Paiakan, the Altamira Gathering was orchestrated by the Kayapó, drawing media attention worldwide. This demonstration, staged at the planned site for the first dam in Altamira, Pará, lasted several days and brought much pressure upon both the World Bank and the Brazilian government. The Altamira gathering brought the Kayapó, as well as other Brazilian Indians and their supporters into a forum where discussion could be had about how to protect the environment and the native peoples. The Kayapó demanded information that was being withheld by the government relating to the negative consequences for their people who would be directly affected by the construction of the dam, as well as rural Brazilians in the Xingu River area, who they felt were not receiving adequate and fair information. The Kayapó continued to fight adversity and retaliated using traditional war oratory and dances, proving that they were not only capable of "effectively reintegrating their society, (but) also of adapting their organization and culture to manipulate the mass media that covered the demonstration". The Kayapó attended the meeting to protest the hydroelectric dam development whilst in traditional costume and wielding machetes. Perhaps "the most dramatic single image to emerge from this tumultuous gathering was that of Tuíra, a female indigenous leader, angrily waving a machete in the face of engineer José Antônio Muniz Lópes (later president of Eletronorte, the state power company in charge of the dam), which had worldwide repercussions and probably influenced further postponement of the project".[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]An important media element of the presentations was the appearance of the rock star Sting during the demonstration. Sting continued to support the Kayapó in their efforts to protect their land, and in 1989 he founded the Rainforest Foundation Fund. Three years later, the first privately funded demarcation of the Brazilian indigenous reserve was made possible by the RFF. In 2008, they were again threatened by secretive government plans to build a series of hydroelectric dams on their land. The Belo Monte Dam resurfaced, and would be built on the Xingu River, the homeland to many Kayapó people. The Construction plans continue to be fought by the Kayapó people. Government corruption continues to weaken the resistance efforts of the indigenous and opposition forces within the government. Kayapó leaders protesting the creation of the dam are constantly threatened, and some have been killed by developers and land prospectors. Because of the nature of the circumstances, these crimes are rarely punished.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The forest is the home of the Kayapó and they rely on its bounty for their food and medicinal needs. Rivers are essential to their way of life and gold mining in Brazil is polluting the rivers, while the proposed Belo Monte Dam project would use up vast amounts of resources essential to the survival and livelihood of the Kayapó and would severely impact fishing conditions. Between 18,000-25,000 (indirectly associated) jobs will be created by the construction of the dam. These numbers will have a vast and far reaching implication on population growth in the area which has the very real potential to put even more pressure on the fragile forest infrastructure and ever decreasing natural resource base, escalating concerns of flooding and deforestation in particular.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--RAONI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI">
			<Text>Raoni</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Overview</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>
				Raoni Metuktire, also known as Chief Raoni or Ropni, is an Indigenous Brazilian leader and environmentalist. He is a chief of the Kayapo people, a Brazilian Indigenous group from the plain lands of the Mato Grosso and Pará in Brazil, south of the Amazon River and along Xingu River and its tributaries. He is internationally famous as a living symbol of the fight for the preservation of the Amazon rainforest and indigenous culture.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Campaigns</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Raoni Metuktire was born in the State of Mato Grosso in 1932, in the heart of the Brazilian part of the Amazon rainforest, in a village called Krajmopyjakare. Born in the Metuktire family of Kayapo people, he is one of Cacique Umoro's sons. As the Kayapo tribe is nomadic, his childhood was marked by continuous travel, during which he witnessed many tribal wars. Guided by his brother Motibau, at the age of 15 he chose to have a painted wooden lip plate called botoque placed under his lower lip.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Raoni and other members of the Metuktire tribe encountered the Western World for the first time in 1954. Initiated into the Portuguese language by Orlando Villas-Bôas, the eldest of the Villas-Bôas brothers and a famous indigenous anthropologist in Brazil, the young Raoni was ready for the Kuben’s invasion (Kuben meaning « the others », « white people »).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1964, he met King Leopold III of Belgium while the latter was on an expedition into indigenous reservations in Mato Grosso.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Deforestation was already a cause for concern when “Raoni”, a documentary film by Jean-Pierre Dutilleux and narrated by Jacques Perrin was shot. Marlon Brando, known for his support of Native American people, had just been paid an unprecedented $3.7 million for his 10-minute part in Superman, but agreed to appear for no salary in "Raoni's" opening sequence.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Brazilian media's sudden interest made Raoni the banner-bearer of the fight for the preservation of the Amazon rainforest, which had been jeopardized by illegal deforestation, the increasing cultivation of soya beans, and the use of hydroelectric dams for the generation of electricity.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Raoni gained international attention thanks to musician Sting, who came to meet him in the Xingu in November 1987. On October 12, 1988, Sting participated with Raoni in a press conference prior to the Sao Paulo show of the ‘Human Rights Now!’ Amnesty International tour. After this event, Sting, his wife Trudie Styler, and Jean-Pierre Dutilleux founded the Rainforest Foundation. Its initial purpose was to support Raoni's projects, the first being the demarcation of Kayapos territory threatened by invasion.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In February 1989, Raoni became one of the fiercest opponents to the Belo Monte Dam project. Television broadcasts transmitted his opinions in Altamira during a large assembly of chiefs.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Raoni visited 17 countries with Sting from April to June 1989. The very successful campaign gave him the opportunity to raise awareness around the world about the deforestation. Twelve rainforest foundations were created to raise funds for the establishment of a huge national park in the Rio Xingu River region, in Para and Mato Grosso Brazilian states. Raoni's dream was to unite the five demarcated indigenous territories (Baú, Kaiapó, Panará, Kapôt Jarina, Bàdjumkôre) with then undemarcated Mekragnotire lands. Along with the adjoining Xingu National Park, the united indigenous lands would cover approximately 180000 km2 (nearly one-third the area of France).[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1993, funds raised worldwide helped to make Raoni's dream a reality. The Xingu indigenous lands were reunited, creating one of the world's most important rainforest reserves.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>International Ambassador</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Another uncle who influenced him in his youth was Domingo de Oro, a notable figure in the young Argentine Republic who was influential in bringing Juan Manuel de Rosas to power. Though Raoni did not follow de Oro's political and religious leanings, he learned the value of intellectual integrity and honesty. He developed scholarly and oratorical skills, qualities which de Oro was famous for. After completing primary school, his mother wanted him to go to Córdoba to become a priest. He had spent a year reading the Bible and often spent time as a child helping his uncle with church services, but Raoni soon became bored with religion and school, and got involved with a group of aggressive children.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Opposition to the Belo Monte Dam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_TEXT_4">
			<Text>In an interview on French TV channel TF1, during Raoni's 2010 European campaign to France, Belgium, Switzerland, Monaco and Luxembourg, he declared war on the Belo Monte Dam project, which jeopardized indigenous territories on the bank of the Xingú river in the state of Pará (Brazil). He also reaffirmed his determination to protect the Amazon rainforest from a major disaster.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the tour, he visited France where he promoted his memoirs “Raoni, mémoires d'un chef indien”. He was welcomed by former French president Jacques Chirac, and endorsed Fondation Chirac, whose purpose was to preserve the cultures of indigenous people and the rainforest's biodiversity, including the creation of an institute in the middle of the Brazilian Amazon rainforest.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the tour, he was also welcomed by Albert II, Prince of Monaco, known as an advocate for the protection of nature. The former French president Nicolas Sarkozy declined to welcome Raoni during the tour, even though he invited Raoni to France in September 2009 during an official visit to Brazil.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Brazilian Institute of Environment and Renewable Natural Resources (IBAMA), last defence against the construction of the Belo Monte dam, delivered the licence to the consortium of Brazilian companies Norte Energia on June 1, 2011. This information has been forwarded by the media and social networks all over the world with a picture of Raoni crying. The caption added that his tears were provoked by the announcement of the final validation of the project. Indignant, Chief Raoni denied on his official website: ‘I didn’t cry because of the authorization of the construction of the Belo Monte dam and the beginning of the construction (…). President Dilma will cry but I will not. I want to know who gave this picture and spread this false information (…). President Dilma will have to kill me in front of the Planalto Palace (Palácio do Planalto). Then you will be able to build the Belo Monte dam. » According to Amazon Watch his crying had nothing to do with the dam or any news related to it; it is a custom among the Kayapo to cry when they greet an old acquaintance or relative that they have not seen for a long time, as was happening when this photo was taken.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In September 2011, Chief Raoni went to the United Nations Human Right Council in Geneva and participated to Rio+20 in June 2012. Raoni is not disheartened. He recently received the support of famous people such as James Cameron, Sigourney Weaver, Arnold Schwarzenegger, Vincent Cassel, Marion Cotillard, Edgar Morin, Jan Kounen, Nicolas Hulot, Danielle Mitterrand, Mino Cinelu and launched an international petition in 7 languages against the proposed Belo Monte dam project on his official website.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, the President Dilma Rousseff did not hear Chief Raoni appeal and made her decision with little apparent regard for dealing comprehensively with its anticipated severe economic, ecological and social impacts, and with minimal consultation of the indigenous populations. In fact, the building of the dam was later suggested as a part of a huge corruption scheme in the President Rousseff government and Chief Raoni considered the biggest symbol of opposition to the Belo Monte dam.</Text></Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_NAME">
			<Text>Raoni Metuktire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Cacique</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Cacique</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_GPUZ_RAONI_LIVED">
			<Text>1932 AD - Today</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_GPUZ_RAONI_TEXT">
			<Text>Oh, wise Cacique Raoni, the people turn to you in the land's hour of need. Born before the contact of the Kayapó with the white man, you have been one of the most activate and overall important activists for the natives of the Amazon ever since, with opuses such as the foundation of the National Park of the Xingu. It is your tireless work that's brought so much attention to the devastation ongoing in your homeland, and the measures put in place to stop it directly go back to you.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh, wise Cacique, the land is once again wounded by the actions of those too greedy to commune with it, and it calls back to you to protect it. Can you set off and defend the sanctuaries of life? Will you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--RAONI CITY LIST-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_01">
			<Text>Kremoro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_02">
			<Text>Gorotire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_03">
			<Text>Baú</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_04">
			<Text>Mekrãgnoti</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_05">
			<Text>Kuben-Kran-Krên</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_06">
			<Text>Kôkraimôrô</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_07">
			<Text>Metyktire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_08">
			<Text>Kararaô</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_09">
			<Text>Kenjam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_10">
			<Text>Kikretum</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_11">
			<Text>Las Casas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_12">
			<Text>Pykany</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_13">
			<Text>A'Ukre</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_14">
			<Text>Môikàràkô</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_15">
			<Text>Piaraçu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_16">
			<Text>Cateté</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_17">
			<Text>Djudjê-Kô</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_18">
			<Text>Bacajá</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_19">
			<Text>Mebêngôkre</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_GPUZ_RAONI_KAYAPO_20">
			<Text>Xikrin</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--NEKREX-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GPUZ_RAONI_SHORT">
			<Text>Nekrex</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_GPUZ_RAONI">
			<Text>[ICON_INTERNATIONAL_TRADE] Trade Routes to other Civilizations provide their origin city with the same [ICON_GREAT_PERSON] Great Person points of the destination city. Marshes and Jungle tiles yield +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture, increasing to +3 with Ecology.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--UNCUA-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GPUZ_UNCUA">
			<Text>Uncuã</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GPUZ_UNCUA_HELP">
			<Text>Unlike the Granary it replaces, the Uncuã does not grant its normal bonuses, instead increasing the [ICON_FOOD] Food in riverine, lake, jungle and marsh tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GPUZ_UNCUA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Uncuã is a slightly less restrictive version of the Granary it replaces, and encourages you to not deforestate or remove marshlands!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GPUZ_UNCUA_TEXT">
			<Text>Tortoises make a large part of the traditional Kayapó diet. They are routinely hunted for their meat, stacked on top of one another, and hauled tied to two large logs, with the entire contraption weighing up to 60 kilos and or 3 meters long. They are eaten during special feasts, during which up to 300 tortoises may be eaten, and it may last as long as a month.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--BENADIORO-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GPUZ_BENADIORO">
			<Text>Benadioró</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GPUZ_BENADIORO_HELP">
			<Text>The Benadioró, unlike the Great Meerchant it Replaces, allows you to connect luxuries and strategic resources without burning up forests, jungles and marshes, provides combat bonuses to nearby land units, is generated from combat and the clearing of nearby tiles, and is also expendable to increase influence or perform a concert tour.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GPUZ_BENADIORO_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Benadioró is an effective all-rounder, allowing you to connect luxuries and strategic resources without burning up forests, jungles and marshes, as well as providing combat bonuses to nearby units, and being generated from combat and the clearing of nearby tiles, being expendable to increase influence or perform a concert tour. As a whole, they grant you a ton of flexibility.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_GPUZ_BENADIORO_TEXT">
			<Text>Benadióros are the Kayapó chiefs. They coordinate hunts and work alongside thir own small groups, called oopen, which all work in a workshop calld a ngobe, which is male-only. They also extensively practice bekeeping.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Diplomacy Responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Cacique Raoni Metuktire, speaking on behalf of the Kayapó people who inhabit this land. We are willing to be friends, if are willing to listen to us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You destroy our lands, poison the planet and sow death, for you are lost. Soon, it will be too late to change, and you too shall feel the same fear we have.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>The big winds are here. Soon you feel the fear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_ATTACKED_HOSTILE">
			<Text>We call on you to stop what you are doing, to stop the destruction, to stop your attack on the spirits of the Earth. You must, for the good of all.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>We believe you share the willingness to participate in the beauty of the forest and of our culture. Join us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>When you pour poisons on the land and into the rivers, you impale the heart of the Earth. When poison pours from your mouth, you impale common decency.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>You have to change the way you live because you are lost, you have lost your way. Where you are going is only the way of destruction and of death.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>What you are doing will change the whole world and will destroy our home. And it will destroy your home too.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now looking to insects for social skills and wearing Macaw feather headdresses. I worry the rest of the world will succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_GPUZ_RAONI_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>I see that your people are now looking to insects for social skills and wearing Macaw feather headdresses. I welcome this change!</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--SPIES-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_0">
			<Text>Gorotire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_1">
			<Text>Kuben-Krân-Krên</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_2">
			<Text>Kumrenhtx</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_3">
			<Text>Irã'ãmranh-re</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_4">
			<Text>Kôkraimôrô</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_5">
			<Text>Kararaô</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_6">
			<Text>Mekrãgnoti</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_7">
			<Text>Metyktire </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_8">
			<Text>Xikrin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_GPUZ_KAYAPO_9">
			<Text>Porekry</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>