<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
	<!-- Civilization -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TITLE">
			<Text>Turkmenistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_DESC">
			<Text>Turkmenistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Turkmenistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Turkmen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT">
			<Text>Let the weak grovel at your feet, Turkmenbashy Saparmurat Niyazov, inaugural President of Turkmenistan. Upon the independence of your great nation, you published the brilliant Ruhnama, a modern epic of the Turkmen people. You also de-Russified the nation, introducing a new Latin-based Turkmen alphabet to replace Russian Cyrillic. Replacing Marx and Lenin, you even had the wisdom to change the names of the calendar months! Cultural imperfectness was eliminated when you banned lip syncing, dogs from the capital, opera, ballet, circuses, and make-up on news television. Yet more strong reforms. Under your rule, Turkmenistan’s economy was grown by the forward-thinking central planning, which saw a move toward energy independence and the export of natural gases. Truly a great success![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Turkmenbashy Niyazov, the nation of Turkmenistan flourished under your guidance. The National Revival continued long after you were gone. But your people miss you, of course. They loved you. It is time to come back and lead the nation that you love. It is time that the Ruhnama is taught in schools once more. Will you continue to lead Turkmenistan through its cultural revival? Can you build a civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Trait -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JWW_RUHNAMA">
			<Text>Expending [ICON_GREAT_WRITER] Great Writers start a "We Love the King" Day in all cities. The first [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing in a city will spawn a random strategic resource nearby.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JWW_RUHNAMA_SHORT">
			<Text>Ruhnama</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_TURKMEN_UA_DUMMY">
			<Text>Turkmenistan UA Dummy</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Great Work -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_PERSON_JWW_SAPARMURAT_TURKMENBASHY">
			<Text>Turkmenbashy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_JWW_RUHNAMA">
			<Text>Ruhnama</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GREAT_WORK_QUOTE_JWW_RUHNAMA">
			<Text>"You are the meaning of my life.[NEWLINE]I am spending my days only for your happiness.[NEWLINE]My wings are my people.[NEWLINE]My destiny is my people.[NEWLINE]Long live the Turkmen people as the world turns![NEWLINE]Long live the State of Turkmenistan as the world turns!"</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Leader -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV">
			<Text>Saparmurat Niyazov</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_LIVED">
			<Text>1940-2006 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_NAME">
			<Text>Saparmurat Atayevich Niyazov</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>His Excellency Turkmenbashy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TITLES_1">
			<Text>1st President of Turkmenistan</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Building -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_GAS_PIPELINE">
			<Text>Gas Pipeline</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_GAS_PIPELINE_HELP">
			<Text>Can only Be built by Turkmenistan. Replaces the Factory, and has the original bonuses of the Factory. On top of that, trading away strategic resources owned by this city will increase [ICON_GREAT_WRITER] Great Writer points, as well as [ICON_GOLD] Gold. During "We Love the King" Days in this city, improving strategic resources with double the amount of resources on the tile. It only works once per tile though!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_GAS_PIPELINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>+4 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production. +10% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production. +2 Engineer Specialist Slots. Requires 1 [ICON_RES_COAL] Coal.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Trading away strategic resources in city limits will generate [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_GREAT_WRITER] Great Writer points. If strategic resources are improved during a "We Love the King" Day in this city, the amount of resources on the tile will be doubled.</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Unit -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JWW_EDERMAN">
			<Text>Ederman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_HELP_JWW_EDERMAN">
			<Text>Can only be built by Turkmenistan. Replaces the Marine, but is weaker. You can get it earlier than its Marine counterpart however, unlocking at Refrigeration instead of Penicilin. It is built faster in cities with a [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing. On top of that, if trained during a "We Love the King" Day, the Ederman will grant the city a [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing slot.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JWW_EDERMAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Trained faster if the city has a [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing. If trained during a "We Love the King" Day, grant the city a [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing slot.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_EDERMAN_TRAIN_DUMMY">
			<Text>Turkmenistan UU Trained Dummy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JWW_EDERMAN_WLTK_DUMMY">
			<Text>slot created by an Ederman</Text> <!-- cause it appears in the tool tip for Great Writers -->
		</Row>
	<!-- Civilopedia -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Overview</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Turkmenistan is a landlocked country in Central Asia, bordered by Kazakhstan to the northwest, Uzbekistan to the north, east and northeast, Afghanistan to the southeast, Iran to the south and southwest and the Caspian Sea to the west. Ashgabat is the capital and largest city of the country. The population of the country is about 6 million, the lowest of the Central Asian republics. Turkmenistan is one of the most sparsely populated nations in Asia. The area currently known as Turkmenistan has long served as a thoroughfare for many other nations and cultures.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>The Bronze Age to the Silk Road</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Scant remains point to early human settlements east of the Caspian Sea, possibly including Neanderthals, although the archaeology of the region as a whole is under researched. By 2000 BCE, Indo-European peoples had settled throughout the region. Civilizations which occupied the area at this time where the Bactria–Margiana Archaeological Complex, Dahae, Massagetae and Scythians. Alexander the Great conquered the territory in the 4th century BC. After Alexander's death his empire quickly fell apart. It was ruled by Seleucids before the satrap of Parthia declared independence. The Parthians – fierce, nomadic warriors from the north of Iran – then established the kingdom of Parthia, which covered present-day Turkmenistan and Iran. During the 4th to early 7th century CE, much of the population was already in settlements around the fertile river valleys along the Amu Darya, and Merv and Nisa became centers of sericulture, the raising of silkworms. A busy caravan route, connecting Tang Dynasty China and the city of Baghdad passed through Merv. Thus, the city of Merv constituted an important prize for any conqueror.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>The Caliphate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Central Asia came under Arab control after a series of invasions in the late 7th and early 8th centuries and was incorporated into Islamic Caliphate. The city of Merv was occupied by the lieutenants of the caliph Uthman ibn Affan, and was constituted as the capital of Khorasan. Using this city as their base, the Arabs, led by their commander Qutayba ibn Muslim, brought under subjection Balkh, Bokhara, Fergana and Kashgaria, and penetrated into China as far as the province of Kan-suh early in the 8th century. Present Turkmenistan was ruled by Tahirids between 821 and 873. In 873, Arab rule in Central Asia came to an end as a result of the Saffarid conquest. During their dominion Merv, like Samarkand and Bokhara, was one of the great schools of learning, and the celebrated historian Yaqut studied in its libraries. Merv produced a number of scholars in various branches of knowledge, such as Islamic law, Hadith, history, literature, and the like. But Saffarid rule was brief and they were defeated by Samanids in 901. The Samanid dynasty weakened after second half of 10th century and Ghaznavids took present Turkmenistan in 990s. But, they challenged with Seljuks, newcomers from north. Seljuks' decisive victory against them, present Turkmenistan was passed to them in 1041.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The Turkmen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The origins of the Turkmen may be traced back to the Oghuz confederation of nomadic pastoral tribes of the early Middle Ages, who lived in present-day Mongolia and around Lake Baikal in present-day southern Siberia. This confederation was composed of Turkic-speaking peoples who formed the basis of powerful steppe empires in Inner Asia. In the second half of the 8th century, Oghuz components migrated through Jungaria into Central Asia. Oghuz expansion by means of military campaigns went at least as far as the Volga River and Ural Mountains, but the geographic limits of their dominance fluctuated in the steppe areas extending north and west from the Aral Sea. Accounts of Arab geographers and travelers portray the Oghuz ethnic group as lacking centralized authority and being governed by a number of "kings" and "chieftains." Because of their disparate nature as a polity and the vastness of their domains, Oghuz tribes rarely acted in concert. Hence, by the late 10th century, the bonds of their confederation began to loosen. At that time, a clan leader named Seljuk founded a dynasty and the empire that bore his name on the basis of those Oghuz elements that had migrated southward into present-day Turkmenistan and Iran. The Seljuk Empire was centered in Persia. The name Turkmen first appears in written sources of the 10th century to distinguish those Oghuz groups who migrated south into the Seljuk domains and accepted Islam from those that had remained in the steppe. Gradually, the term took on the properties of an ethnonym and was used exclusively to designate Muslim Oghuz, especially those who migrated away from the Syrdariya Basin. By the 13th century, the term Turkmen supplanted the designation Oghuz altogether. The origin of the word Turkmen remains unclear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Passing Between Hands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_5">
			<Text>In the 11th century, Seljuk domains stretched from the delta of the Amu Darya delta into Iran, Iraq, the Caucasus region, Syria, and Asia Minor. In 1055 Seljuk forces entered Baghdad, becoming masters of the Islamic heartlands and important patrons of Islamic institutions. Until these revolts, Turkmen tribesmen were an integral part of the Seljuk military forces. Turkmen migrated with their families and possessions on Seljuk campaigns into Azerbaijan and Anatolia, a process that began the Turkification of these areas. During this time, Turkmen also began to settle the area of present-day Turkmenistan. Prior to the Turkmen habitation, most of this desert had been uninhabited, while the more habitable areas along the Caspian Sea, Kopetdag Mountains, Amu Darya, and Murgap River were populated predominantly by Iranians. The Seljuk empire broke down in the second half of the 12th century, and the Turkmen became independent tribal federation. The Turkic rulers of Khiva took control of the area of Turkmenistan, under the title of Khwarezmshahs in 1221, central Asia suffered a disastrous invasion by Mongol warriors who swept across the region from their base in eastern Asia. Under their commander, Genghis Khan, founder of the Mongol Empire, the Mongols conquered Khwarezm and burned the city of Merv to the ground. These areas were soon repopulated by the Turkmen who survived the invasion and had retreated northward to the plains of Kazakhstan or westward to the shores of the Caspian Sea. After the division of the Mongol Empire, present Turkmenistan was passed to Chagatai Khanate except southernmost part was belonged to Ilkhanate. The history of Turkmenistan from the 16th until the 19th century is mostly known by the relations with the states of Iran, Khiva, Bukhara, and Afghanistan. Wars of the period took place mostly in the lands of Turkmenistan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_6">
			<Text>The Great Game and the Revolutionary Game</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_6">
			<Text>In the 18th century Turkoman tribes came into contact with Tsarist Empire. The Russian Empire began to move into the area in 1869 with the establishment of the Caspian Sea port of Krasnovodsk, present-day Turkmenbashy. fter the suppression of the Emirate of Bukhara in 1868 and the Khanate of Khiva in 1873, the Turkmen area remained independent. Russians decided to move into Transcaspian region, allegedly to subdue Turkmen slave trade and banditry. By 1894, Imperial Russia had taken control of almost all of Turkmenistan except around part of Konye-Urgench was in Khiva and around part of Charju was in Emirate of Bukhara. The Transcaspian Railway was started from the shores of the Caspian in 1879 in order to secure Russian control over the region and provide a rapid military route to the Afghan border. In 1885 a crisis was precipitated by the Russian annexation of the Pandjeh oasis, to the south of Merv, on a territory of modern Afghanistan, which nearly led to war with Britain. Following the October Revolution of 1917 in Russia, Ashgabat became a base for anti-Bolshevik counterrevolutionaries, who soon came under attack from the Tashkent Soviet. The Communists succeeded in taking control of Ashkhabad in the summer of 1918, forming a Soviet. In response, Junaid Khan and forces loyal to the Tsarist government joined together to drive out the Communists. In July 1919, these anti-Communist allies established the independent state of Transcaspia. A small British force, led by General Wilfrid Malleson, from Ashgabat and parts of southern Turkmenistan until 1919.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_7">
			<Text>The Soviet Union</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_7">
			<Text>On 27 October 1924, the Turkestan ASSR was dissolved. In accordance with the decree of the Central Executive Committee of the USSR and the Turkmen SSR, it became one of the republics of the Soviet Union. At this time the modern borders of Turkmenistan were formed. In February 1925, the Turkmenistan Communist Party held its first Congress in Ashkhabad. From this period onward the city experienced rapid growth and industrialisation, although it was severely disrupted by the October 1948 Ashgabat earthquake. With an estimated surface wave magnitude of 7.3, the earthquake killed 10,000–110,000. According to other local sources, two-thirds of a population of 176,000 inhabitants perished. In the 1950s, the 1,375 long kilometre long Qaraqum Canal was built. Draining the Amu-Darya River, it enabled huge areas to be opened for cotton production. It also greatly diminished the inflow of water to the Aral Sea, resulting in an ecological catastrophe. Turkmenistan was not among the most economically developed Soviet republics, with a largely agrarian economy. This is despite exploration and exploitation of enormous oil and gas resources. A discovery of 62 trillion cubic feet Dawletabad gas field in the 1960s became the largest gas field find in the world outside Russia and Middle East.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Independence and Modern Turkmenistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_8">
			<Text>Turkmenistan became independent on October 27, 1991, amidst the dissolution of the Soviet Union. The former head of Turkmenistan's Communist Party at the time of independence, Saparmurat Niyazov, was elected president of the newly independent nation in an uncontested election. At the 25th Congress of the Communist Party of Turkmenistan in the autumn of 1991, the party decided to dissolve itself, a process that continued into 1992. In its place, the Turkmenistan Democratic Party was organized, and on December 16, 1991, Saparmurat Niyazov, who was elected President of Turkmenistan in October 1990, signed a decree officially conferring TDP membership on former TCP members. Niyazov assumed the title of Turkmenbashi, or Leader of all Turkmen, penning the Ruhnama, which was made a mandatory reading in Turkmenistan's schools and months of the calendar were renamed after members of his family. Turkmenistan's declaration of "permanent neutrality" was formally recognized by the United Nations in 1995. On December 21, 2006, Niyazov died unexpectedly, leaving no heir-apparent and an unclear line of succession. A former deputy prime minister rumored to be the illegitimate son of Niyazov, Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedow, unconstitutionally became acting president. In an election on February 11, 2007, Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedow was elected president with 89% of the vote and 95% turnout, although the election was condemned by outside observers. Following his election, Berdimuhamedow moved to reduce foreign isolation and reversed some of Niyazov's more egocentric and damaging policies. Internet cafes offering free and uncensored Web access opened in Ashgabat. President Berdimuhamedow began to reduce the personality cult surrounding Niyazov and the office of the president. He called for an end to the elaborate pageants of music and dancing that formerly greeted the president on his arrival anywhere. However, Berdimuhamedow is criticized for building a personality cult of his own. On 19 March 2022, Serdar Berdimuhamedov was sworn in as Turkmenistan’s new president to succeed his father.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Gas and Petrol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_9">
			<Text>The country possesses the world's fourth largest reserves of natural gas and substantial oil resources. Turkmenistan has taken a cautious approach to economic reform, hoping to use gas and cotton sales to sustain its economy. President Niyazov spent much of the country's revenue on extensively renovating cities, Ashgabat in particular. Corruption watchdogs voiced particular concern over the management of Turkmenistan's currency reserves, most of which are held in off-budget funds such as the Foreign Exchange Reserve Fund in the Deutsche Bank in Frankfurt, according to a report released in April 2006 by London-based non-governmental organization Global Witness. Turkmenistan's first electrical power plant was built in 1909 and went into full operation in 1913. As of 2019 it was still in operation. The original triple-turbine Hindukush hydroelectric plant, built by the Austro-Hungarian company Ganz Works. As of 2010 Turkmenistan featured eight major power plants operating on natural gas. Turkmenistan is the world's tenth-largest cotton producer. Turkmenistan reported arrival of 14,438 foreign tourists in 2019.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_10">
			<Text>Secret Census</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_10">
			<Text>The last census to be published was held in 1995. Results of every census since then have been kept secret. Available figures indicate that most of Turkmenistan's citizens are ethnic Turkmens with sizeable minorities of Uzbeks and Russians. Smaller minorities include Kazakhs, Tatars, Ukrainians, Kurds, Armenians, Azeris, Balochs and Pashtuns. The percentage of ethnic Russians in Turkmenistan dropped from 18.6% in 1939 to 9.5% in 1989. Turkmen is the official language of Turkmenistan. According to the CIA World Factbook, Muslims constitute 93% of the population while 6% of the population are followers of the Eastern Orthodox Church and the remaining 1% religion is reported as non-religious. Former president Saparmurat Niyazov ordered that basic Islamic principles be taught in public schools. President Niyazov wrote his own religious text, published in separate volumes in 2001 and 2004, entitled the Ruhnama.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_11">
			<Text>Cultural Nomads</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_11">
			<Text>The Turkmen people have traditionally been nomads and equestrians, and even today after the fall of the USSR attempts to urbanize the Turkmens have not been very successful. They never really formed a coherent nation or ethnic group until they were forged into one by Joseph Stalin in the 1930s. Rather they are divided into clans, and each clan has its own dialect and style of dress. Turkmens are famous for making knotted Turkmen carpets, often mistakenly called Bukhara rugs in the West. These are elaborate and colorful hand-knotted carpets, and these too help indicate the distinctions among the various Turkmen clans. Ethnic groups throughout the region build yurts, circular houses with dome roofs, made of a wooden frame covered in felt from the hides of sheep or other livestock. Horses are an essential ingredient of recreational activities in most of the region, in such games as horseback fighting, in which riders grapple to topple each other from their horses; horse racing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_HEADING_12">
			<Text>What We Like, Clothes and Sport</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_TEXT_12">
			<Text>Turkmen men wear traditional telpek hats, which are large black or white sheepskin hats resembling afros. Traditional dress for men consists of these high, shaggy sheepskin hats and red robes over white shirts. Women wear long sack-dresses over narrow trousers. Holidays in Turkmenistan are laid out in the Constitution of Turkmenistan. Holidays in Turkmenistan practiced internationally include New Year's Day, Nowruz, Eid al-Fitr, and Eid al-Adha. Turkmenistan exclusive holidays include Melon Day, Turkmen Woman's Day, and the Day of Remembrance for Saparmurat Niyazov. Education is universal and mandatory through the secondary level. The most popular sport in Turkmenistan is football. The national team has never qualified for the FIFA World Cup but has appeared twice at the AFC Asian Cup, in 2004 and 2019, failing to advance past the group stage at both editions. Another popular sport is archery, Turkmenistan holds league and local competitions for archery.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Overview</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Saparmurat Atayevich Niyazov was a Turkmen politician who ruled Turkmenistan from 1985 until his death in 2006. He was First Secretary of the Turkmen Communist Party from 1985 until 1991 and supported the 1991 Soviet coup d'état attempt. He continued to rule Turkmenistan for 15 years after independence from the Soviet Union in 1991. In his time, he was one of the world's most totalitarian, despotic and repressive dictators. He promoted a cult of personality around himself and imposed his personal eccentricities upon the country, such as renaming Turkmen months and days of the week to references of his autobiography the Ruhnama. He made it mandatory to read the Ruhnama in schools, universities and governmental organizations, new governmental employees were tested on the book at job interviews and an exam on its teachings was a part of the driving test in Turkmenistan. In 2005, he closed down all rural libraries and hospitals outside of the capital city Ashgabat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Niyazov was born on 19 February 1940 in Gypjak, just outside Ashgabat in the Turkmen SSR. He was a member of the influential Teke tribe of the Turkmens. After finishing school in 1959, he worked as an instructor in the Turkmen trade-union exploratory committee. He then studied at the Leningrad Polytechnic Institute, where in 1967 he received a diploma as an electrical engineer. After graduating, he went to study in Russia, but was expelled a few years later for academic failure. In 1962 Niyazov started his political career, becoming a member of the Communist Party. He quickly rose through the ranks, becoming First Secretary of the Ashgabat City Committee, and First Secretary of the Communist Party of the Turkmen SSR in 1985. He gained this post after Soviet General Secretary Mikhail Gorbachev had removed his predecessor, Muhammetnazar Gapurov, following a cotton-related scandal. Under Niyazov, the Turkmen Communist Party had a reputation as one of the most hardline and unreformed party organizations in the Soviet Union.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_3">
			<Text>The End of Gorbachev</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_3">
			<Text>On 13 January 1990, Niyazov became Chairman of the Supreme Soviet of the Turkmen SSR, the supreme legislative body in the republic. The post was equivalent to that of president. Niyazov supported the Soviet coup attempt of 1991. However, after the coup collapsed, he set about separating Turkmenistan from the dying Soviet Union. The Turkmen Supreme Soviet declared Turkmenistan independent and appointed Niyazov as the country's first president on 27 October 1991. On 21 June 1992 the Turkmenistani presidential election of 1992 featured Niyazov as the sole candidate and chosen as the country's first popularly elected president. A year later he declared himself Türkmenbashy, meaning "Leader of all Turkmen". In 1994 a plebiscite extended Niyazov's term to 2002 so he could oversee a 10-year development plan. The official results showed that 99.9% of voters approved this proposal. On 28 December 1999, Parliament declared Niyazov President for Life; parliamentary elections had been held a few weeks earlier for which the president had hand-picked all candidates.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The Ruhnama</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Niyazov became president at the transition of Turkmenistan from a Soviet republic to an independent state. His presidency was characterised by an initial crumbling of the centralised Soviet model that in many respects was unsuited for a transition to smaller, separate, states. There was outside concern about press freedom and to a lesser extent religious rights of minority religious groups. Niyazov attempted to replace the cultural gravity of the Soviet Union with the Ruhnama. Scholars note Ruhnama to be a mosaic of different literary genres, the text combines spiritual and political advice, legends, autobiography, short stories, poems, and fabricated Turkmen history, an epic in its own right. He also took part in creating new holidays with a specific Turkmen nature and introduced a new Latin-based Turkmen alphabet to replace Russian Cyrillic. Niyazov became a substitute for the vacuum left by the downfall of the communist system, with his image replacing those of Marx and Lenin. He renamed a town near Krasnovodsk after his title, and renamed schools, airports and even a meteorite after himself and members of his family. The doting actions of the official Turkmen media supported a cult of personality. In Ashgabat, he erected a rotating, $12 million, golden statue of himself that always faces the sun. The eccentric nature of some of his decrees, and the vast number of images of the president led to the perception, especially in western countries, of a despotic leader, rich on oil wealth glorifying himself whilst the population gained no benefit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_5">
			<Text>The Money Man</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Despite emphasizing a need to move from central planning to a market economy and to a full democracy during his reign, neither plan progressed. Yearly plans set forth by the government and a centralised economy gave little indication of moving away from state-dominated economics, and the dictatorial nature of many of his decrees and his declaring himself "President for Life" gave little hope as to much progress in these two areas. In the years following independence, Turkmenistan invested heavily in plants and machinery in an attempt to convert it from being primarily a supplier of petroleum to a more advanced economy; such investments included oil refineries and a polyethylene plant. In an interview with Rossiyskaya Gazeta newspaper, Niyazov claimed that Turkmenistan was able to process 85% of its domestic output. In 1991 and 2001, Niyazov issued decrees making water, gas, electricity, and refined salt free to use for ten-year periods.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Political Victories and Hidden Defeats</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_6">
			<Text>One of the earliest acts of the president was to abolish the death penalty. He also granted official human rights to the people, though they were not respected in practice with his government being criticised as one of the worst human rights violators in the world. Press freedom under Niyazov's leadership was much criticised as it was with other former Soviet central Asian states. Turkmenistan's media constantly doted on the president and helped build his cult of personality. In May 2000, the government revoked all Internet licenses except for the state-owned Turkmen Telecom. In March 2004, 15,000 public health workers were dismissed including nurses, midwives, school health visitors and orderlies. In February 2005 all hospitals outside Ashgabat were ordered closed, with the reasoning that the sick should come to the capital for treatment. According to the paper Neitralniy Turkmenistan physicians were ordered to swear an oath to the President, replacing the Hippocratic Oath. All libraries outside of the capital were also closed. In January 2006, one-third of the country's elderly had their pensions discontinued, while another 200,000 had theirs reduced. Pensions received during the prior two years were ordered paid back to the state.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_7">
			<Text>The Forgotten Neutral Nation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_7">
			<Text>Niyazov promoted a policy of strict neutrality in foreign affairs, refraining from seeking membership in NATO or GUAM and almost ignoring the CSTO. Turkmenistan has not participated in any United Nations peacekeeping missions. It has however become a member of Interpol. In 2005 Turkmenistan would downgrade its links with the Commonwealth of Independent States becoming only an associate member under article 8 of the CIS charter, as such it would not participate in any of the military structures of the CIS.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_8">
			<Text>The Later Years</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_8">
			<Text>On 25 November 2002, Niyazov's motorcade was fired upon at about 7 a.m. in downtown Ashgabat as he was traveling to his office from his official residence in Arshabil. Niyazov claimed that it was an attempt at a coup, and as a result, the Turkmen government arrested thousands of suspected conspirators and members of their families. The summer of 2004 saw a leaflet campaign calling for the overthrow and trial of Niyazov. The authorities were unable to stop the campaign and the President responded by firing his Interior Minister and director of the police academy on national television. Niyazov later announced that surveillance cameras were to be placed at all major streets and sites in Turkmenistan, an apparent precaution against future attempts. On the afternoon of 21 December 2006, Turkmen state television announced that President Saparmurat Niyazov had died of a sudden heart attack, age 66. The circumstances of Niyazov's death have been surrounded by some media speculation. Some Turkmen opposition sources also claim that Niyazov died several days before the officially announced date of 21 December. Niyazov was buried in his ready prepared tomb in Kipchak Mosque on 24 December at his home village of Gypjak, approximately 7 kilometres west of Ashgabat. Prior to being moved to the village, Niyazov's body lay in state in an open coffin in the presidential palace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Strange Laws</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TEXT_9">
			<Text>Throughout his time as President, Niyazov's promulgated some truly strange laws. These included banning the use of lip syncing at public concerts and cultural events in 2005, citing a negative effect on the development of musical arts incurred by the use of recorded music. He also banished dogs from the capital, order the building of an indoor ice skating rink, outlawed opera, ballet and circuses, decreed that men should no longer wear long hair or beards, banned news reporters and presenters from wearing make-up on television, abolished the Turkmen word for bread, for it to be replaced with Gurbansoltan, his mother's name, and discouraged gold teeth.</Text>
		</Row>
		
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_UNIT_JWW_EDERMAN_TEXT">
			<Text>The Special Task Force Türkmen Edermen, meaning Valiant Turkmen, is a military unit of the Armed Forces of Turkmenistan. It is a composite unit drawn from the armed forces and national law enforcement agencies such as the Ministry of Internal Affairs, the State Border Service, and the Ministry for National Security. The Turkmen Alabai, adorns the emblem of the Turkmen Edermen unit. It has also become a de facto unit mascot. It primarily has a special operations role during war time situations. The main distinguishing feature of the battalion is high level of combat, theoretical and physical training.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_JWW_GAS_PIPELINE_TEXT">
			<Text>Turkmenistan is a natural gas and petroleum exporting country. Turkmenistan's major gas deposits were discovered in its central and eastern areas in the 1940s and 1950s, and in the 1980s the republic became the second largest producer of gas in the Soviet Union, behind the Russian SFSR. One method of export is the pipeline. Turkmenistan is an origin in the Central Asia–Center gas pipeline system, constructed by the Soviet Union between 1960 and 1998. In 2003, the late President of Turkmenistan Saparmurat Niyazov proposed to renovate existing systems and construct a new parallel pipeline to the western branch. The Central Asia–China gas pipeline began construction in 2007. The Dauletabad–Sarakhs–Khangiran pipeline was completed in October 2009. The East–West pipeline, operated by Türkmengaz,w as completed in 2015. The Korpeje–Kordkuy pipeline to Iran was inaugurated on 29 December 1997 by presidents Saparmurat Niyazov and Mohammad Khatami. The Trans-Afghanistan Pipeline is still in construction, while the proposed Afghanistan Oil Pipeline never came to fruition.</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Diplomacy Responses -->
		<!-- First Greeting -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Türkmenbashy, leader of all Turkmen and friend of God. Enjoy your time here at Turkmenistan and bask in the glory of our nation!</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Defeated -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>No, it cannot be! My people need me, Turkmenbashy, they demand for me to lead them because of their mentality!</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Diplomacy: Wars, Denunciations, and DoF -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_ATTACKED_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>You dare attack me and my sacred lands?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>I declare you a friend of all Turkmen. Now you can smile at death in the face and it will leave you untouched!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Turkmenistan is the motherland of neutrality by my decree. But your deeds are so outlandish, not even Turkmenistan can stand and watch![NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>I declare your land sacred Turkmen land. Thus, it must be under my command!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I cannot allow you to venture close and take the Motherland, its land is sacred and blessed from heaven itself!</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You see, there are many portraits, pictures, and monuments of me. The mentality of my people demand it, so it is no use trying to control my land.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>I hope that life for you can be just as beautiful as our melons.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>I watched young dogs when I was young. They were given bones to gnaw. Those of you whose teeth have fallen out did not gnaw on bones. This is my advice.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>I am an enjoy from heaven on high! I will be speaking to God about condemning you to hell, where you belong.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Misc -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>All Turkmen life is as beautiful as our melons. I cannot allow your nearby army to get into a conflict with the glorious Turkmen people!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_LETS_HEAR_IT_1">
			<Text>My glorious country will need a bit more convincing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_LOSEWAR_1">
			<Text>This outcome is decidedly unturkmen-like. I hope you reflect on your horrible actions to all Turkmen, or else I may need to have another word with God!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>This is a necessity for me. I would even give sacred Turkmen melons for it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Fate decreed this pain and path for me. My Turkmen people want me, Turkmenbashy, to continue this war!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE">
			<Text>Rejoice! I decided to give you access to beautiful Turkmenistan soil!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_REPEAT_NO_1">
			<Text>I ban this deal from Turkmenistan. You annoyed me too much.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>The Turkmen people call upon you to grant them their sacred needs! If you accept, I will personally grant you a copy of Ruhnama, which is necessary to read to get to heaven!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Sounds like I will need to speak to God to not allow you in heaven, as no Turkmen can do no wrong!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>God has called upon me to take sacred Turkmen lands, I cannot stop so early!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>Fate has already decreed for me this victory, and all Turkmen rejoice due to my outstanding brillance.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Unique Diplomacy Responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_DOG_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Türkmenbashy, leader of all Turkmen and-- Hold on a second, is that a dog? Get it out of my sight, I banished dogs from Ashgabat! I can't stand their unappealing odor. I will have a word with God about not letting you in heaven.</Text>
		</Row>

		<!-- Cultural Influence -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now reading a book called "Ruhnama" and banishing dogs from their homes due to their "unappealing odor". I worry the rest of the world will also succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JWW_SAPARMURAT_NIYAZOV_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>We are glad to see that your people are now reading a book called "Ruhnama" and banishing dogs from their homes due to their "unappealing odor". The amazing works of our civilization are truly inspiring!</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- City Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_0">
			<Text>Ashgabat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_1">
			<Text>Türkmenabat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_2">
			<Text>Dashoguz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_3">
			<Text>Mary</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_4">
			<Text>Balkanabat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_5">
			<Text>Serdar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_6">
			<Text>Baýramaly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_7">
			<Text>Anau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_8">
			<Text>Turkmenbashi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_9">
			<Text>Tejen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_10">
			<Text>Magdanly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_11">
			<Text>Kerki</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_12">
			<Text>Ýolöten</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_13">
			<Text>Köneürgench</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_14">
			<Text>Hazar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_15">
			<Text>Ýylanly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_16">
			<Text>Gumdag</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_17">
			<Text>Baharly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_18">
			<Text>Gazojak</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_19">
			<Text>Bereket</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_20">
			<Text>Boldumsaz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_21">
			<Text>Gökdepe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_22">
			<Text>Hojambaz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_23">
			<Text>Seýdi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_24">
			<Text>Saýat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_25">
			<Text>Kaakhka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_26">
			<Text>Görogly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_27">
			<Text>Serhetabat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_28">
			<Text>Garabogaz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_29">
			<Text>Babadaýhan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_30">
			<Text>Galkynysh</Text>
		</Row>
	<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_0">
			<Text>Gurbanguly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_1">
			<Text>Kasymguly</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_2">
			<Text>Ata</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_3">
			<Text>Sakhat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_4">
			<Text>Rejepbay</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_5">
			<Text>Öwezgeldi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_6">
			<Text>Tagandurdy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_7">
			<Text>Akja</Text>
			<gender>feminine</gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_8">
			<Text>Gülshat</Text>
			<gender>feminine</gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_9">
			<Text>Gurbansoltan</Text>
			<gender>feminine</gender>
		</Row>
		
	<!-- Additional Achievements Support -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_NAME">
			<Text>JakeWalrusWhale's Turkmenistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_MODID">
			<Text>c5b04927-2c13-4884-9961-134b2bf76c8b</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_AUTHORS">
			<Text>JakeWalrusWhale</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_VICTORY_HEADER">
			<Text>All Hail Turkmenbashy!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_VICTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>Win as Turkmenistan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_SPECIAL_HEADER">
			<Text>#1 Ashgabat Times Bestseller</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_SPECIAL_TEXT">
			<Text>As Turkmenistan, get the "Ruhnama" Great Work of Writing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TAB_JWW_CIVS_TURKMENISTAN_HEADER">
			<Text>JakeWalrusWhale's Civilizations</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JWW_TURKMENISTAN_CIVS_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>Achievements for mods created by JakeWalrusWhale</Text>
		</Row>	
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>