<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--CIVILIZATION-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Afghan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DESC">
			<Text>Afghan Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Afghanistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--TAL-->
		<Replace Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_TAL_AFGHANISTAN">
			<Text>Afghanistan</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Pedia-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Central Asian region now known as Afghanistan has served as a focal point of trans-Eurasian trade for millennia Unfortunately, it has also been the site of conflict for as long of a time. Known as “The Graveyard of Empires,” Afghanistan's critical location has made it a sought-after territory, but one that has been successfully resistant to some imperial ventures. Ethnically and linguistically diverse. Afghanistan is a melting pot of cultures, resulting in a strong national literary tradition.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Geography and Climate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Afghanistan is a landlocked region located at the crossroads of continental trade. Geographically diverse, Afghanistan contains plains in the north and southwest and highlands and the Hindu, Kush and Pamir mountains in the central and southeastern areas. Afghanistan is generally quite dry, but is devoid of desert. The mountainous regions contain a number key mountain passes leading to South Asia.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Early History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Evidence of human settlement exists as early as 3000 BCE. In 2000 BCE, Central Asian peoples, including Indo-Iranians, migrated into the region. These societies were characterized by the Zoroastrian faith. In fact, the prophet Zoroaster is believed to have been born in the Afghan city of Balkh. These peoples were likely connected with other, more developed early civilizations such as the Harappans of the Indus River Valley. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Much of Afghanistan's early history is characterized by being a part of a series of larger, more prominent empires. The Achaemenid Empire conquered Afghanistan under the emperor Darius I, at which point the land was divided into satraps, or local units of government. This came to an end with the destruction of Achaemenid Persia at the hands of Alexander the Great.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Alexander's Empire and Successors</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_4">
			<Text>After Alexander the Great of Macedonia arrived in Afghanistan in 330 BCE, Afghanistan was incorporated into the short-lived Macedonian Empire. More significantly, one of the succesor empires to Alexander’s Macdeon, the Seleucid Empire, then gained control of the region. Only decades later, Afghanistan was ceded to the Mauryan Empire on the Indian subcontinent as part of an alliance. The Mauryans introduced Buddhism to the region. This was manifest in the Buddhas of Bamiyan, the largest statues of Buddha before they were destroyed by the Taliban in 2001.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_5">
			<Text>The Kushan Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_5">
			<Text>The final state to occupy Afghanistan prior to Islamisation was the Parthian Empire, during the first century BCE. Soon after, in the first century CE, the Kushan Empire emerged, centered in Afghanistan. This great Buddhist empire had contact with all corners of Eurasia, including China and Rome. It took influence from Hellenistic culture, the product of Alexander’s influence. The Silk Road - the crosscontinental trade from China to Europe - was made possible by the peace created by the Kushans. It was also expanded further - the empire connected the Silk Road commerce to the Indian Ocean trade.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Kushan Empire lasted three centuries. The kingdom split and collapsed through the third and fourth centuries, succumbing to a number of successor dynasties.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Islam comes to Afghanistan Islam was brought into Afghanistan through Herat and Zaranj by 642 AD. Islam’s reception was mixed. The noteworthy religious diversity of the region - with Hinduism, Buddhism, Zoroastrianism, and other faiths - was not easily supplanted. Nonetheless, Islam became a strong force in Afghanistan, and has been ever since.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Afghanistan fell under a series of Islamic empires, where it flourished. The Ghazanavid Empire, centered in Afghanistan at Ghazana, completed the Islamization of Afghanistan by the 10th century. During this time, Kabul thrived as an anchor of the Muslim world. This dynasty also helped to introduce Islam to India. The Ghazanvids gave way to further Persian and Turkic dynasties.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Mongol Invasion</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_6">
			<Text>In the 13th century, the Mongol Genghis Khan invaded Afghanistan. The cities that flourished under the Islamic dynasties were destroyed, and the country depopulated. Afghanistan was subjected to Mongol rule until another steppe power, the Timurids, forced the Mongols out a century later. Babur, who would go on to found the Mughal Empire in India, also conquered his way through Kabul. Eventually, the Afghan region was divided between the Mughal Empire and the Safavid Persians.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_7">
			<Text>The Hotak Dynasty</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_7">
			<Text>Mirwais Hotak rebelled against the Safavids in 1709. This moment is regarded as the founding moment of Afganistan as its own polity, and Hotak is regarded as its grandfather. While Hotak himself did not live long, his family carried on his dynasty and the struggle against the Persians. Hotak’s son Mahmud led his armies to the Safavid capital at Isfahan, where he sacked the city and declared himself King of Persia. However, a resurgent Persian force ousted the Hotakis by 1729.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_8">
			<Text>The Durrani Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_8">
			<Text>In 1738, the Persians made their way to Afghanistan itself, freeing Ahmed Shah Durrani in Kandahar. Durrani was appointed the commander of the local forces under the Persians. After the Persian dynasty collapsed, Durrani was chosen to rule Afghanistan. Durrani and his army conquered Afghanistan, Pakistan, parts of Iran and as far as Delhi in India. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Durrani is regarded as the father of the Afghan nation. Durrani went on to defeat the Maratha Empire in India. Ahmad Shah Durrani died naturally in 1772, and his descendants continued his legacy for decades. In the 19th century, the Afghan empire was under threat from both Persians and a Sikh empire backed by the British. The Durrani declined, and the arrival of European colonialism signaled the end of the Durrani empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_9">
			<Text>The Great Game</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_9">
			<Text>The Great Game refers to the geopolitical struggle between Russia and Britain over the Central Asian countries, including Afghanistan. Much as the dynasties of old desired Afghanistan for its crossroads location, the Brits and Russians sought to control this valuable link between Europe and Asia, as well as British India and Russian lands.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The First Anglo-Afghan war began with the British ostensibly supporting Shah Shujah’s attempt to reclaim what was his. The British installed Shujah and occupied the country despite their claim that they were not invading. Afghans began insurrectionary actions in 1841, eventually forcing the British out of the country.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Second Anglo-Afghan war occurred amidst continuing Anglo-Russian tension. It began after a British diplomatic mission (sent in response to a Russian one) to Kabul was turned away. The British began to invade, and the Afghan ruler, Mohammad Yaqub Khan, ceded control of Afghanistan’s foreign affairs to the British in exchange for protection. As had happened before, uprisings in major Afghan cities caused renewed conflict. The conflict ended with the continuance of British influence over Afghanistan’s foreign affairs.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_10">
			<Text>The Nation of Afghanistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_10">
			<Text>Afghanistan finally declared its status as an independent nation-state , triggering the Third Anglo-Afghan War, in 1918. The limited war ended with the ceasing of hostilities between Afghanistan and British India. King Amanullah Khan instituted reforms in the new nation, upsetting religious leaders and tribesmen. This forced his abdication in 1929. Rebels took Kabul, but then Amunallah’s cousin Nadir Shah defeated them.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Nadir Shah’s son Mohammed Zahir Shah took power after his father’s assassination in 1933. The monarchy continued through the 1970s. Afghanistan was not ideologically involved in the World Wars, nor the Cold War, until this time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_11">
			<Text>Soviets, Taliban and Americans</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_11">
			<Text>The Marxist People’s Democratic Party of Afghanistan successfully led a revolution in 1978. Civil war started almost immediately. The Soviet Union invaded Afghanistan in 1979, and they stayed there until 1989. The war was deadly for both sides. The United States covertly armed Mujahideen rebels. These rebels included Saudi radical Osama bin Laden.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Civil war continued, even after the Soviets left in 1989. Out of this chaos emerged the Taliban, an Islamic fundamentalist movement that took power in 1996. The Islamic Emirate of Afghanistan was notably repressive toward women, advocating a strict interpretation of Sharia law.The Taliban never controlled all of Afghanistan’s territory, as insurgent groups never dissipated.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the September 11 terrorist attacks, the United States invaded Afghanistan in 2001 because Osama bin Laden was believed to be hiding there. While bin Laden was not found until 2010 in Pakistan, the Americans did depose the Taliban. The Taliban was one of many insurgent groups that persisted in occupied Afghanistan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_12">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_CIVS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_12">
			<Text>Sir Arthur Conan Doyle’s character Dr. Watson, companion to Sherlock Holmes, is a veteran of conflict in Afghanistan in both Conan’s original version and the 2010 BBC modernization of the character. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Afghan currency is the Afghani.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]There is no majority ethnicity in Afghanistan, nor is there an Afghan ethnicity. Pashtuns comprise 42% of the population according to the CIA, with Tajiks comprising 27% and Hazara and Uzbeks comprising 8% each.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Despite a low literacy rate, Pashtun poetry and proverb play an important role in Afghan culture.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Afghanistan is part of the Golden Crescent, which produces more opium than any other part of the world. The Taliban declaration of poppy cultivation as un-Islamic resulted in one of the most successful anti-drug campaigns the world has ever seen, according to the International Journal of Drug Policy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Cities-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_1">
			<Text>Kandahar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_2">
			<Text>Kabul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_3">
			<Text>Herat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_4">
			<Text>Multan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_5">
			<Text>Peshawar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_6">
			<Text>Balkh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_7">
			<Text>Jalalabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_8">
			<Text>Jammu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_9">
			<Text>Mazar-i-Sharif</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_10">
			<Text>Lashkargah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_11">
			<Text>Taloqan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_12">
			<Text>Khost</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_13">
			<Text>Sheberghan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_14">
			<Text>Ghazni</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_15">
			<Text>Jalandhar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_16">
			<Text>Kunduz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_17">
			<Text>Sar-e Pol</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_18">
			<Text>Chaghcharan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_19">
			<Text>Farah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_20">
			<Text>Mihtarlam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_21">
			<Text>Pul-i-Alam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_22">
			<Text>Samangan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_23">
			<Text>Fayzabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_24">
			<Text>Zaranj</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_25">
			<Text>Asadabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_26">
			<Text>Maymana</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_27">
			<Text>Puli Khumri</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_28">
			<Text>Maidan Shar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_29">
			<Text>Gardez</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_0">
			<Text>Masjidi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_1">
			<Text>Laila</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_2">
			<Text>Aroon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_3">
			<Text>Samira</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_4">
			<Text>Behrooz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_5">
			<Text>Zabiullah</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_6">
			<Text>Ramez</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_7">
			<Text>Pooya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_8">
			<Text>Awrang</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_9">
			<Text>Lashkar</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--LEADER-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI">
			<Text>Ahmad Shah Durrani</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Pedia-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_NAME">
			<Text>Ahmad Shah Durrani</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Ahmad Shah Durrani, also known as Ahmad Khan Abdali, was the founder of the Durrani Empire and is regarded as the founder of the modern state of Afghanistan. He began his career by enlisting as a young soldier in the military of the Afsharid kingdom and quickly rose to become a commander of the Abdali Regiment, a cavalry of four thousand Abdali Pashtun soldiers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the death of Nader Shah Afshar in 1747, Ahmad Shah Durrani was chosen as King of Afghanistan. Rallying his Afghan tribes and allies, he pushed east towards the Mughal and the Maratha empires of India, west towards the disintegrating Afsharid Empire of Persia, and north toward the Khanate of Bukhara. Within a few years, he extended his control from Khorasan in the west to Kashmir and North India in the east, and from the Amu Darya in the north to the Arabian Sea in the south.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Durrani's mausoleum is located at Kandahar, Afghanistan, adjacent to the Shrine of the Cloak in the center of the city. Afghans often refer to him as Ahmad Shah Baba ("Ahmad Shah the Father").</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Durrani's victory over the Marathas influenced the history of the subcontinent and, in particular, British policy in the region. His refusal to continue his campaigns deeper into India prevented a clash with the East India Company and allowed them to continue to acquire power and influence after they took complete control of the former Mughal province of Bengal in 1793. However, fear of another Afghan invasion was to haunt British policy for almost half a century after the battle of Panipat. The acknowledgment of Abdali's military accomplishments is reflected in a British intelligence report on the Battle of Panipat, which referred to Ahmad Shah as the 'King of Kings'. This fear led in 1798 to a British envoy being sent to the Persian court in part to instigate the Persians in their claims on Herat to forestall an Afghan invasion of India that might have halted British East India company's expansion.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Ahmad Shah's successors, beginning with his son Timur and ending with Shuja Shah Durrani, proved largely incapable of governing the last Afghan empire and faced with advancing enemies on all sides. Much of the territory conquered by Ahmad Shah fell to others by the end of the 19th century. They not only lost the outlying territories but also alienated some Pashtun tribes and those of other Durrani lineages. Until Dost Mohammad Khan's ascendancy in 1826, chaos reigned in Afghanistan, which effectively ceased to exist as a single entity, disintegrating into a fragmented collection of small countries or units. This policy ensured that he did not continue on the path of other conquerors like Babur or Muhammad of Ghor and make India the base for his empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Lived-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_LIVED">
			<Text>1722 - 1772 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Titles-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Afghanistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Emperor of Loy Afghanistan</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DOM-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_DAWN_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TEXT">
			<Text>Blessings, Ahmad Shah Durrani, father and founder of the Afghan Empire. Plagued by centuries of bloodshed and war, Afghanistan is a harsh but resilient nation. Caught between the great powers of India, Persia, and Russia, her people, talented poets and craftsmen, have been tested and tried by countless invasions and innumerous campaigns to tame her treacherous hinterlands. But through these trials, the Afghan people, in piety and in spirit, have survived and prospered.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]O' pious Emperor, the foes that once posed threat to the Afghan nation emerge once more. Will you rise to defend her ways and to repulse those that would impregnate her? Will you foster great works of song and verse to honour her people? Will you build a civilisation that stands the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Responses-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I am Ahmad Shah Durrani, chosen father of Afghanistan. You would be foolish not to bow to me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I would be buried in gaze of my Lord, and Afghanistan with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You have made a fatal mistake in attacking Afghanistan.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>Loyal friends are hard to come by, and harder to keep. Come, join me in a public Declaration of Friendship that shall last eternally.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You are nothing but trouble for me and my people.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>You have betrayed my trust for the last time.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>It is clear that you mean ill of my people. I will defend this nation with your blood.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Come then. Let us see how you fare in Afghan lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Greetings, heathen.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>So you're back.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Greetings, my friend. Welcome back.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I do not fear your forces entering the lands of my people. Let them try.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>Your great wealth is known far and wide. I asked you to share your luxuries with those peoples less fortunate.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>Come. Afghanistan is no threat to you. Open your borders to us and we shall ensure your people have safe passage in ours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>My people suffer whilst yours grow fat and lazy. Come, share your wealth with is.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>You surely jest.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>As you will. It bothers me not.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--UNIQUE TRAIT-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_SHORT">
			<Text>Graveyard of Empires</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI">
			<Text>Enemy Units in your borders take damage when in Hills or next to Mountains. This and combat victories in Friendly Territory produce [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Writer Points.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--UNIQUE 1-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_JEZAILCHI">
			<Text>Jezailchi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_JEZAILCHI_HELP">
			<Text>Single-ranged Mounted unit that fights best in Hills and in Friendly Territory. Only Afghanistan may build it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_JEZAILCHI_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Jezailchi is a late-game Mounted Unit with a single-range attack, allowing it to take no damage when engaging in battle. This unit is much more effective when fighting in Hills, especially within your borders, although it is inherently weaker than the Cavalry that it replaces. They are unique to Afghanistan. Use Jezailchi to repel enemy invaders and protect your territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_JFD_JEZAILCHI_TEXT">
			<Text>The jezail was a simple, cost-efficient and often handmade muzzle-loading long arm commonly used in British India, Central Asia and parts of the Middle East in the past. They were generally handmade weapons, and consequently they widely varied in their construction. Jezails were seen as very personal weapons, and unlike the typical military weapons of the time which were very plain and utilitarian, jezails tended to be well crafted and were usually intricately decorated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Promotions-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JEZAILCHI">
			<Text>Afghan Hinterlands</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_JFD_JEZAILCHI_HELP">
			<Text>+20% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength when attacking in [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Hills[ENDCOLOR] and +10% when attacking in [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Friendly Territory[ENDCOLOR].</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--UNIQUE 2-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_DIVAN">
			<Text>Divan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_DIVAN_HELP">
			<Text>Receive [ICON_CULTURE] Culture whenever a new tile is acquired by this city.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Land trade routes originating from this city have a 50% increase in range and produce an additional 2 [ICON_GOLD] Gold when connecting to another civilization.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_DIVAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The unique Divan is the Caravansary replacement for Afghanistan. Like the Caravansary, the Divan improves the range and [ICON_GOLD] Gold yield of land trade routes. However, it also produces [ICON_CULTURE] Culture whenever a new Tile is acquired, equal to the city's culture output. It also possesses a [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing slot.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_DIVAN_TEXT">
			<Text>A divan or diwan was a high governmental body in a number of Islamic states, or its chief official. In Arabic, the term was first used for the army registers, then generalized to any register, and by metonymy applied to specific government departments. The sense of the word evolved to "custom house" and "council chamber," then to "long, cushioned seat," such as are found along the walls in Middle-Eastern council chambers. The latter is the sense that entered European languages as divan (furniture).</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--MOD-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_JFD_AFGHANISTAN_DURRANI_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>AFGHANISTAN (AHMAD SHAH DURRANI)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE TRAIT: GRAVEYARD OF EMPIRES[NEWLINE]Enemy Units in your borders take damage when in Hills or next to Mountains. This and combat victories in Friendly Territory produce [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Writer Points.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE BUILDING: DIVAN (CARAVANSARY)[NEWLINE]The unique Divan is the Caravansary replacement for Afghanistan. Like the Caravansary, the Divan improves the range and [ICON_GOLD] Gold yield of land trade routes. However, it also produces [ICON_CULTURE] Culture whenever a new Tile is acquired, equal to the city's culture output. It also possesses a [ICON_GREAT_WORK] Great Work of Writing slot.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: JEZAILCHI (CAVALRY)[NEWLINE]The Jezailchi is a late-game Mounted Unit with a single-range attack, allowing it to take no damage when engaging in battle. This unit is much more effective when fighting in Hills, especially within your borders, although it is inherently weaker than the Cavalry that it replaces. They are unique to Afghanistan. Use Jezailchi to repel enemy invaders and protect your territory.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>