<GameData>
    <Language_en_US>
        <!-- First Greeting -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_FIRSTGREETING_1">
            <Text>I am Cetshwayo kaMpande, king of the Zulu. I believe we can forge a powerful alliance, as long as you give us the respect we deserve.</Text>
        </Row>

        <!-- Defeated -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_DEFEATED_1">
            <Text>I will be gracious in my defeat. Perhaps now there may be rest.</Text>
        </Row>

        <!-- Diplomacy: Wars, Denunciations, and DoF -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_ATTACKED_GENERIC_1">
            <Text>So war was unavoidable after all. Very well then, I shall not back down.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
            <Text>I believe both of our peoples have much to learn from each other. Would you like to make a public Declaration of Friendship?</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_DENOUNCE_1">
            <Text>You are a rank criminal, and I would be remiss not to warn the world of your wrongs. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_DOW_GENERIC_1">
            <Text>It has become clear that peace is no longer workable. Our conflicts must be settled with bloodshed.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
            <Text>Your expansion has come to threaten the rightful Zulu lands. If this continues, you may rest assured that I will take action.</Text>
        </Row>

        <!-- Greetings -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_1">
            <Text>I have no particular desire to engage in pleasantries with the enemy.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
            <Text>Well met. Please, come join me in the kraal.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
            <Text>Greetings. What business do you have today?</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
            <Text>Be quick with it.</Text>
        </Row>

        <!-- Misc -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
            <Text>You are infringing upon our land and driving away our cattle. I urge you to stop; this is the only warning you will receive.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_LETS_HEAR_IT_1">
            <Text>You have my attention.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_LOSEWAR_1">
            <Text>Although I mourn the result of the war, I cannot regret making peace.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
            <Text>No friendship between nations is complete without commerce. Do you care to make a trade?</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_NO_PEACE_1">
            <Text>We cannot be reconciled. It is not worth the effort to bother.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE">
            <Text>It is clear that we both have important claims on this land, but our claims need not be wholly at odds. An Open Borders agreement could allow us both to benefit.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_REPEAT_NO_1">
            <Text>Do not take me for a fool.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_RESPONSE_REQUEST_1">
            <Text>I do not like to ask for help, but in these troubled times it is unavoidable.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
            <Text>I am king in my own country, and must be treated as such. I shall not bear this disrespect.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
            <Text>I do not wage war frivolously. If we are to meet in battle, we must see it through to the end.</Text>
        </Row>
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_THP_CETSHWAYO_WINWAR_1">
            <Text>I hope this has made you realize that the Zulu are not to be trifled with.</Text>
        </Row>
    </Language_en_US>
</GameData>
