<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--The Ainu-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_LITE_AINU">
			<Text>Ainu Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_LITE_AINU_SHORT">
			<Text>The Ainu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILIZATION_LITE_AINU_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Ainu</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Civilopedias-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TITLE">
			<Text>Ainu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Ainu, and in historical Japanese texts Ezo/Emishi/Ebisu or Ainu, are a indigenous people of Japan (Hokkaido and formerly northeastern Honshu), and Russia (Sakhalin, the Kuril Islands, and formerly the Kamchatka Peninsula).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Terrain and Climate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The Ainu were distributed in the northern and central islands of Japan, from Sakhalin island in the north to the Kuril Islands and the island of Hokkaido and Northern Honshū, although some investigators place their former range as throughout Honshū. Others place them as far north as the southern tip of the Kamchatka Peninsula in what is now Cape Lopatka. Hokkaido is the most northerly of the four great land masses that make up Japan, and although separated from the mainland, Honshu, by a strait only a few miles wide, the island remains geologically and geographically distinct. Spiked with mountains, thick with forests, and never more than sparsely populated, it has a stark and wintry beauty that sets it apart from the more temperate landscapes to the south.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Origins</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The Ainu have often been considered to descend from the Jōmon people, who lived in Japan from the Jōmon period. One of their Yukar Upopo, or legends, tells that "The Ainu lived in this place a hundred thousand years before the Children of the Sun came". Recent research suggests that the historical Ainu culture originated in a merger of the Okhotsk culture with the Satsumon, one of the ancient archaeological cultures that are considered to have derived from the Jōmon period cultures of the Japanese Archipelago. Full-blooded Ainu, compared to people of Yamato descent, often have lighter skin and more body hair. Many early investigators proposed a Caucasian ancestry, although recent DNA tests have not shown any genetic similarity with modern Europeans. Genetic testing has shown the Ainu to belong mainly to Y-haplogroup D-M55. Y-DNA haplogroup D2 is found frequently throughout the Japanese Archipelago including Okinawa. The only places outside Japan in which Y-haplogroup D is common are Tibet in China and the Andaman Islands in the Indian Ocean. A recent reevaluation of cranial traits suggests that the Ainu resemble the Okhotsk more than they do the Jōmon. This agrees with the reference to the Ainu being a merger of Okhotsk and Satsumon referenced above.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Traditional Ainu Lifestyle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The Ainu formed a society of hunter-gatherers, living mainly by hunting and fishing, and the people followed a religion based on phenomena of nature. Traditional Ainu culture was quite different from Japanese culture. Never shaving after a certain age, the men had full beards and moustaches. Men and women alike cut their hair level with the shoulders at the sides of the head, trimmed semicircularly behind. The women tattooed their mouths, and sometimes the forearms. The mouth tattoos were started at a young age with a small spot on the upper lip, gradually increasing with size. The soot deposited on a pot hung over a fire of birch bark was used for color. Their traditional dress was a robe spun from the inner bark of the elm tree, called attusi or attush. Various styles were made, and consisted generally of a simple short robe with straight sleeves, which was folded around the body, and tied with a band about the waist. The sleeves ended at the wrist or forearm and the length generally was to the calves. Women also wore an undergarment of Japanese cloth. In winter, the skins of animals were worn, with leggings of deerskin and in Sakhalin, boots were made from the skin of dogs or salmon. Both sexes were fond of earrings, which are said to have been made of grapevine in former times, and also the bead necklaces called tamasay, which the women prized highly. The Ainu hunted from late autumn to early summer. The reasons for this were, among others, that in late autumn, plant gathering, salmon fishing and other activities of securing food came to an end, and hunters readily found game in fields and mountains in which plants had withered. A village possessed a hunting ground of its own or several villages used a joint hunting territory (iwor). Heavy penalties were imposed on any outsiders trespassing on such hunting grounds or joint hunting territory. The Ainu hunted bear, Ezo deer (a subspecies of sika deer), rabbit, fox, raccoon dog, and other animals. Ezo deer were a particularly important food resource for the Ainu as were salmon. They also hunted sea eagles such as white-tailed sea eagles, raven and other birds. The Ainu hunted eagles to obtain their tail feathers, which they used in trade with the Japanese. The Ainu hunted with arrows and spears with poison-coated points. They obtained the poison, called surku, from the roots and stalks of aconites. The Ainu were traditionally animists, believing that everything in nature has a kamuy (spirit or god) on the inside. The Ainu have no priests by profession; instead the village chief performs whatever religious ceremonies are necessary. Ceremonies are confined to making libations of sake, uttering prayers, and offering willow sticks with wooden shavings attached to them. A village was called a kotan in the Ainu language. Kotan were located in river basins and seashores where food was readily available, particularly in the basins of rivers through which salmon went upstream. A village consisted basically of a paternal clan. The average number of families was four to seven, rarely reaching more than ten. Cise or cisey (houses) in a kotan were made of cogon grasses, bamboo grass, barks, etc. The Ainu people had various types of marriage. A child was promised in marriage by arrangement between his or her parents and the parents of his or her betrothed or by a go-between. When the betrothed reached a marriageable age, they were told who their spouse was to be. There were also marriages based on mutual consent of both sexes. In some areas, when a daughter reached a marriageable age, her parents let her live in a small room called tunpu annexed to the southern wall of her house. The parents chose her spouse from men who visited her. The age of marriage was 17 to 18 years of age for men and 15 to 16 years of age for women, who were tattooed. At these ages, both sexes were regarded as adults. Children were raised almost naked until about the ages of four to five. Even when they wore clothes, they did not wear belts and left the front of their clothes open. Subsequently they wore bark clothes without patterns, such as attush, until coming of age. The functions of judgeship were not entrusted to chiefs; an indefinite number of a community's members sat in judgment upon its criminals. Capital punishment did not exist, nor did the community resort to imprisonment. Beating was considered a sufficient and final penalty. However, in the case of murder, the nose and ears of the culprit were cut off or the tendons of his feet severed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Early Contacts with Japanese</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_5">
			<Text>In 1264, Ainu invaded the land of Nivkh people controlled by the Yuan Dynasty of China, resulting in battles between Ainu and the Chinese. Active contact between the Wajin (the ethnic Japanese) and the Ainu of Ezochi (now known as Hokkaido) began in the 13th century. Hokkaido does not appear in Japanese chronicles until around 1450, and was not formally incorporated into greater Japan until 1869. As late as 1650, the island was known as “Ezo,” and was a distant frontier zone, only tenuously controlled from Edo (modern Tokyo). And while it seems always to have possessed a small population of Japanese hunters and merchants, Hokkaido was home to, and for the most part run by, a significantly larger group of indigenous tribes known collectively as the Ainu.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Tensions Between the Ainu and Japanese</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_6">
			<Text>It was only after 1600 that relations between the Ainu and the Japanese reached a tipping point, and Japan became distinctly the senior partner in both diplomacy and trade. The change coincided with momentous events in Honshu. The Tokugawa shogunate, established in 1603, restored peace, stability and unity to the country after more than a century of war and civil war; the new ruling family shifted the capital to Edo (now Tokyo), thoroughly reorganized the feudal system, and suppressed Christianity. The mid-1630s saw the introduction of the policy of sakoku–which may be roughly translated as “locking the country”–under which practically all trade with the outside world was prohibited, foreigners were expelled from Japan, and others were forbidden, on pain of death, from entering imperial territory. The Japanese were not permitted to leave, and trade with the outside world was permitted only through four “gateways.” One of these was Nagasaki, where Chinese vessels were cautiously admitted and the Dutch were permitted to unload a handful of vessels annually on an artificial island in the harbor. Another, on Tsushima, conducted business with Korea; a third was located in the Ryukyu Islands. The fourth gateway was the Japanese enclave on Hokkaido, where trade was permitted with Ainu-land. The Ainu, likewise, were objects of suspicion. They were typically shorter and stockier than most Japanese, and had considerably more body hair. Ainu men cultivated long beards, a most un-Japanese trait. They were also not disposed to yield to increasing pressure from the south. Many Ainu were subject to Japanese rule which led to violent Ainu revolts such as the Koshamain's Revolt in 1456 against Japanese influence and control on an island. There was fighting between the Ainu and the Japanese in 1456-57 (Koshamain’s Rebellion), from 1512 until 1515, and again in 1528-31 and 1643. In each case, the issue was trade. And each time, the Ainu lost. This growing imbalance of power accelerated after 1600. By then, the Japanese had firearms in the shape of matchlock muskets, which they had acquired from the Portuguese, while the Ainu still depended on spears and bows and arrows. Japan had also become a unified state at a time when the people of Hokkaido still lived in warring tribal groupings, lacking an economy large enough to support any “permanent political organization”–or, indeed, a standing army. The largest Ainu polity of the 17th century was only 300 people strong.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Increase in Japanese Involvement in Hokkaido: the Matsumae</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_7">
			<Text>The Tokugawa shogun’s authority, admittedly, was not absolute. Rather, it was exercised through several hundred daimyo–feudal lords who lived in castles, collected taxes and maintained order in their districts with the help of samurai. For the most part, the daimyo maintained a sort of semi-independence that became more entrenched the further from the capital they were based. Certainly Japan’s representatives in the northernmost parts of Honshu, the Matsumae clan, were reluctant to invite interference from Edo, and a missionary who visited their territory in 1618 was curtly informed that “Matsumae is not Japan.” Japan’s feudal system helped to shape the course of Shakushain’s revolt. Matsumae was the smallest and the weakest of all Japan’s lordships. It could muster only 80 samurai, and, uniquely among all the daimyo, lived by trade rather than agriculture. Matsumae imported the rice it needed from the south, and the Ainu were, thus, vital to its survival; the trade in hawks alone–sold on to other daimyo further to the south–accounted for half the clan’s annual revenues. It was the urgent need to make money that led Matsumae to carve out an enclave north of the Tsugaru Strait, which was ruled from Fukuyama Castle. The creation of this small sliver of Japan in Hokkaido was, in turn, the proximate cause of the Ainu rebellion, and had Shakushain confronted only Matsumae, it is possible that his people might have triumphed by sheer weight of numbers. As it was, however, the shogunate was unwilling to tolerate the possibility of military defeat. Two neighbouring daimyo were ordered to go the Matsumae’s aid, and it is thanks to the records kept by one of them that we have a tolerably independent account of what transpired on Hokkaido in the 1660s. During the Edo period (1601–1868) the Ainu became increasingly involved in trade with Japanese who controlled the northern portion of the island that is now called Hokkaido. The Tokugawa bakufu (feudal government) granted the Matsumae clan exclusive rights to trade with the Ainu in the northern part of the island. Later the Matsumae began to lease out trading-rights to Japanese merchants, and contact between Japanese and Ainu became more extensive. Throughout this period Ainu became increasingly dependent on goods imported by Japanese, and suffered from epidemic diseases such as smallpox. Although the increased contact brought by trade between the Japanese and the Ainu contributed to increased mutual understanding, sometimes it led to conflict, occasionally intensifying into violent Ainu revolts, of which the most important was Shakushain's Revolt (1669–1672), an Ainu rebellion against Japanese authority. Another large-scale revolt by Ainu against Japanese rule was the Menashi-Kunashir Battle in 1789. As late as the 1590s, Hokkaido’s natives had retained almost complete control over the resources of their island; they caught hawks, speared fish, shot deer and trapped bears, paddled their canoes to Japanese ports, and there chose the merchants to whom they were prepared to sell their salmon, furs and birds of prey. The trade was quite profitable. All this changed, though, in the 17th century. First gold was discovered on Hokkaido in 1631, leading to a rapid influx of Japanese miners and the establishment of mining camps in the island’s interior–the first time that any Japanese had settled there. These incomers were not policed by Matsumae, and behaved toward the Ainu as they pleased. Then, in 1644, the shogunate granted Matsumae a monopoly over all trade with Hokkaido. This was a catastrophic decision from the Ainu point of view, since–by dealing selectively with several daimyo–they had hitherto managed to keep the prices of their products high. Matsumae wasted no time in exploiting its new rights; after 1644, Ainu canoes were forbidden to call at Japanese ports. Instead, Matsumae merchants began setting up fortified trading bases on Hokkaido itself, from which they made take-it-or-leave-it offers to buy what they wanted. Some Ainu resisted, advocating a retreat to the interior and a return to their traditional way of life. But the lure of imported rice and metal was too much. Trade therefore continued on the new terms, and it was not long before the situation deteriorated further. Matsumae began netting the mouths of rivers, catching salmon before they could ascend to the spawning grounds where the Ainu speared them. The islanders were also angered to discover that Matsumae had unilaterally changed the exchange rate for their goods.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Meiji Period: Assimilation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_8">
			<Text>In the 18th century there were 80,000 Ainu. In 1868, there were about 15,000 Ainu in Hokkaido, 2,000 in Sakhalin, and around 100 in the Kuril Islands. Many Ainu were forced to work, essentially as slaves, for the ethnic Japanese, resulting in the breakup of families and the introduction of smallpox, measles, cholera and tuberculosis into their community. In 1869, the new Meiji government renamed Ezo as Hokkaido and unilaterally incorporated it into Japan. It banned the Ainu language, took Ainu land away, and prohibited salmon fishing and deer hunting. The beginning of the Meiji Restoration in 1868 proved a turning point for Ainu culture. The Japanese government introduced a variety of social, political and economic reforms in hope of modernizing the country in the Western style. One innovation involved the annexation of Hokkaido. In 1899 the Japanese government passed an act labelling the Ainu as "former aborigines", with the idea they would assimilate—this resulted in the Japanese government taking the land where the Ainu people lived and placing it from then on under Japanese control. Also at this time, the Ainu were granted automatic Japanese citizenship, effectively denying them the status of an indigenous group. The Ainu were becoming increasingly marginalized on their own land—over a period of only 36 years, the Ainu went from being a relatively isolated group of people to having their land, language, religion and customs assimilated into those of the Japanese. In addition to this, the land the Ainu lived on was distributed to the Japanese who had decided to move to Hokkaido, encouraged by the Japanese government of the Meiji era to take advantage of the island’s abundant natural resources, and to create and maintain farms in the model of Western industrial agriculture. While at the time the process was openly referred to as colonization, the notion was later reframed by Japanese elites to the currently common usage "kaitaku", which instead conveys a sense of opening up or reclamation of the Ainu lands. As well as this, factories such as flour mills and beer breweries and mining practices resulted in the creation of infrastructure such as roads and railway lines, during a development period that lasted until 1904. During this time the Ainu were forced to learn Japanese, required to adopt Japanese names, and ordered to cease religious practices such as animal sacrifice and the custom of tattooing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_9">
			<Text>Ainu in Russia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_9">
			<Text>As a result of the Treaty of Saint Petersburg (1875), the Kuril Islands - along with their Ainu inhabitants - came under Japanese administration. A total of 83 North Kuril Ainu arrived in Petropavlovsk-Kamchatsky on September 18, 1877 after they decided to remain under Russian rule. They refused the offer by Russian officials to move to new reservations in the Commander Islands. Finally, a deal was reached in 1881 and the Ainu decided to settle in the village of Yavin. In March 1881, the group left Petropavlovsk and started the journey towards Yavin on foot. Four months later they arrived at their new homes. Another village, Golygino, was founded later. Under Soviet rule, both the villages were forced to disband and residents were moved to the Russian-dominated Zaporozhye rural settlement in Ust-Bolsheretsky Raion. As a result of intermarriage, the three ethnic groups assimilated to form the Kamchadal community. The southern half of Sakhalin was acquired by Japan as a result of the Russo-Japanese War of 1904–05, but at the end of World War II in 1945, the Soviets declared war on Japan and took possession of the Kuril Islands and southern Sakhalin. The Ainu population, as previously Japanese subjects, were "repatriated" to Japan. During Tsarist times, the Ainu living in Russia were forbidden from identifying themselves as such, since Imperial Japanese officials claimed that all the regions inhabited by the Ainu in the past or present belonged to Japan. The terms "Kurile", "Kamchatka Kurile", etc., were used to identify the ethnic group. During Soviet times, people with Ainu surnames were sent to gulags and labor camps, as they were often mistaken for Japanese. As a result, large numbers of Ainu changed their surnames to Slavic ones. After World War II, most of the Ainu living in Sakhalin were deported to Japan. Of the 1,159 Ainu, only around 100 remained in Russia. Of those who remained, only the elderly were full-blooded Ainu. Others were either mixed race or married to ethnic Russians. To eradicate Ainu identity, Soviet authorities removed the ethnic group from the list of nationalities which could be mentioned in a Soviet passport. Due to this, children born after 1945 were not able to identify themselves as Ainu. In 1979 the USSR removed the term "Ainu" from the list of living ethnic groups of Russia, an act by which the government proclaimed that the Ainu as an ethnic group were extinct in its territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_10">
			<Text>Modern Period for Japanese Ainu: Recognization as a Minority People</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_10">
			<Text>The 1899 act mentioned above was replaced in 1997—until then the government had stated there were no ethnic minority groups. On May 8, 1997, the Japanese Diet passed the Ainu Culture Law and repealed the Ainu Protection Act—the 1899 law that had been the vehicle of Ainu oppression for almost one hundred years. It was not until June 6, 2008, that Japan formally recognised the Ainu as an indigenous group. On June 6, 2008 the Japanese Diet passed a bipartisan, non-binding resolution calling upon the government to recognize the Ainu people as indigenous to Japan, and urging an end to discrimination against the group. The resolution recognised the Ainu people as "an indigenous people with a distinct language, religion and culture". The government immediately followed with a statement acknowledging its recognition, stating, "The government would like to solemnly accept the historical fact that many Ainu were discriminated against and forced into poverty with the advancement of modernization, despite being legally equal to (Japanese) people." Intermarriage between Japanese and Ainu was actively promoted by the Ainu to lessen the chances of discrimination against their offspring. As a result, many Ainu are indistinguishable from their Japanese neighbors, but some Ainu-Japanese are interested in traditional Ainu culture. There are also many small towns in the southeastern or Hidaka region where ethnic Ainu live such as in Nibutani (Ainu: Niputay). Many live in Sambutsu especially, on the eastern coast. In 1966 the number of "pure" Ainu was about 300. The only Ainu speakers remaining (besides perhaps a few partial speakers) live solely in Japan. There, they are concentrated primarily on the southern and eastern coasts of the island of Hokkaido. Today, it is estimated that fewer than 100 speakers of the language remain, while other research places the number at fewer than 15 speakers. The language has been classified as “endangered”. In fact, no attempt to show a relationship with Ainu to any other language has gained wide acceptance, and Ainu is currently considered to be a language isolate. Ainu assimilated into mainstream Japanese society have adopted Buddhism with Shinto influences, while some northern Ainu are members of the Russian Orthodox Church. Most Hokkaido Ainu and some other Ainu are members of an umbrella group called the Hokkaido Utari Association. It was originally controlled by the government to speed Ainu assimilation and integration into the Japanese nation-state. It now is run exclusively by Ainu and operates mostly independently of the government. The Ainu Party was founded on January 21, 2012, after a group of Ainu activists in Hokkaido announced the formation of a political party for the Ainu on October 30, 2011. Their aim is to contribute to the realization of a multicultural and multiethnic society in Japan, along with rights for the Ainu. The Ainu have historically suffered from economic and social discrimination throughout Japan that continues to this day. The Japanese Government as well as people since contact with the Ainu, have in large part regarded them as a dirty, backwards and a primitive people. The majority of Ainu were forced to be petty laborers during the Meji Restoration, which saw the introduction of Hokkaido into the Japanese Empire and the privatization of traditional Ainu lands. The Japanese government during the 19th and 20th centuries denied the rights of the Ainu to their traditional cultural practices, most notably the right to speak their language, as well as their right to hunt and gather. These policies were designed to fully integrate the Ainu into Japanese society with the cost of erasing Ainu culture and identity. The Ainu’s position as manual laborers and their forced integration into larger Japanese society have led to discriminatory practices by the Japanese government that can still be felt today. This discrimination and negative stereotypes assigned to the Ainu have manifested in the Ainu’s lower levels of education, income levels and participation in the economy as compared to their ethnically Japanese counterparts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_HEADING_11">
			<Text>Modern Period for the Russian Ainu: Invisibility</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_TEXT_11">
			<Text>As of 2015 the North Kuril Ainu of Zaporozhye form the largest Ainu subgroup in Russia. The Nakamura clan (South Kuril Ainu on their paternal side), the smallest group, numbers just 6 people residing in Petropavlovsk. On Sakhalin island a few dozen people identify themselves as Sakhalin Ainu, but many more with partial Ainu ancestry do not acknowledge it. Most of the 888 Japanese people living in Russia (2010 Census) are of mixed Japanese-Ainu ancestry, although they do not acknowledge it. Similarly, no one identifies themselves as Amur Valley Ainu, although people with partial descent live in Khabarovsk. There is no evidence of living descendants of the Kamchatka Ainu. In the 2010 Census of Russia, close to 100 people tried to register themselves as ethnic Ainu in the village, but the governing council of Kamchatka Krai rejected their claim and enrolled them as ethnic Kamchadal. In 2011, the leader of the Ainu community in Kamchatka, Alexei Vladimirovich Nakamura, requested that Vladimir Ilyukhin (Governor of Kamchatka) and Boris Nevzorov (Chairman of the State Duma) include the Ainu in the central list of the Indigenous small-numbered peoples of the North, Siberia and the Far East. This request was also turned down. The Ainu have emphasized that they were the natives of the Kuril Islands and that the Japanese and Russians were both invaders. In 2004, the small Ainu community living in Russia in Kamchatka Krai wrote a letter to Vladimir Putin, urging him to reconsider any move to award the Southern Kuril Islands to Japan. In the letter they blamed both the Japanese, the Tsarist Russians and the Soviets for crimes against the Ainu such as killings and assimilation, and also urged him to recognize the Japanese genocide against the Ainu people, which was turned down by Putin. As of 2012 both the Kurile Ainu and Kurile Kamchadal ethnic groups lack the fishing and hunting rights which the Russian government grants to the indigenous tribal communities of the far north.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_FACTOID_HEADING">
			<Text>Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVLOPEDIA_LITE_AINU_FACTOID_TEXT">
			<Text>...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Matagi Archer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LITE_AINU_MATAGI">
			<Text>Matagi Archer</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LITE_AINU_MATAGI_HELP">
			<Text>Unique Ainu Archer. Weaker, but faster. Provides [ICON_FOOD] Food and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture when stationed on unimproved worked animal resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LITE_AINU_MATAGI_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Matagi Archer is an Archer replacement unique to the Ainu. It is Weaker, but faster, and when stationed on an unimproved Animal Resource, it generates +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food and +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture to the nearest Ainu City.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LITE_AINU_MATAGI_TEXT">
			<Text>The Matagi are traditional winter hunters of the Tohoku region of northern Japan, most famously today in the Shirakami-Sanchi forest between Akita and Aomori. They hunt deer and bear, and their culture has much in common with the bear cult of the Ainu. They live in small hamlets of the mountain beech forests of Tohoku and engage in agriculture during the planting and harvest season. In the winter and early spring, they form hunting bands that spend weeks at a time in the forest. With the introduction of guns in the 20th century, the need for group hunting for bear has diminished, leading to a decline in Matagi culture. Attested since the Medieval period, the Matagi have now come into conflict with environmentalists now that the forest has been partly cleared. Their specialized hunting vocabulary contains Ainu words. Indeed, the word “matagi” itself may be of Ainu origin, from matangi or matangitono “man of winter, hunter”.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Heper Set-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITE_AINU_HEPER_SET">
			<Text>Heper Set</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITE_AINU_HEPER_SET_TEXT">
			<Text>A heper set is or was a cage for young bears used by the Ainu people. These bears were to be used in a ritual called the Iomante. The cub was fed human food from a carved wooden platter. When the cub reaches 2-3 years of age, the cub was taken to the alter and then sacrificed. The villagers will shoot it with both normal and ceremonial arrows, make offereings, dance, and pour wine on top of the cub corpse. The words of sending off for the bear god are then recited. This festivity lasts for three days and three nights to properly return the bear god to his home.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITE_AINU_HEPER_SET_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Heper Set increases the [ICON_FOOD] Food intake of a City as the regular Granary, speeding up the City's growth, but additionally provides [ICON_PEACE] Faith from all animal resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITE_AINU_HEPER_SET_HELP">
			<Text>Besides the effects of the Granary it replaces, the Heper Set provides +1 [ICON_PEACE] Faith on all animal Resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Dummy building-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITE_AINU_DUMMY">
			<Text>LITE: Ainu: Dummy building</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LITE_AINU_DUMMY_HELP">
			<Text>Dummy building for the Ainu civilization</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Shakushain-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_DESC">
			<Text>Shakushain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_LIVED">
			<Text>ca. 1650s</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_NAME">
			<Text>Shakushain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of the Ainu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Leader of the Ainu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Shakushain was an Ainu chieftain who led a rebellion against Japanese authority on Hokkaido between 1669 and 1672. The revolt was led against the Matsumae clan, who represented Japanese trading and governmental interests in the area of Hokkaido controlled by the Japanese.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Pre-Rebellion: Tensions between Two Chieftains</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Shakushain would come into prominence during a time of turmoil for some of the Hokkaido Ainu. By the 1650s, tribes along Hokkaido’s eastern coast, where most of Matsumae’s trading forts were located, had begun to turn upon one another. This sporadic warfare encouraged dozens of small communities scattered along the banks of Hokkaido’s rivers to coalesce. By 1660 there were several powerful chieftains on the island, and of these, the two greatest were Onibishi (who led a confederation known as the Hae) and Shakushain, who as early as 1653 ruled over the Shibuchari. The two men lived in villages only eight miles apart, and there had been rivalry between them for years; Onibishi’s father had fought with Shakushain’s, and Shakushain’s immediate predecessor had been killed by Onibishi. Shakushain’s tribe was the larger, but gold had been found on Onibishi’s land, and Matsumae thus favored the Hae. Little is known of Shakushain himself. The one Japanese eyewitness to describe him wrote that he was “about 80 years old, and a really big man, about the size of three ordinary men.” But most historians of the period trace the origins of his revolt to sporadic conflict between the Hae Ainu and the Shibuchari that began as early as 1648 and came to a head in 1666, when Shakushain’s tribe committed the unforgivable sin of refusing to provide a cub for sacrifice by the Hae during the annual bear festival. The plea that Onibishi made on this occasion reflects decades of gradually worsening economic prospects: “My land is very unhappy, as we have not been able to capture even one bear.”</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Conflict Between Ainu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The increasing scarcity of resources probably explains the determination of both Ainu tribes to prevent poaching on their territory, and this escalated the conflict. In the summer of 1667, a Hae Ainu hunter related to Onibishi ventured onto Shakushain’s land and trapped a valuable crane. When the trespass was discovered, the hunter was killed, and when Onibishi demanded 300 tsugunai (compensatory gifts), Shakushain sent a miserly 11. The result was what amounted to a blood feud. The Shibuchari raided their neighbors, killing two of Onibishi’s brothers; soon, Onibishi and his remaining men were surrounded in a Japanese mining camp. Shakushain gave the order to attack, and Onibishi was killed and the camp burned to the ground. The Hae retaliated in kind, but in July 1668 their main fortress fell and the Ainu’s civil war was over. Shakushain must have realized that by attacking a Matsumae mining camp he was in effect declaring war on Japan, but his defeat of the Hae opened up fresh possibilities. The Shibuchari followed up their victory by assembling a coalition of other Ainu tribes that they hoped would be strong enough to resist the inevitable counterattack. Many Ainu were feeling so desperate by the late 1660s that the members of 19 eastern tribes were willing to set aside their differences and form a formidable coalition that probably mustered at least 3,000 fighting men.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Challenging the Japanese: Poison Arrows Meet Samurai Armor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_4">
			<Text>What set Shakushain apart from other Ainu rebels is what he did with the force he had assembled. Ainu resistance hitherto had been almost entirely defensive; the odd arrogant merchant might be ambushed and killed, but the Ainu seem to have recognized the likely futility of launching an all-out attack on the Japanese. In June 1669, however, Shakushain decided to ignore the lessons of history. He ordered an attack on all the isolated mining camps, Matsumae trading forts and Japanese merchant ships in Hokkaido–and it says much for the Ainu’s improving organization, and his own standing as a leader, that the result was a well coordinated assault that rained down destruction all along Hokkaido’s coasts. More than 270 Japanese died in the attacks, and 19 merchant ships were destroyed. Half the coast was devastated, and only about 20 of the Japanese living outside Matsumae’s enclave on Hokkaido survived the massacres. Once word got out, officials at Fukuyama Castle were faced with general panic among the merchants and civilians living in the enclave. It was only at this point that Matsumae seems to have realized that things were getting out of hand in Ainu-land. The destruction of the mining camp was not only a blow to trade and a direct challenge to the clan’s assumed supremacy in Hokkaido; the mustering of a substantial Ainu army also represented a genuine threat to its security. That Matsumae was forced–albeit reluctantly–to report the disasters of 1669 to Edo and accept help from the neighboring daimyo seems proof that the position was considered serious. The first preparations for war, moreover, show how uncertain the Japanese were of their position; a good deal of effort was plowed into the construction of defensive positions, and there seems to have been no thought yet of taking the offensive. Meanwhile, Shakushain did his best to retain the initiative. An Ainu army advanced south and covered about half the distance to Fukuyama Castle before it encountered an advance guard of Japanese troops near Etomo. A few days later the two forces met further south, at Kunnui, but poor weather and high rivers dented the Ainu assault. When Shakushain’s men came under sustained musket fire from the Matsumae’s samurai, they were forced to retreat. This skirmish proved to be the main engagement of the war. The Japanese army was not large; at first it was only 80 strong, and even after reinforcements arrived from other daimyo in northern Honshu it numbered no more than 700. In terms of arms and armor, though, Matsumae’s advantage was decisive. As “peasants,” the Ainu had no right to bear arms in feudal Japan. Their most effective weapons were aconite-tipped poison arrows, which they made by dipping arrowheads first in fir resin and then in a bowl of dried, ground wolfsbane. These arrows had long caused consternation among the Japanese, who expended significant effort, unsuccessfully, to uncover the secret of their manufacture. In action, however, they proved ineffective, since the Ainu’s under-powered bows were unable to penetrate samurai armor, or even the cotton-wadded jackets worn by ordinary foot-soldiers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_5">
			<Text>End of the Rebellion and Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_5">
			<Text>With Shakushain now in retreat, the revolt was ended a month or so later by the arrival of substantial reinforcements from Honshu. Counterattacks burned a large number of Ainu forts and canoes, and by October, Shakushain had been surrounded; at the end of that month, he surrendered. The Ainu threat was ended shortly thereafter when, at a drinking party held to celebrate peace, an old Matsumae samurai named Sato Ganza’emon arranged the murder of the unarmed Shakushain and three other Ainu generals. “Being unable to fight back,” an eyewitness reported, “Shakushain arose gave a big glare in all directions, shouting loudly, ‘Ganza’emon, you deceived me! What a dirty trick you pulled.’ squatted on the ground like a statue. Keeping this posture, Shakushain was killed without moving his hands.” The Shibuchari’s main fortress was then burned down. It is believed that the Japanese murdered the Ainu leader because they were swayed by fantastic rumors that the Ainu had established an alliance with a much more dangerous “barbarian” kingdom, the Tatars of Orankai, who wielded power in southern Manchuria; for a while there seemed to be a threat that they and the Jurchens might combine forces and lead an invasion of Japan that would succeed where Kublai Khan had failed four centuries earlier. For Edo, this must have seemed no empty threat; another northern people, the Manchus, had only recently completed their conquest of China, overthrowing the Ming dynasty.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Aftermath of Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Even so, it took three years for Matsumae to complete the pacification of Ainu-land, and although the outcome was scarcely in doubt, it was nonetheless a compromise. The peace treaty bound the Ainu to swear allegiance to Matsumae and to trade solely with the Japanese. There was a considerable expansion in the Japanese presence in the far north, and soon 60 new Matsumae trading posts were operating in Hokkaido, driving such hard bargains that several Ainu settlements were reported to be on the verge of starvation. On the other hand, the Ainu retained formal autonomy through most of their island, and even won some important concessions on the rice-fish exchange rate that had sparked the uprising in the first place. Certainly relations between Japan and Ainu-land shifted fundamentally after 1669. Thenceforth, while the Ainu retained much of their old de facto independence, it was rendered increasingly worthless by the de jure peace settlement they had signed. The Ainu were compelled to sell what they had–both goods and labor–at prices determined by the Japanese. Their canoes no longer appeared in Honshu ports, and those unable to support themselves by hunting were compelled to work as what amounted to forced labor in fish-processing plants on the mainland at about a seventh of the rate paid to Japanese.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Judgment of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_TEXT_7">
			<Text>Shakushain was a charismatic leader who proved able to bridge regional differences among Ainu communities, threatening to unite them against the Japanese intrusion from the south. The only other comparable large-scale revolt by Ainu against Japanese rule was the Menashi-Kunashir Battle of 1789. An earlier rebellion along the same lines was Koshamain’s Revolt in 1456. Though his revolt was a failure and the Japanese influx onto their island accelerated, Shakushain still inspires new generations of Ainu nationalists.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_FACTOID_HEADING">
			<Text>Ainu Factoids</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_FACTOID_TEXT">
			<Text>...</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Responses-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_FIRST_GREETING_1">
			<Text>Welcome to the lands of my people. If you respect our traditions you are free to stay.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_FIRST_GREETING_2">
			<Text>Careful, stranger. These lands of ours are unforgiving to those who don't respect their Gods.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>We fought with all our strength, but alas, it was not enough.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>Your kind has nothing to do in these lands. Begone!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>You will regret this day when you become history.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_LITE_SHAKUSHAIN_INSULT_LEADER_1">
			<Text>Even the most rotten meat is more pleasant than you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Trait-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LITE_IOMANTE_SHORT">
			<Text>Iomante</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LITE_IOMANTE_DESC">
			<Text>Cities on or adjacent to Tundra or Snow will produce a unique [ICON_RES_LITE_AINU_BEAR] Bear luxury Resource. When Ainu Military Units are killed or captured, their essence is returned to the [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital or nearest City through Yields.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Resource-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_LITE_AINU_BEAR">
			<Text>Bear</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_RESOURCE_LITE_AINU_BEAR_TEXT">
			<Text>The Ainu people call the bear “kamui” in their language, which translates to mean “god”. The bear is the head of the gods. They willingly and thankfully ate the bear as they believed that the disguise (the flesh and fur) of any god was a gift to the home that the god chose to visit. To return a god back to his country, the people would sacrifice and eat the animal, sending the god’s spirit away with civility. This ritual is called Omante. For a bear cub, a different ritural called Iomante was performed. The cub was fed human food from a carved wooden platter. When the cub reaches 2-3 years of age, the cub was taken to the alter and then sacrificed. The villagers will shoot it with both normal and ceremonial arrows, make offereings, dance, and pour wine on top of the cub corpse. The words of sending off for the bear god are then recited. This festivity lasts for three days and three nights to properly return the bear god to his home.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--DOM-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_LITE_AINU_TEXT">
			<Text>Greetings, fair and proud chief Shakushain. Your people, the Ainu, come from the island of Hokkaido. her cold forests and seas kept out invaders for centuries while they allowed your people to live and prosper.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]You rose to fame in the 17th centuries when you led a revolt against the Yamato opressors from the Japanese mainland. You were feared by them as a strong, yet charismatic leader, who threatened to unite various tribes of the Ainu against the Japanese. In the end your people settled for peace, after which they were betrayed by the Japanese invaders.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh great chief, Shakushain. Your people are calling your name again, hoping for a strong leader. Can you build a Civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spy Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_0">
			<Text>Haukase</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_1">
			<Text>Onibishi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_2">
			<Text>Sentaiin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_3">
			<Text>Kamokutain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_4">
			<Text>Rashaukain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_5">
			<Text>Kanrinka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_6">
			<Text>Jasinoske</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_7">
			<Text>Saushi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_8">
			<Text>Kinkiriu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_LITE_AINU_9">
			<Text>Wajima</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_1">
			<Text>Sat Poro Pet</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_2">
			<Text>Shinhidaka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_3">
			<Text>Shiraoi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_4">
			<Text>Usukeshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_5">
			<Text>Yam Wakkanay</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_6">
			<Text>Mo Ruerani</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_7">
			<Text>Iskarun</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_8">
			<Text>Rurumoppe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_9">
			<Text>Paramushir</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_10">
			<Text>Simushir</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_11">
			<Text>Urup</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_12">
			<Text>Iturup</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_13">
			<Text>Kunashir</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_14">
			<Text>Yoichi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_15">
			<Text>Etomo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_16">
			<Text>Iwanai</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_17">
			<Text>Akkeshi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_18">
			<Text>Shiranushi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_19">
			<Text>Nayoro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_20">
			<Text>Boluohe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_21">
			<Text>Turupan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_22">
			<Text>Kushunkotan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_23">
			<Text>Shibuchari</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_24">
			<Text>Hae</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_25">
			<Text>Saru</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_26">
			<Text>Mitsuishi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_27">
			<Text>Urakawa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_28">
			<Text>Mukuchi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_LITE_AINU_29">
			<Text>Shipe Ichan</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>