<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 4/30/2021 1:37:00 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_CHAD_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Chadian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_CHAD_DESC">
			<Text>Chadian Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_SAS_CHAD_TEXT">
			<Text>We salute you, President Idriss Déby, great Marshal of Chad! You began your career in the military, rising through the ranks as you destroyed pro-Libyan forces throughout Chad before ousting the Libyans themselves in the Toyota War, leading your forces to supreme victory at the battle of Maaten al-Sarra. However, as his power crumbled, then-President Habré accused you of plotting a coup, causing you to flee the country as he began a terrible campaign of reprisals against people of your Zaghawa ethnicity. In a poetic turnabout, it was none other than Muammar Gaddafi himself who would welcome you in exile, and gave you the support needed to march into N'Djamena and oust Habré once and for all. Assuming the Presidency yourself, you worked tirelessly to try and bring peace to Chad, and were re-elected every 5 years for a total of 31 years in power, until your untimely death in 2021. Visiting your soldiers on the very frontlines of the fight against rebels, you were fatally wounded by gunfire just days after winning your 6th term.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Oh Marshal, Chad needs your strong leadership once again, to fight for her rightful place in the harsh sands of the Sahel. Will your enemies be crushed beneath the wheels of your Toyotas? Or can you master diplomacy to bring peace to a weary Chad? Will you build a civilization to stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_SAS_CHAD_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Chad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_CHAD_TITLE">
			<Text>Chad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_CHAD_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_CHAD_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Chad, officially known as the Republic of Chad, is a landlocked country in north-central Africa. It is bordered by Libya to the north, Sudan to the east, the Central African Republic to the south, Cameroon to the south-west, Nigeria to the southwest (at Lake Chad), and Niger to the west. Chad has several regions: a desert zone in the north, an arid Sahelian belt in the centre and a more fertile Sudanian Savanna zone in the south. Lake Chad, after which the country is named, is the second-largest wetland in Africa. The capital N'Djamena is the largest city. Chad's official languages are Arabic and French. It is home to over 200 different ethnic and linguistic groups. Islam (52%) and Christianity (44%) are the main religions practiced in Chad.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Beginning in the 7th millennium BC, human populations moved into the Chadian basin in great numbers. By the end of the 1st millennium AD, a series of states and empires had risen and fallen in Chad's Sahelian strip, each focused on controlling the trans-Saharan trade routes that passed through the region. France conquered the territory by 1920 and incorporated it as part of French Equatorial Africa.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In 1960, Chad obtained independence under the leadership of François Tombalbaye. Resentment towards his policies in the Muslim north culminated in the eruption of a long-lasting civil war in 1965. In 1979 the rebels conquered the capital and put an end to the South's hegemony. But, the rebel commanders fought amongst themselves until Hissène Habré defeated his rivals. The Chadian–Libyan conflict erupted in 1978 by the Libyan invasion which stopped in 1987 with a French military intervention (Operation Épervier). Hissène Habré was overthrown in turn in 1990 by his general Idriss Déby. With French support, a modernization of the Chad National Army was initiated in 1991. Since 2003 the Darfur crisis in Sudan has spilt over the border and destabilised the nation. Poor already, the nation and people struggled to accommodate the hundreds of thousands of Sudanese refugees who live in and around camps in eastern Chad. While many political parties are active, power lies firmly in the hands of the ruling party, the Patriotic Salvation Movement, formerly led by President Déby, whose multi-decade rule was described as authoritarian. Chad remains plagued by political violence and recurrent attempted coups d'état. It is a least developed country, ranking among the lowest in the Human Development Index. Chad is one of the poorest and most corrupt countries in the world; most of its inhabitants live in poverty as subsistence herders and farmers. Since 2003 crude oil has become the country's primary source of export earnings, superseding the traditional cotton industry. Chad has a poor human rights record, with frequent abuses such as arbitrary imprisonment, extrajudicial killings, and limits on civil liberties by both security forces and armed militias.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In April 2021, President Déby was killed by FACT rebels. The transitional military council, led by interim president Mahamat Idriss Déby, son of the former president, has assumed control of government.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Leader-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_SAS_DEBY">
			<Text>Idriss Déby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Idriss Déby Itno was a Chadian politician and military officer, and head of the ruling Patriotic Salvation Movement, who was the president of Chad from 1990 until his death at the hands of militant forces when commanding troops on the front in 2021. Déby was a member of the Bidayat clan of the Zaghawa ethnic group. He took power by leading a rebellion against President Hissène Habré in December 1990 and survived various rebellions and coup attempts against his own rule. Déby won elections in 1996 and 2001, and after term limits were eliminated he won again in 2006, 2011, 2016, and 2021. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life and Military Career</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Déby was born on 18 June 1952, in the village of Berdoba, approximately 190 kilometers from Fada in northern Chad. His father was a herdsman of the Bidayat clan of the Zaghawa community. After attending the Qur'anic School in Tiné, Déby studied at the École Française in Fada and at the Franco-Arab school in Abéché. He also attended the Lycée Jacques Moudeina in Bongor and held a bachelor's degree in science.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After finishing school, he entered the Officers' School in N'Djamena. From there he was sent to France for training, returning to Chad in 1976 with a professional pilot certificate. He remained loyal to the army and President Félix Malloum even after Chad's central authority crumbled in 1979. He returned from France in February 1979 and found Chad had become a battleground for many armed groups. Déby tied his fortunes to those of Hissène Habré, one of the chief Chadian warlords. A year after Habré became president in 1982, Déby was made commander-in-chief of the army.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]He distinguished himself in 1984 by destroying pro-Libyan forces in eastern Chad. In 1985, Habré sent him to Paris to follow a course at the École de Guerre and upon his return in 1986, he was made chief military advisor to the president. In 1987, he confronted Libyan forces on the field, with the help of France in the so-called "Toyota War", adopting tactics that inflicted heavy losses on enemy forces. During the war, he also led a raid on Maaten al-Sarra Air Base in Kufrah, in Libyan territory. A rift emerged in 1989 between Habré and Déby over the increasing power of the Presidential Guard.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]According to Human Rights Watch, Habré was found responsible for "widespread political killings, systematic torture, and thousands of arbitrary arrests", as well as ethnic purges when it was perceived that group leaders could pose a threat to his rule, including many of Déby's Zaghawa ethnic group who supported the government. Increasingly paranoid, Habré accused Déby, minister of the interior Mahamat Itno, and commander in chief of the Chadian army Hassan Djamous of preparing a coup d'état. Déby fled first to Darfur, then to Libya, where he was welcomed by Muammar Gaddafi in Tripoli. Itno and Djamous were arrested and killed. Since all three were ethnic Zaghawa, Habré started a targeted campaign against the group which saw hundreds seized, tortured, and imprisoned. Dozens died in detention or were summarily executed. In 2016, Habré was convicted of war crimes by a specially created international tribunal in Senegal. Déby gave the Libyans detailed information about CIA operations in Chad. Gaddafi offered Déby military aid to seize power in Chad in exchange for Libyan prisoners of war.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Déby relocated to Sudan in 1989 and formed the Patriotic Salvation Movement, an insurgent group, supported by Libya and Sudan, which started operations against Habré, and on 2 December 1990 Déby's troops marched unopposed into N'Djamena in a successful coup, ousting Habré. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Early Presidency</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_TEXT_3">
			<Text>After three months of the provisional government, on 28 February 1991, a charter was approved for Chad with Déby as president. During the following two years, Déby faced a series of coup attempts as government forces clashed with pro-Habré rebel groups, such as the Movement for Democracy and Development (MDD). Seeking to quell dissent, in 1993 Chad legalized political parties and held a National Conference which resulted in the gathering of 750 delegates, the government, trade unions, and the army to discuss the establishment of a pluralist democracy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, unrest continued. The Comité de Sursaut National pour la Paix et la Démocratie (CSNPD), led by Lt. Moise Kette, and other southern groups sought to prevent the Déby government from exploiting oil in the Doba Basin and started a rebellion that left hundreds dead. A peace agreement was reached in 1994, but it broke down soon thereafter. Two new groups, the Armed Forces for the Federal Republic (FARF) led by former Kette ally Laokein Barde, and the Democratic Front for Renewal (FDR), and a reformulated MDD clashed with government forces from 1994 to 1995.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Déby, in the mid-1990s, gradually restored basic functions of government and entered into agreements with the World Bank and IMF to carry out substantial economic reforms. A new constitution was approved by referendum in March 1996, followed by a presidential election in June. Déby fell short of a majority; he was then elected president in the second round of votes held in July, with 69% of the vote.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Déby was re-elected in the May 2001 presidential election, winning in the first round with 63.17% of the vote, according to official results. A civil war between Christians and Muslims erupted in 2005, accompanied by tensions with Sudan. An attempted coup d'état, involving the shooting down of Déby's plane, was foiled in March 2006. In mid-April 2006, there was fighting with rebels at N'Djaména, although the fighting soon subsided with government forces still in control of the capital. Déby subsequently broke ties with Sudan, accusing it of backing the rebels, and said that the May 2006 election would still take place. Deby was sworn in for another term in office on 8 August 2006.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After Déby's re-election, several rebel groups broke apart. Déby was in Abéché from 11 to 21 September 2006, flying in a helicopter to personally oversee attacks on Rally of Democratic Forces rebels.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The rebellion in the east continued, and rebels reached N'Djamena on 2 February 2008, with fighting occurring inside the city. After days of fighting, the government remained in control of N'Djamena. Speaking at a press conference on 6 February, Déby said that his forces had defeated the rebels, whom he described as "mercenaries directed by Sudan", and that his forces were in "total control" of the city as well as the whole country. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Later Presidency and Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Because of Chad's strategic position in West Africa, Déby sent troops or played a key mediating role in tackling multiple regional crises, such as Darfur, the Central African Republic (CAR), Mali, as well as the fight against Boko Haram. Chad’s recent history, under Déby's leadership, has been characterized as having been rife with endemic corruption and a deeply entrenched patronage system that permeated society, according to Transparency International. The recent exploitation of oil has fueled corruption, as revenues have been misused by the government to strengthen its armed forces and reward its cronies, which contributes to the undermining of the country’s governance system. In 2006, Chad was placed at the top of the list of the world's most corrupt nations by Forbes magazine. In 2012, Déby launched a nationwide anticorruption campaign called Operation Cobra, which reportedly recovered some $50 million in embezzled funds. Nongovernmental organizations say, however, that Déby has used such initiatives to punish rivals and reward cronies. As of 2016, Transparency International ranked Chad 147 out of 168 nations on its corruption index.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In January 2016, Déby succeeded Zimbabwe's Robert Mugabe to become the chairman of the African Union for a one-year term. Upon his inauguration, Déby told presidents that conflicts around the continent had to end "Through diplomacy or by force... We must put an end to these tragedies of our time. We cannot make progress and talk of development if part of our body is sick. We should be the main actors in the search for solution to Africa's crises". One of Déby's first priorities was to accelerate the fight against Boko Haram. On 4 March, the African Union agreed to expand the Multinational Joint Task Force (MNJTF) to 10,000 troops. In January 2019, Déby and Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced the resumption of diplomatic relations between Chad and Israel. Netanyahu described his visit to Chad as "part of the revolution we are having in the Arab and Muslim world."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In February 2021, Déby annouced Chad would send 1,200 soldiers alongside French troops to the Sahel border between Niger, Mali, and Burkina Faso, to combat al-Qaeda linked groups. In the 2021 presidential election, Déby won his sixth term as president, when results were announced on 19 April, with 79.32% of the votes. Instead of giving a victory speech, Déby went to visit the Chadian soldiers on the frontlines fighting the northern rebel incursion by the Front for Change and Concord in Chad (abbreviated FACT in French). He was said to have been mortally wounded by gunfire in the village of Mele, near the town of Nokou, on Sunday, 18 April, and was flown to the capital, where he died on 20 April, at the age of 68. The Chadian Parliament and Government were both dissolved upon his death and a Transitional Military Council was formed in its place with his son Mahamat Déby Itno as chairman. In addition, the Constitution of Chad was suspended and replaced by a new charter. Déby's funeral took place on 23 April 2021. On that day, thousands gathered in the streets of N'Djamena to pay their respects to Déby. French President Emmanuel Macron and Guinean President Alpha Condé, as well as several other African leaders, attended the funeral.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_LIVED">
			<Text>1952 - 2021 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_NAME">
			<Text>Idriss Déby</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Chad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_TITLES_1">
			<Text>President</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_SAS_DEBY_TITLES_2">
			<Text>Marshal</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Trait-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_OASISSAHEL_SHORT">
			<Text>Oasis Of The Sahel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_OASISSAHEL">
			<Text>Discovering Technologies which provide a Trade Route Slot increases the [ICON_CITIZEN] Population of all cities, particularly cities receiving Trade Routes or in Desert. +1 [ICON_FOOD] Food from Lakes and Oases.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_FAP">
			<Text>Desert Blitz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_SAS_FAP_HELP">
			<Text>Moves at double speed through Desert tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Technical-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_TECHNICAL">
			<Text>Technical</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_TECHNICAL_HELP">
			<Text>Replacing the Anti-Tank Gun for Chad, the Technical possesses a 2-tile Ranged attack with Indirect Fire, and moves significantly faster (4 [ICON_MOVES] vs 2) than the unit it replaces. Additionally, friendly units that start their turn adjacent to a Technical receive +1 [ICON_MOVES] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_TECHNICAL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Unique Anti-Tank Gun for Chad with a Ranged attack and increased mobility, that also increases the movement of adjacent friendly units. Use them to hit and run high-value enemy targets, especially Tanks!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_TECHNICAL_TEXT">
			<Text>A technical, in professional military parlance often called a non-standard tactical vehicle (NSTV), is a light improvised fighting vehicle, typically an open-backed civilian pickup truck or four-wheel drive vehicle mounting a machine gun, anti-aircraft gun, rotary cannon, anti-tank weapon, anti-tank gun, ATGM, mortar, multiple rocket launcher, recoilless rifle or other support weapon, somewhat like a light military gun truck or potentially even a self-propelled gun. In 1987, Chadian troops equipped with technicals drove the heavily mechanized Libyan army from the Aozou Strip. The vehicles were instrumental in the victory at the Battle of Fada, and were driven over 150 km (93 mi) into Libya to raid military bases. It was discovered that these light vehicles could ride through anti-tank minefields without detonating the mines when driven at speeds over 100 km/h. The vehicles had become so famous that, in 1984, Time dubbed early stages of the conflict the "Great Toyota War". The Toyota War was unusual in that the force equipped with improvised vehicles prevailed over the force equipped with purpose-built fighting vehicles. MILAN anti-tank guided missiles provided by France were key to the Chadian success, while the Libyan forces were poorly deployed and organized. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!--FAP-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_FAP">
			<Text>FAP</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_FAP_HELP">
			<Text>Chadian Infantry replacement that moves at double speed through Desert tiles and possesses the Heavy Charge promotion, forcing enemies to retreat or take extra damage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SAS_FAP_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Chadian Infantry replacement that moves at double speed through Desert tiles and possesses the Heavy Charge promotion, forcing enemies to retreat or take extra damage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_SAS_FAP_TEXT">
			<Text>The Forces Armées Populaires (People's Armed Forces, or FAP) was a Chadian insurgent group composed of followers of Goukouni Oueddei after the schism with Hissène Habré in 1976. With an ethnic base in the Teda clan of the Toubou from the Tibesti area of northern Chad, the force was armed by Libya and formed the largest component of the Transitional Government of National Unity (GUNT) coalition army opposing Habré. However, FAP troops rebelled against their Libyan allies in the latter part of 1986. Many of them were subsequently integrated into the national army, the Chadian National Armed Forces (FANT), and participated in the 1987 Toyota War, helping to drive Libya out of Chadian territory. </Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_9">
			<Text>Hassan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_8">
			<Text>Mahamat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_7">
			<Text>Hinda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_6">
			<Text>Amani</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_5">
			<Text>Hadja</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_4">
			<Text>Brahim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_3">
			<Text>Acheikh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_2">
			<Text>Achta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_1">
			<Text>Ali</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_CIV_SAS_CHAD_0">
			<Text>Moussa</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--City Names-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_1">
			<Text>N'Djamena</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_2">
			<Text>Moundou</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_3">
			<Text>Abéché</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_4">
			<Text>Sarh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_5">
			<Text>Aouzou</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_6">
			<Text>Kélo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_7">
			<Text>Fada</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_8">
			<Text>Am Timan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_9">
			<Text>Pala</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_10">
			<Text>Faya-Largeau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_11">
			<Text>Bongor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_12">
			<Text>Koumra</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_13">
			<Text>Oum Chalouba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_14">
			<Text>Sala</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_15">
			<Text>Zouar</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_16">
			<Text>Bardaï</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_17">
			<Text>Mongo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_18">
			<Text>Mao</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_19">
			<Text>Doba</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_20">
			<Text>Koro Toro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_21">
			<Text>Biltine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_22">
			<Text>Adré</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_23">
			<Text>Arada</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_24">
			<Text>Goz Beïda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_25">
			<Text>Nokou</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_26">
			<Text>Moussoro</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_27">
			<Text>Bitkine</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_28">
			<Text>Melfi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_29">
			<Text>B'ir Kora</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_SAS_CHAD_30">
			<Text>Ati</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: VANILLA -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_SAS_CHAD_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are now mounting machine guns on their pickup trucks and eating bouillie. I worry the rest of the world will soon succumb to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>