<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 29/09/2020 3:24:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--Bengal-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_ERJAR_BENGAL_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Bengali</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_ERJAR_BENGAL_DESC">
			<Text>Bengal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_ERJAR_BENGAL_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Bengal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Geographic Importance</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Bengal, situated on the apex of the Bay of Bengal and on the banks of the fertile Ganges delta is uniquely situation to be the centre of the world's population. Situated at the perfect latitude at the crossroads of the most populous yields of the world, Bengal is the world's city.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] It is no surprise that civilisation dates back four millennia recorded as far away as the Greeks as the Gangaridai region. Ancient Bengal was home to several kingdoms that stretched their influence out into ancient colonies and traded as far away as Arabia. Thalassocracies reigned at the entrepot of the maritime silk road and was a prized possession of several pan-Indian empires, the Gauda Kingdom and Pala Empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Islamic Conquests and the Sultanate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The Muslim conquest of the Indian subcontinent brought Bengal into the Islamic world. In the 13th century, Bengal was a province of the Delhi Sultanate. In 1352, Ilyas Shah created an independent Bengal Sultanate that would rule for two centuries where Bengal because a mighty trade kingdom and Sufism delved further into Bengal. Bengali literature became to replace the strong hold of Sanskrit and the region slowly Islamised. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Sultanate began to decline in the late 16th and early 17th century. The region came under the suzerainty of the Mughal Empire and was the wealthiest province of the Empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_3">
			<Text>The Nawabate</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The Nawab of Bengal was the hereditary rule of the Bengal Subah, or autonomous province. The title of Nawab was comparable to Grand Dukes in Europe. By the early 18th century, the Nawab of Bengal was a de facto independent ruler who oversaw the provinces of Bengal, Bihar, and Orissa. The Nawabs were the backbone of the Mughal court and became one of the wealthiest rulers of the world able to assert their independence to the Mughals given the declining power of Mughal dynasties.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Proto Industrialization</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_4">
			<Text>The period of Nawab rule was also a period of proto industrialization. The Bengal Sultanate before them had established Bengal as a major trading power with the ability to trade the resources of South Asia to the rest of the world. The textiles industry was particularly important and lucrative, and Bengal-Bihar-Orissa became a major production centre for cotton muslin cloth and silk cloth. Aurangs, or workshops, were created to make the textile production more efficient and the massive amount of people added to the factories set up in the cities of Bengal. Beyond textiles, factories to make ships, gunpowder and metal were also set up in the region. All the extra production further accelerated Bengal's lucrativeness to traders, particularly the British.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_5">
			<Text>British East India Company</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Through some rights given by Nawabs, the British East India Company set up a base around Calcutta alongside other European companies looking to produce and trade the massively lucrative products of Bengal. Eventually with Industrialised British production lines, the British East India Company eventually managed to rival the authorities of the Nawabs after Maratha invasions of the region. The British refused to pay taxes and incited anger.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Nawab Siraj-ud-Daulah took drastic action by sieging Calcutta which prompted a British counter-defence that defeated Siraj in 1757. Mir Jafar was installed as a puppet and his successor tried to stop the British but was unable to. The Nawab of Bengal continued to reign under the British and an attempt by the Mughal Emperor Shah Alam to stop it only paved the road for Britain to move into India. It took until 1858 for the British to abolish the symbolic authority of the Mughals and create new titles for the Nawabs. Calcutta would become the de facto capital of British India as Bengal became Britain's strongest hold on the subcontinent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_6">
			<Text>India, Pakistan, and Bangladesh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_6">
			<Text>At the turn of the 20th century, the Indian Independence movement was fuelled by growing frustration of Indian intellectuals who were barred from participating in their own government. The British constructed institutions of higher learning in India, giving the Indians the general understanding that they could take over control of the instruments of government once they had received the proper education and served the necessary apprenticeships. It soon became apparent that these were hollow promises, as the British kept the higher offices for themselves and froze out the most promising native candidates, no matter how brilliantly they did in university. This was a disastrous policy for the British, for it created a class of highly-educated, highly-dissatisfied Indians.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]In the meantime, Muslim Indians feared that their interests would not be served by the majority Hindu Indian National Congress, and they created a parallel organization, the Muslim League, to fight for Muslim independence. In 1947 the British Parliament passed the Indian Independence Act. The Act recognized two countries: Hindu India and Muslim Pakistan. Pakistan was divided into two sections, one on the east and the other on the west. Nearly 15 million people were displaced during the disintegration of India: Hindus fled from the newly created Pakistan into Hindu India, and Muslims fled India into Muslim Pakistan. Perhaps one million people died during the upheaval.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The new nations were openly hostile to each other, and over the years have fought several wars. Much of the tension has been related to border disputes. In 1971 India intervened in a civil war in East Pakistan, which gained its independence from West Pakistan and became the nation of Bangladesh.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_HEADING_7">
			<Text>West Bengal and Bangladesh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT_7">
			<Text>Bangladesh today is a parliamentary democracy with a very dense population facing severe issues with climate change and natural disasters. Bengal is split along the border with the Indian state of West Bengal. West Bengal is home to Kolkata (Calcutta) and is 70.54% Hindu. Not all West Bengal is Bengali, but much of the lands were part of the historical region of Bengal and contains both Murshidabad and Kolkata. West Bengal is also the fourth most populous state in India and the sixth largest state economy.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] The People's Republic of Bangladesh forms the eastern part of Bengal alongside a few territories like Sylhet and the Chittagong hills. Bangladesh is the eighth most populous county and the most densely populated country on earth with more than 500 square miles. It is the only country today created based on language and ethnicity explicitly with 98% of the region being Bengali. Islam remains a state religion in this secular state. It stands today as the world's city the size of a country.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Cities-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_01">
			<Text>Murshidabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_02">
			<Text>Dhaka</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_03">
			<Text>Kolkata</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_04">
			<Text>Chittagong</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_05">
			<Text>Patna</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_06">
			<Text>Darbhanga</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_07">
			<Text>Midnapore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_08">
			<Text>Ghoraghat</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_09">
			<Text>Sylhet</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_10">
			<Text>Rangpur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_11">
			<Text>Sonargaon</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_12">
			<Text>Nasirabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_13">
			<Text>Palashi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_14">
			<Text>Hajipur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_15">
			<Text>Fathabad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_16">
			<Text>Jessore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_17">
			<Text>Durgapur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_18">
			<Text>Khulna</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_19">
			<Text>Motijheel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_20">
			<Text>Kishenagur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_21">
			<Text>Serampore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_22">
			<Text>Ismailpur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_23">
			<Text>Rajshahi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_24">
			<Text>Cuttack</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_25">
			<Text>Gaur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_26">
			<Text>Gaya</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_27">
			<Text>Jellasore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_28">
			<Text>Bogra</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_29">
			<Text>Hugli</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_30">
			<Text>Chandernagore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_31">
			<Text>Bissunpore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_32">
			<Text>Gauhati</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_33">
			<Text>Madaripur</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_34">
			<Text>Malda</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_35">
			<Text>Tarwas</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_0">
			<Text>Muhammad</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_1">
			<Text>Murshid</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_2">
			<Text>Sharmin</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_3">
			<Text>Jannatul</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_4">
			<Text>Abdul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_5">
			<Text>Sadia</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_6">
			<Text>Basu</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_7">
			<Text>Neepa</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_8">
			<Text>Mahin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_9">
			<Text>Taslima</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_10">
			<Text>Nazmul</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_ERJAR_BENGAL_11">
			<Text>Umme</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!-- Leader -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL">
			<Text>Shuja-ud-Din Muhammad Khan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>Early Years</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Shuja-ud-Din was, in his early years, a governor of the province of Orissa. Known for inclusive policies, Shuja-ud-Din made a quick enemy in Murshid Quli Khan- the Nawab of Bengal. Shuja-ud-Din wasn't pleased with the idea that he would soon serve under Murshid's descendant, and was later convinced that he would be the better ruler. Preparing to take over Bengal, he received support from the Mughal Emperor to take power. Taking the capital of Bengal, Murshidabad, Shuja-ud-Din quickly assumed the title of Nawab and sent a gracious donation to the Mughal Emperor to thank him for the support. For this, Shuja-ud-Din received numerous titles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Rule and Policies</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Known to be as brave as he was generous, Shuja-ud-Din was a ruler of considerable skill. Shuja-ud-Din's policies were inclusive, including towards the Hindu Zamindars who were previously kept in confinement under Murshid Quli Khan. He was an excellent economic administrator, and liberally spent treasury funds on public welfare. Surrounded by powerful advisors, Shuja-ud-Din's reign showcased prosperity in the Bengal region. There were no leaders of Bengal who exemlified the splendor of the Region as much as Shuja-ud-Din.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Death and Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Shuja-ud-Din, while known as a fierce warrior, preferred not to engage in conflict. When Nader Shah of Iran started his conflicts with the Mughal Empire, Shuja-ud-Din fell ill shortly after and did not provide any military assistance, preferring to secure the safety for those close to him, including his son and successor, Sarfaraz Khan. At the time of Shuja-ud-Din's death, Nader Shah invaded Delhi. No successor of Shuja-ud-Din ever grew as much influence or skill as he himself. After his death, he remained a notable figure even in the mind of foreign personalities- with many noting his benevolence and faithfulness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_NAME">
			<Text>Shuja-ud-Din Muhammad Khan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Bengal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Nawab Nazim of Bengal, Bihar and Orissa</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_PEDIA_LIVED">
			<Text>1670 - August 1739</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_DAWN_ERJAR_BENGAL_TEXT">
			<Text>May God smile upon you, Shuja-ud-Din Muhammad Khan! The state you inherited was not an open one. Your predecessor was cold and unfriendly, and his policies even moreso. However, when you took over with the support of the Mughals, you were determined to create a benevolent nation. Your kindness was well-known, as was your ferocity in war. Your kindness was well-known, as was your ferocity in war. No man in Bengal was a just as you were, nor as inspiring. Truly you were deserving of the titles Guardian of the Country, Hero of the State, and Lion in War. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Alas, the prosperity of Bengal drew unparalleled envy and greedy forces. Your successors, not a fraction of the leader you were, could not halt them. Can you rebuild the legacy of the Bengali people? Can you establish an unwavering legacy that shines in the light of God? Can you build a Civilization that can stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--RESPONSES-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Welcome to Paradise, traveller. I am Shuja-ud-Din Muhammad Khan. Make no mistake; I am the ruler here.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>You must be tired from the travels. You can rest here in the Mughals' most loyal region. But make no mistake. I am the ruler here.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You can raze our fields and bombard our factories, but can you truly tame this tiger?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You ride the back a tiger seeking pride over wealth, and you will end up inside when I'm done with you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>A public Declaration of Friendship would aid all this trade. Wouldn't you agree?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>Your actions threaten the stability of my trade and the prosperity of my people. And I cannot ignore it anymore. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Our friendship need not last any longer if you refuse to stop with your attacks on our interests.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>With a heavy heart I must unsheath our swords. You are clearly unfit to rule.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Foolish to challenge the might of Bengal with your rash insults!</Text>
		</Row>
        <!-- AI dislikes you -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_1">
            <Text>...Am I supposed to laugh here?</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- Repeatedly trying to trade with the AI -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_REPEAT_TRADE_1">
            <Text>Enjoy the care of our Katra longer. Perhaps then you'll have a better offer.</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- Generic greetings depending on how the AI feels about you -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_GREETING_WORKING_WITH_1">
            <Text>Greetings my friend! Your are always welcome to trade here. What do you want to discuss?</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- AI likes you -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
            <Text>I hope you are well and rested from your travels. What can a friend do for you?</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- AI has no strong feelings -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
            <Text>Well, come to Bengal to trade again, I suppose.</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- AI dislikes you -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
            <Text>Yes, yes. Trade must flow on. Unfortunately... Get on with it then.</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- AI considers you to be a warmonger -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
            <Text>Your thirst for blood and land concerns me. What brings you here? Free trade through force?</Text>
        </Row>
        <!-- AI declares war by backstabbing a friend -->
        <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ERJAR_BENGAL_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
            <Text>A shock it might come, but you might want to re-evaluate our recent trades. You were a good friend but a terrible trade partner.</Text>
        </Row>
		
		<!--UA Paradise of Nations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_ERJAR_BENGAL_SHORT">
			<Text>Paradise of Nations</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_ERJAR_BENGAL">
			<Text>Cities send [ICON_FOOD] Food and [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to other cities on the same river based on the number of specialists. Manufactories increase the yields of trade routes in the nearest city by 3% (max 15%).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_ERJAR_BENGAL_CBP">
			<Text>Cities send [ICON_FOOD] Food and [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production to other cities on the same river based on the number of specialists. Manufactories increase the yields of trade routes in the nearest city by 3% (max 15%). Rivers create [ICON_TRADE] City Connections.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Katra -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ERJAR_KATRA">
			<Text>Katra</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ERJAR_KATRA_HELP">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold on River Tiles. +2 [ICON_GOLD] Gold and +50% range to land and sea trade routes.[NEWLINE]When a Trade Route is completed receive [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great Engineer Points and a temporary boost to [ICON_FOOD] food proportional to the amount of [ICON_GOLD] Gold per turn generated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ERJAR_KATRA_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides [ICON_GOLD] on River Tiles and boosts your ability to trade on both land and sea. It provides Great Engineer Points and food depending on how lucrative your trade routes are.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ERJAR_KATRA_TEXT">
			<Text>Katra are Bengali caravansari that served as resting spots for traders coming out of inland South Asia to trade out of the naval traders coming to Bengal. The Katra united the land and sea trade into a cohesive transition in Bengal. The Katra built by the Mughals and Nawabs grew large in grandeur as they brought wealth to the area and hosted many great ideas.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ERJAR_KATRA_DUMMY">
			<Text>Katra TR dummy</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Paik -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ERJAR_PAIK">
			<Text>Paik</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ERJAR_PAIK_HELP">
			<Text>It has the Amphibious Promotion. In addition, it gain +1 Range when on rivers, and this ability is retained upon upgrade.[NEWLINE]While embarked, stacked Naval Ranged units gain +1 Range.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ERJAR_PAIK_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Being Amphibious and having extra range on rivers allows the Paik to dominate river combat. It also serves as a very powerful naval support unit by increasing the range of naval ranged units when stacked.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_ERJAR_PAIK_TEXT">
			<Text>The Paik or Paika System was present across South Asia, but in Bengal they formed an elite military force. Paik were footmen trained on the offense and defense with archery. The system derives from the Mughals in the 13th century with the Bengal Sultanate adopting forms of it. The Nawabs being associated with the Mughals strengthened this system. The navy was also important to Bengal, especially along rivers and boats backed by the Paiks could command supremacy when land units could not. War boats and their relation with Paik in warfare played an important role in the political affairs of the country.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Promotions-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ERJAR_PAIK_OFF">
			<Text>Bengali military elite</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ERJAR_PAIK_OFF_HELP">
			<Text>+1 Range when on rivers</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ERJAR_PAIK_ON">
			<Text>River supremacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ERJAR_PAIK_ON_HELP">
			<Text>+1 Range active</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_ERJAR_SHIP_RANGE">
			<Text>Paik support</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Unique Cultural Influence-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_GENERIC_ERJAR_BENGAL_INFLUENTIAL_ON_AI_1">
			<Text>Our people are designing luxury fabrics and have started amassing great amounts of wealth. I worry the rest of the world will fall to the influence of your culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ACHIEVEMENTS-->
		<!--Jarcast's Civilizations-->
		<Replace Tag="TXT_KEY_TAB_JAR_CIVS_HEADER">
			<Text>Jarcast's Civilizations</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Tag="TXT_KEY_TAB_JAR_CIVS_DESC">
			<Text>Achievements for Jarcast's mods.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--EmeraldRange's and Jarcast's Bengal-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_ERJAR_BENGAL_NAME">
			<Text>EmeraldRange's and Jarcast's Bengal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_ERJAR_BENGAL_MODID">
			<Text>460dcc36-895f-48dc-85de-1d1fe0998856</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_ERJAR_BENGAL_AUTHORS">
			<Text>EmeraldRange, Jarcast</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Victory-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_ERJAR_BENGAL_VICTORY_HEADER">
			<Text>Bengal Tiger</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_ERJAR_BENGAL_VICTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>Beat the game on any difficulty setting as Bengal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Special-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_ERJAR_BENGAL_SPECIAL_HEADER">
			<Text>Proto-industrialization</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_AA_ERJAR_BENGAL_SPECIAL_TEXT">
			<Text>Establish at least 5 Manufactories before Industrial Era.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>