<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 1/4/2014 8:45:16 AM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--MOD-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_MOD_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DESCRIPTION">
			<Text>AMERICA (FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE TRAIT: NEW DEAL[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Merchant and Engineer Specialists provide a burst of their respective [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great People Points whenever you adopt a new [ICON_CULTURE] Social Policy. +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture from Customs Houses and Manufacturies.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE BUILDING: ASSEMBLY PLANT (FACTORY)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The Assembly Plant is the unique replacement for the Factory for America. In addition to the regular production boosts provided by the Factory, the Assembly Plant grants an additional +20% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when building Air, Armor, and Siege Units. The Assembly Plant also possesses an additional slot for an Engineer Specialist. Constructing Assembly Plants in cities with your highest production outputs will ensure a steady flow of mechanized units with which fuel your war efforts.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: B17 (BOMBER)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The B17 Bomber is an American Unique Unit, replacing the bomber. It is similar to the bomber, but it is more difficult for enemy anti-aircraft and fighters to target. The B17 also receives a bonus when attacking enemy cities. Like the bomber, the B17's range is 10. See the rules on Aircraft for more details.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]AMERICA (GEORGE WASHINGTON)[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]UNIQUE UNIT: SCHOONER (PRIVATEER)[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]The unique Schooner is the American replacement for the Privateer. In addition to the standard abilities of the Privateer, the Schooner is especially good at attacking other Privateers. It also fights much better in friendly territory. Keep your Schooners near to your coastal borders and launch attacks on enemy fleets that get too close.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AMERICA-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>American</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DESC">
			<Text>American Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>America</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Cities-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_01">
			<Text>Washington</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_02">
			<Text>New York</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_03">
			<Text>Chicago</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_04">
			<Text>Philadelphia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_05">
			<Text>Detroit</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_06">
			<Text>Los Angeles</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_07">
			<Text>Cleveland</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_08">
			<Text>Baltimore</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_09">
			<Text>St. Louis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_10">
			<Text>Boston</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_11">
			<Text>Pittsburgh</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_12">
			<Text>San Francisco</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_13">
			<Text>Milwaukee</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_14">
			<Text>Buffalo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_15">
			<Text>New Orleans</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_16">
			<Text>Minneapolis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_17">
			<Text>Cincinnati</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_18">
			<Text>Kansas City</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_19">
			<Text>Indianapolis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_20">
			<Text>Houston</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_21">
			<Text>Seattle</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_22">
			<Text>Las Vegas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_23">
			<Text>Denver</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_24">
			<Text>Columbus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_25">
			<Text>Atlanta</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_26">
			<Text>Louisville</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_27">
			<Text>Dallas</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_28">
			<Text>Richmond</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_29">
			<Text>San Diego</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_30">
			<Text>Miami</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Spies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_0">
			<Text>Moe</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_1">
			<Text>John</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_2">
			<Text>Sterling</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_3">
			<Text>Elizabeth</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_4">
			<Text>Eric</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_5">
			<Text>Jim</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_6">
			<Text>Edward</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_7">
			<Text>Richard</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_8">
			<Text>Virginia</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_9">
			<Text>Claire</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<!--FRANKLIN ROOSEVELT-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT">
			<Text>Franklin Roosevelt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Franklin Delano Roosevelt, the 32nd President of the United States, is best known for leading the US out of the Great Depression and to victory in WWII. Crippled by polio at 39, Roosevelt displayed indomitable courage and resolve to overcome his disability and achieve his goals.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Roosevelt was a man of contradictions. Though wealthy and powerful, Roosevelt was beloved by the poor and downtrodden and despised as a socialist by the wealthy and powerful. Roosevelt ran for office on a platform of isolationism, but he hated fascism and oppression, and unceasingly worked behind the scenes to aid the UK and get America into World War II.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When Roosevelt first became President in 1932, the United States was in a crippling depression. Banks had closed and businesses had failed. Millions were unemployed and falling into poverty. To counter this malaise, Roosevelt enacted a series of policies that he called the "New Deal:" a sweeping program to bring recovery to business and agriculture, relief to the unemployed and to those in danger of losing businesses, farms and homes.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Meanwhile, the Depression raged across the entire planet, and much of the rest of the world was degenerating into chaos. Japan was attacking China, while the two great dictators - Hitler and Stalin - were threatening to engulf Europe. The United States had largely withdrawn from world politics after World War I and the failure of the League of Nations, and few American politicians had the stomach to call for intervention. Roosevelt didn't, either, and in fact he ran for reelection on a platform of isolationism.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]However, Roosevelt sincerely believed that the United States would have to become involved in the conflict one way or another - he abhorred fascism and totalitarianism - and he feared that, left unchecked, Germany, Russia and Japan would become powerful enough to overwhelm everything in their path - including, eventually, the US. Thus he did everything in his power to ready the US for the upcoming conflict by dramatically increasing the size of the US armed forces, pitifully weakened after the end of World War I. Further, he gave as much aid as was politically feasible to England, whom he rightly saw as the unprepared US's chief protection from the German war machine. Meanwhile, he did his best to turn public opinion around in favor of more direct action.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]It is not clear that Roosevelt would have succeeded in that, if it weren't for Japan's attack against Pearl Harbor. Though casualties were extremely heavy, Pearl Harbor did "awake a sleeping giant," and at long last the citizens of the country realized their peril. And when Germany made the huge strategic blunder of declaring war on the United States shortly thereafter, Roosevelt was able to put all of the United States' massive industrial and military might into the conflict.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]During the war, Roosevelt showed himself to be a masterful international politician; the UK-Soviet-American alliance was shaky at best, and his adroit handling of Stalin and Churchill did much to keep things running (relatively) smoothly. Meanwhile his "fireside chats" kept the country firmly behind him, and world opinion in the allies' favor. It has been said that Hitler hated Roosevelt even more than Stalin or Churchill - high praise indeed.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]As a military leader Roosevelt was less sure-footed and the US made some early strategic blunders that could have been avoided. He learned quickly, however, and by the end of his life the US military machine was the most powerful that the world had ever seen.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Roosevelt died in 1945, shortly before the war ended. His legacies of social welfare and international cooperation would dominate United States policies for the next half a century.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_LIVED">
			<Text>1882 - 1945</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_NAME">
			<Text>Franklin Roosevelt</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of America</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_TITLES_1">
			<Text>President of the United States of America</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DAWN">
			<Text>Greetings, President Roosevelt, leader of the United States of America. With courage and determination, you led America through her darkest hours. Elected to the presidency in 1933, your aim would be to reinvigorate a shattered economy. Against the pressures of your republican foes, you championed extensive policies aimed at alleviating the status of the poor and disadvantaged. But it was in 1941 that the United States would be suddenly and deliberately attacked by the Empire of Japan, and the strength of your leadership would be called upon with lasting success.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The time has come for you to show that leadership once more, Mr. President. Can you give voice to the downtrodden and raise America's industries from off the ground? Can you lead the Western world to prosperity in the aftermath of war? Can you build a civilization that will stand the test of time?</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Responses-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Welcome to America. I am President Franklin Roosevelt. I greet you as a friend and prospective ally.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>History will judge me by the enemies I have made.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>America shall rise against you, and you shall see that you have awoken a sleeping giant.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>The American government sees an ally in you and I see a friend. Will you join me in making a public Declaration of Friendship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You are an enemy to freedom and liberty, and you must be stopped.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DENOUNCE_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>You have betrayed my trust and the trust of the American people.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_DOW_GENERIC_1">
			<Text>When you see a rattlesnake poised to strike, you do not wait until he has struck to crush him. We march to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>America will not stand for this injustice.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--NEW DEAL-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT_SHORT">
			<Text>New Deal</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_JFD_AMERICA_F_ROOSEVELT">
			<Text>Merchant and Engineer Specialists provide a burst of their respective [ICON_GREAT_PEOPLE] Great People Points whenever you adopt a new [ICON_CULTURE] Social Policy. +2 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture from Customs Houses and Manufacturies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--ASSEMBLY PLANT-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_ARMS_FACTORY">
			<Text>Assembly Plant</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_ARMS_FACTORY_HELP">
			<Text>+20% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production toward Air, Armor, and Siege Units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Requires 1 [ICON_RES_COAL] Coal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_JFD_ARMS_FACTORY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Assembly Plant is the unique replacement for the Factory for America. In addition to the regular production boosts provided by the Factory, the Assembly Plant grants an additional +20% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when building Air, Armor, and Siege Units. The Assembly Plant also possesses an additional slot for an Engineer Specialist. Constructing Assembly Plants in cities with your highest production outputs will ensure a steady flow of mechanized units with which fuel your war efforts.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>