<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 8/2/2016 11:49:10 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: VANILLA Vanilla -->
		<!--First Greeting messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>We're building the future in here Compañero. I am Salvador Allende, representative of the people of Chile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Welcome to the Nation of Chile. I am Salvador Allende, representative of the will of the working people of this country.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Defeated messages from AI leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>These are my last words. But I have the certainty that my sacrifice shall not be in vain. I know that my defeat will be a moral lesson that will castigate felony, cowardy and treason.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>Workers of my Nation! I have faith in Chile and its destiny. Soon shall we overcome this dark day and the day when people will be able to walk freely once again through peaceful avenues. As for now... Long Live Chile! Long live the People. Long live the Workers!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>Placed in a historic transition, I will pay for my loyalty to the people with my life.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--First Greeting from leaders that don't have their own file yet-->
		<!-- Human repeats an action too much, gets the following responses -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REPEAT_TOO_MUCH">
			<Text>You really go crazy with all these button things.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REPEAT_TRADE_1">
			<Text>This is utterly unacceptable for the people of Chile.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REPEAT_TRADE_2">
			<Text>This won't cut it with the necessecities we have right now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REPEAT_TRADE_3">
			<Text>Are you trying to take advantage of the people of Chile?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_REPEAT_1">
			<Text>Forgot your documents?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_REPEAT_2">
			<Text>Do you want a tea now?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_1">
			<Text>We've both made our intentions very clear. Why do you keep coming back?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_REPEAT_2">
			<Text>I should stop serving wine on meetings</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Greetings -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Oh, do you like wine? I've got an excellent Cabernet Sauvignon around here...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_2">
			<Text>I know you come with good news!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_3">
			<Text>Compañero!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_POLITE_HELLO_4">
			<Text>Always glad to see a friend!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Welcome Compañero, what can I do to help you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_2">
			<Text>This room sure leaves an impression, eh?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_3">
			<Text>Don't mind the computers, What would you like to discuss?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_4">
			<Text>Hope the people of your nation are doing well</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_5">
			<Text>Oh those reports just came in, but come in, I'll take care of them later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_NEUTRAL_HELLO_6">
			<Text>What have you done for your people recently?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_HELLO_1">
			<Text>Have you come to take advantage of our humble nation?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_DESTRUCTION_LOOMS_1">
			<Text>The people must not sacrifice themselves! Let us make peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_DESTRUCTION_LOOMS_2">
			<Text>I cannot bear to see this nation burn... let's end this war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Violence is not the solution to our problems!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_2">
			<Text>We've got the right to live in peace!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AT_WAR_WANTS_PEACE_3">
			<Text>Please. We must overcome this dark and bitter moment.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>The people united will never be defeated!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Underestimated the power of the people, did you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AT_WAR_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>Chileans, never mess with chileans.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_BROKEN_MILITARY_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>Oh, I know conspirators and wannabe coupers all too well...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_WORKING_WITH_1">
			<Text>I'm glad we can go through this historic transition together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_COOP_WAR_1">
			<Text>We shall triumph my friend. We shall overcome.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_COOP_WAR_2">
			<Text>This is most detestable bussiness. But if it means the downfall of {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey} I'm glad we're going at it together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_COOP_WAR_3">
			<Text>Soon {1_ThirdPlayerName:textkey} shall stop tarnishing the values of our nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>Violence is not the only way, you know.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HUMAN_AT_WAR_1">
			<Text>I know the armed way may sometimes look necessary, but please, reconsider your ways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>I fully trust my generals if war times are to come. Just so you may know...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>The press has talked about saber rattling over our border. Anything to say about that?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>I shall not tolerate such imperialistic policies as yours. Keep your land grabbing at bay.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_EXPANSION_1">
			<Text>I've heard of some border incidents with your people. I hope that these won't amount to anything. What would you like to discuss?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>The land of the People of Chile is not for sale. I shall not tolerate such violent irruption into the lands of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_AGGRESSIVE_PLOT_BUYING_1">
			<Text>We're going through a sort of agrarian reform in my territory. Could you please not take advantage of my people while doing so?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Though I do not support these ideals myself. I can understand the power a strong military, as long as it protects the people. I commend your efforths.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_FRIENDLY_STRONG_ECONOMY_1">
			<Text>Oh, while you're here. May I ask some economic advice from your nation? My advisors aren't quite... reliable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_FEW_CITIES_1">
			<Text>Don't worry, I don't look down on... smaller nations</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_SMALL_ARMY_1">
			<Text>Listen, I can understand wanting to cut down on the army, I've personally had my problems with it. But you have to bear in mind, the military is there for a reason...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_HOSTILE_HUMAN_IS_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>Your imperialistic tendencies are a threat to the entire world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_1">
			<Text>If it were by me, I'd gladly accept your friendship. However I represent the will of all the people of this nation, and at this moment, it isn't in our best interests to do so.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_2">
			<Text>We're still not sure the intentions of your civilization being compatible with this project of ours, so as of now, I must decline.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_TOO_SOON_FOR_DOF_3">
			<Text>The people of Chile haven't yet made a good image of your country, try later.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOF_AI_DENOUNCE_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>Compañero! Glad to see you. I fear this is not the best moment for this nation, for {1_CivName} has been conspiring for my downfall and that of everything we've built, could you do a Denounciation towards them as a token of support towards our cause?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOF_NOT_HONORED_1">
			<Text>I should have suspected as much. I shall make it known that you too conspire against our Cyberbolivarian Transition.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOF_NOT_HONORED_2">
			<Text>So it is then? No one's to be trusted these days, I shall tell the world of how you're too seeking the downfall of a nation as peaceful as mine.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DENOUNCING_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>I've heard terrible rumours and everything is pointing out for them to be true. You have been conspiring against my project since the very beginning, and I shall let the world know of your treachery.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DENOUNCING_FRIEND_2">
			<Text>You're not a friend of the people's government and our peaceful resolve.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_1">
			<Text>Well, I'm not friends to everyone, I know my project may seem a little bit unorthodox, but history shall prove me right.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_TO_BEING_DENOUNCED_2">
			<Text>At least I have my people's support.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DOFED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Ahhh, I've noticed that you've become friends with {1_CivName}. Glad to hear of it. I'm already on good terms with them myself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DOFED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>I've had many altercates with {1_CivName} in the past. I just say... they may not be who they claim to be.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_FRIEND_1">
			<Text>Both {1_CivName} and I are working towards similar goals. How much of a surprise it is that you're against that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DENOUNCED_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>Glad to hear there are others in the world which share my disgust with {1_CivName}. They are clearly not to be trusted.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Being on such good terms, I couldn't help but notice that you'd become friends with {1_CivName}. Our cooperation truly shall leave a message to the world at large.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>I share your convictions that {1_CivName} only causes problems for the civilized nations of the world. Perhaps the combination of our denouncements will teach them a lesson.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DOF_SO_AI_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>You made a Declaration of Friendship with {1_CivName}? I should have suspected as much.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DENOUNCE_SO_AI_DOF_1">
			<Text>Anyone who you don't get along with is clearly worth building a friendship with. Give {1_CivName} my regards.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- LEADER_ALLENDE Diplo Text -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I see you sabre-rattling near our borders. The people of Chile shall not cower from war, if it comes to happen.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that you have a large number of Units near my borders. I request that you move them elsewhere to avoid causing undue distress to my citizens.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_KILLED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>Your wanton violence towards {@1_MinorCivName} is an horrible display of absolute disregard for human life.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{@1_MinorCivName} is a nation that needs and has our protection. Neither my people nor I shall tolerate this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EXPANSION_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Your expansion efforts are an insult. Know that there will be consequences for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EXPANSION_WARNING_1">
			<Text>I couldn't help but notice that you seem to be expanding into lands which I regard to be mine. I request that you reconsider this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EXPANSION_WARNING_2">
			<Text>Your habit of claiming every bit of land you've spotted has not gone unnoticed. I advise you to discontinue this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EXPANSION_WARNING_3">
			<Text>If you should continue to expand your empire in lands I feel are mine it can only ruin the possibility of friendship between us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EXPANSION_WARNING_4">
			<Text>The settling of your people near my sovereign territory is placing a strain upon relations between our two nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EXPANSION_BROKEN_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>Your guarantee of not expanding near us seems to have been empty words. Know that there will be consequences for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PLOT_BUYING_SERIOUS_WARNING_1">
			<Text>The aggressive manner in which you buy up territory near us is an insult. I had hoped you would be a better neighbor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PLOT_BUYING_WARNING_1">
			<Text>Your purchase of land in my vicinity has caused some alarm. I caution you so that this issue does not become more serious.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PLOT_BUYING_BROKEN_PROMISE_1">
			<Text>So it seems you lied when you told us that your empire would stop purchasing land near us. I do not take this insult lightly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PLOT_BUYING_BROKEN_PROMISE_2">
			<Text>I am very disappointed that you did not stop funding land acquisition near my territory. I had hoped you were a more honorable leader.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_1">
			<Text>It is hard to find worthy friends in this world. I'd like to forge a Pact of Cooperation with your great empire. What do you say?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_2">
			<Text>Great leader, would you care to enter a Pact of Cooperation? My hope is that we can build a long-lasting bond between our two empires.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_3">
			<Text>Let us plant the seeds of a bright future by forming a Pact of Cooperation. What say you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_4">
			<Text>This world can be cruel. Only with the assistance of others can we overcome it. Shall we join in a Pact of Cooperation?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_1">
			<Text>It is hard to find worthy friends in this world. I'd like to make a public Declaration of Friendship, informing the other empires of the bond between our peoples. What do you say?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_2">
			<Text>Great leader, would you care to make a Declaration of Friendship to the world? My hope is that we can build a long-lasting bond between our two empires.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_3">
			<Text>Let us plant the seeds of a bright future by making a Declaration of Friendship to the world. What say you?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEC_FRIENDSHIP_4">
			<Text>This world can be cruel. Only with the assistance of others can we overcome it. Shall we announce to the world our Declaration of Friendship?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DENOUNCE_1">
			<Text>So, then, we were fated to be enemies all along.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DENOUNCE_2">
			<Text>Your treachery is unbounded. The world will know of what you have done.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]([COLOR_WARNING_TEXT]They have publicly denounced us! NOTE: You are not at war.[ENDCOLOR])</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_COOP_WAR_REQUEST_1">
			<Text>{1_PlayerName:textkey} has brought immeasurable suffering to this earth. For the sake of everything that's still good in this Earth. I fear we must cooperate to bring down his regime.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_COOP_WAR_TIME_1">
			<Text>I fear the time has come for this ugly bussiness, let's... let's just start war against {1_PlayerName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_NOW_UNFORGIVABLE_1">
			<Text>Your actions are unforgivable. There can never be reconciliation between our two nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_NOW_ENEMY_1">
			<Text>Your actions betray your words. I should have known as much sooner. I've been a fool. Consider the relations between our two civilizations over.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_COMPLIMENT_1">
			<Text>I wanted to make it known to you that I value our friendship, and hope that it might remain strong.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_BOOT_KISSING_1">
			<Text>I'm glad to know I can count on your support during these uncertain times.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_BOOT_KISSING_2">
			<Text>We may not always agree, but I really trust your guidance as an example to my own government.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WARMONGER_1">
			<Text>I this really your regard to the people of the world? Invading and conquering with no care for those caught in the middle? Please, reconsider this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WARMONGER_2">
			<Text>Your threatening the entire world by getting yourself involved in wars that are none of your bussiness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WARMONGER_3">
			<Text>I shouldn't tolerate such people in my lands. But I do because I care. Amend your ways, seek the path of peace</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WARMONGER_4">
			<Text>Your intervention in other people's affairs shall be your downfall.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_MINOR_CIV_COMPETITION_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that you're getting a little friendly with {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Trust me, it's not necessary, they are under our protection and we can take care of them just fine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_MINOR_CIV_COMPETITION_2">
			<Text>I've noticed your relationship with {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. While that's nice, it would be best that you leave their protection to us. I'd hate for either of us to step on any toes.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Insults-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_ALLENDE_1">
			<Text>You are a tyrant to your people</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_MILITARY_1">
			<Text>Take this as personal advice. I know the military may be annoying at times. But whether we like it or not, it's fundamental for the sovereingty of a nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_BULLY_1">
			<Text>Why must you bully those lesser than you? I would do not such thing, myself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_UNHAPPINESS_1">
			<Text>As a person I tell you, you must listen to what your people has to say. You're about to face a revolution.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_CITIES_1">
			<Text>The size of your nation is quite... quaint.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_POPULATION_1">
			<Text>Travelers have told us that your empire's economy is in pretty sad shape.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_CULTURE_1">
			<Text>What a sad sight... your empire is so uncultured.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INSULT_CULTURE_2">
			<Text>Your cultural development is simply sad.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Public Declarations-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DECLARATION_PROTECT_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} announces to the world that it is now protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}. Attacking the City-State will greatly damage relations and may lead to war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DECLARATION_ABANDON_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>{2_MajorCivName:textkey} has taken back its guarantee of protecting {1_MinorCivName:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Human is asking the AI for something-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REPEAT_NO_1">
			<Text>We've been over this before. The answer is still no. Do not bring this up again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REPEAT_NO_2">
			<Text>I may be gentle, but that doesn't mean I shall give in easily, the answer is still no</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DONT_SETTLE_YES_1">
			<Text>Very well. I agree to avoid settling in the vicinity of your empire for the time being. Perhaps in the future you will be a more accommodating neighbor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DONT_SETTLE_YES_2">
			<Text>So be it. I will not settle near your lands. Cooperation is clearly not one of your strong suits.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DONT_SETTLE_NO_1">
			<Text>Unacceptable. These lands need development and I shall provide it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DONT_SETTLE_NO_2">
			<Text>You dare insult me in such a manner? I will not forget this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DONT_SETTLE_NO_3">
			<Text>How dare you? Do you believe me to be weak-willed?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DONT_SETTLE_NO_4">
			<Text>Not a chance. You need to brush up on your diplomacy, my friend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_YES_1">
			<Text>That will work. May a strong friendship lead to a bright future for us all.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_YES_2">
			<Text>An excellent idea. May our alliance kead to a better living for our people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WORK_WITH_US_YES_3">
			<Text>I am happy to accept. May the people work freely in cooperation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DECLINE_1">
			<Text>I must decline.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DECLINE_2">
			<Text>Sorry, but no. Perhaps another time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DECLINE_3">
			<Text>I fear that such an arrangement is not in my best interests, so I must decline.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_COOP_WAR_YES_1">
			<Text>As it pains me to admit it, it's the correct choice. I hope I'll be able to forgive me for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_COOP_WAR_SOON_1">
			<Text>Though I personally don't agree with it. My advisors tell me it's on the best of my interests. However we're not prepared. Give us 10 turns.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_1">
			<Text>Very well. I do what I must to maintain peace in my lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_2">
			<Text>I will do what it takes to keep the peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_YES_3">
			<Text>Fine. But know that you poison your reputation with acts such as these. For what that might be worth to you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_1">
			<Text>Please. You're in no position to make such demands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_2">
			<Text>You should be well aware of your own inability to back those threats up.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_3">
			<Text>You're not fooling anyone. I have nothing to fear from you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_WEAK_4">
			<Text>Haha! I'll assume this transgression just happened because you're not in the best state of mind.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You dare insult me in such a manner? If you want something so badly then do your best to come and take it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>You'll have to take it from my dead body.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>If you want that you'll have to come and get it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_4">
			<Text>Unacceptable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_HOSTILE_5">
			<Text>Don't be a fool.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_1">
			<Text>You ask for too much. I will not drive my nation into poverty to satisfy your greed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_2">
			<Text>No. I have my dignity, and refuse to hand over such a great bounty so freely.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_MUCH_3">
			<Text>Your desire to strip my lands of so much wealth is intolerable. Do not ask for so much.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_1">
			<Text>You threaten me again so soon? I refuse your demands, you vile beast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_2">
			<Text>I think you should enact some reforms in your lands to better your production, rather.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_DEMAND_REFUSE_TOO_SOON_3">
			<Text>Asking for the fruits of others' labor yet again? Your behavior is too bourgeois. Learn to enjoy the fruits of your own labor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Deal Offers and related-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_LETS_HEAR_IT_1">
			<Text>Always glad to encourage fair trade between equals.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_LETS_HEAR_IT_2">
			<Text>This shall be interesting</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PEACE_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I'm willing to pay this, if it means the wellbeing of my people</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PEACE_OFFER_2">
			<Text>I'm not a violent man. I think it's time to end this buffonade.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PEACE_OFFER_3">
			<Text>For the sake of our people, of our future. Let's make peace.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DEMAND_1">
			<Text>I don't like to do this. But you have something we need and I'm willing to take any measures to make sure my people get it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REQUEST_ITEM_1">
			<Text>Unfortunately things aren't going terribly well over here. Can you spare something for a friend? I'll try to return the favor when things are going better for me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REQUEST_ITEM_2">
			<Text>Although it pains me to do so, I must ask for your assistance, friend.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_REQUEST_ITEM_3">
			<Text>My people are in great need. I beg of you, from person to person, please, help us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>We must let the free man walk freely without fear of borders, do you agree?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_OPEN_BORDERS_EXCHANGE_2">
			<Text>Opening our borders to one another can only serve to solidify our friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_OPEN_BORDERS_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I would like to negotiate passage through your territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PLAN_RESEARCH_AGREEMENT_1">
			<Text>I would like to lay plans for establishing a Research Agreement with your great nation. Doing so would require each of us to spend 150 [ICON_GOLD]. What do you think?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE](Agreeing will not form a Research Agreement yet)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESEARCH_AGREEMENT_OFFER_1">
			<Text>I bet your scientists are desperate for an opportunity to witness the secrets in the computers behind me. Maybe we can reach an agreement?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RENEW_DEAL_1">
			<Text>This deal strengthened our nations and our bonds of friendship. Shall we renew this deal and continue our shared prosperity?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WANT_MORE_RENEW_DEAL_1">
			<Text>Times change. Necessities and Values get reconsidered. To renew this deal, we would need more from your side of the negotiation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_LUXURY_TRADE_1">
			<Text>The people of Chile are in grave need of this resource.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Attacked by another player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>I shall save your people from your ways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>The battle for Chile shall be one to be remembered. Let history know us as a people who fought tooth and claw against oppresion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_2">
			<Text>Though my armies may be weak, the will of my people is strong and won't be subdued easily.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_3">
			<Text>Destroy me if you can. I can promise you though, history will reivindicate me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_4">
			<Text>So be it. The people of Chile will give the fight of their lives.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_WEAK_HOSTILE_5">
			<Text>You will forever be known as a villain who preys on the weak.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_STRONG_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>You mistake my gentle demeanor for weakness. You shall pay for that mistake.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Oh, let me tell you, my advisors really find this an excellent opportunity to prove their word.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_WEAK_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>I find no joy in these militaristic endeavours. But if it must come to happen. I shall make sure it'll be for the best outcome of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_STRONG_EXCITED_1">
			<Text>Haha. Well, I won't question your decision, but it appears to me that you've made a big mistake.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_SAD_1">
			<Text>Your actions fill me with sadness... There is surely a special place in Hell for those such as you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_SAD_2">
			<Text>You would attack us in such a manner? Your hubris knows no limits. I hope that you will one day be judged for this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_SAD_3">
			<Text>Taking advantage of another's weakness is unnecessary in the pursuit of victory. Surely you know there's a better way?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_SAD_4">
			<Text>How could you do such a thing? Begone, you vile being.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_BETRAYED_1">
			<Text>I had thought us friends. This is a grave betrayal.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- AI Declaring War-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_LEADER_ALLENDE_1">
			<Text>We knew this day would come. Your unjust rule has come to an end.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_ATTACKED_MILITARY_PROMISE_BROKEN_1">
			<Text>You have betrayed your word. Make no mistake, the world will know of your treachery.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_LAND_1">
			<Text>Your lands is poorly kept and corruptly managed. We shall ammend that. By force.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_1">
			<Text>It is now the moment to begin the true world revolution.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_2">
			<Text>Fate has christened me the one which shall bring unity to this divided planet.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_3">
			<Text>You shall be assimilated.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_4">
			<Text>I'll be honest with you - I intend to destroy you along with everyone else.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_5">
			<Text>You are merely a stepping-stone on my grand ascent to world domination.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WORLD_CONQUEST_6">
			<Text>Now is the time for my master plan to commence. It is time for you to die like the rest of these fools.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_1">
			<Text>The advantage is mine. I will now destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_2">
			<Text>I have waited long enough. I have seen an opening in your defense and I will use it to my advantage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_3">
			<Text>I have been waiting a long time for this day. Now would be a good time to put your affairs in order.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_4">
			<Text>It is now my time. I will defeat you and come one step closer to victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_5">
			<Text>My advisors tell me this is the best course of action.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_6">
			<Text>The current situation cannot be ignored. It is now or never.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_7">
			<Text>I cannot ignore this chance to eliminate a potential competitor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_OPPORTUNITY_8">
			<Text>Your weakness presents to me a great opportunity. You have my apologies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_1">
			<Text>Although the task before me may be impossible, I am compelled to find a way to destroy you and all that you stand for. I will do so or die trying.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_2">
			<Text>It is clear that you are strong. I will, however, find a way to defeat you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_3">
			<Text>You are a villain without equal. Within every fiber of my being, I know I must destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_4">
			<Text>Your might is unmatched, but I will find a way to defeat you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_5">
			<Text>The time to make a stand is now. The odds are not with me, but I find a way to destroy you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_6">
			<Text>My people are proud and strong and would rather die fighting than under the joke of an oppressor. Odds are not in my favor, but were they ever?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_7">
			<Text>Although I do not wish it, I fear that now may be my only opportunity to defeat you. Let us meet on the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_DESPERATE_8">
			<Text>Destruction might be the fate which awaits me, but should I back down only eventual defeat awaits anyways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>Although feigning friendship with you wasn't very polite, few who make their mark on history were known for their manners. May your passage be swift.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_BETRAYAL_2">
			<Text>I couldn't tolerate it anymore. Your people shall be much better under my protection.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_BETRAYAL_3">
			<Text>I fear your project was anathema to mine. There was no recourse but war. I shall take care of your people, you have my word.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_BETRAYAL_4">
			<Text>As much as it pains me to. My advisors told me this was the best course of actions. War was necessary and it shall be done. I hope you'll eventually understand.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DOW_WEAK_BETRAYAL_1">
			<Text>The odds are clearly not with me, but I fully trust in my generals and the will of my people to get us through the worst in this war.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WAR_DEMAND_REFUSED_1">
			<Text>So be it. My armies will extract it from your lands then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WAR_DEMAND_REFUSED_2">
			<Text>Then war it is.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a human peace offer-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_1">
			<Text>What is your offer?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_2">
			<Text>What would you suggest?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_PEACE_WHAT_WILL_HUMAN_OFFER_3">
			<Text>What is the price of peace?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>Cyberbolivarianism must still be imposed upon you, by force.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_NO_PEACE_2">
			<Text>This is not the time for negotiation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_NO_PEACE_3">
			<Text>We still have business to settle.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_TOO_SOON_NO_PEACE_1">
			<Text>So you think you can just declare war on my people and then come back and act like nothing happened? We shall keep fighting. We shall not surrender, not now.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--AI Responses to a discussion mode topics-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_1">
			<Text>Make it so!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_2">
			<Text>I am grateful that this has ended without violence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_3">
			<Text>I am pleased to hear this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_PLEASED_4">
			<Text>That is good to hear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_1">
			<Text>You have my thanks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_2">
			<Text>I am grateful that this has ended without violence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_THANKFUL_3">
			<Text>History will long remember your great deeds.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_1">
			<Text>That is a shame.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_2">
			<Text>Perhaps another time then.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_DISAPPOINTED_3">
			<Text>That is disappointing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SO_BE_IT_1">
			<Text>So be it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SO_BE_IT_2">
			<Text>Then you will be responsible for the consequences.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SO_BE_IT_3">
			<Text>You will regret this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_1">
			<Text>For freeing those captives, you have my thanks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_2">
			<Text>I am appreciative for the actions you have taken on behalf of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RETURNED_CIVILIAN_3">
			<Text>Thank you. May this be remembered as a historic event which brought our two great empires closer together.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CULTURE_BOMBED_1">
			<Text>This imperialistic culture you're trying to impose upon us, it's. There's no words to what you're doing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CULTURE_BOMBED_2">
			<Text>Are you trying to start a propaganda war against my nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_BAD_1">
			<Text>Guess it's truth when they say these military folk have this code of honor. We shall meet on the battlefield, regrettably.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>In the interest of our peaceful relations, I'll believe you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_BAD_1">
			<Text>That is what I was afraid of.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_AGGRESSIVE_MILITARY_WARNING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I only hope that is indeed the case.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>It'll make sense in the future.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>They were a threat to our project.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_ATTACKED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>I remain confident that my decision was the best for my people and my nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_1">
			<Text>It seems that you cannot be reasoned with. What a shame.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_2">
			<Text>I wish you had more carefully considered your response.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_3">
			<Text>I don't appreciate that tone that you're using with me.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_RESPONSE_BAD_4">
			<Text>You know that this can only sow tension between our two nations.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- DIPLOMACY: BWN Vanilla -->
		<!-- Statements to player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>I thought you might like to know that I've launched an invasion of one of your little pet states. The lands of {@1_MinorCivName} shall trouble the cyberbolivarian revolution no more.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>Oops, it seems I've attacked your little friend {@1_MinorCivName}. Care to do something about it?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that I may have attacked {@1_MinorCivName}, a city-state under your protection. While it was not my goal to be at odds with your empire, this was deemed a necessary course of action.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_ATTACKED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>I've been informed that my empire has commenced an attack on {@1_MinorCivName}. I assure you, this was not on purpose, and hope that this does not serve to drive us apart.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EMBASSY_EXCHANGE_1">
			<Text>We should consider exchanging embassies, which would allow for more advanced diplomacy between our peoples.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_EMBASSY_OFFER_1">
			<Text>We would like to set up an embassy in your capital. What do you think?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_BULLIED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_1">
			<Text>Your bullying of {@1_MinorCivName} is intolerable. I demand that you refrain from squeezing tribute out of city-states under my protection.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_BULLIED_PROTECTED_CITY_STATE_2">
			<Text>I heard about what you did to {@1_MinorCivName}.  Did you not realize they are under my protection?  Do not provoke me further.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>We asked {@1_MinorCivName} for a tribute recently and they gave in. You promised to protect them from such things, but we both know you cannot back that up.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>Your little friend {@1_MinorCivName} is so easy to push around. They may have made fun of our nation once, but now they serve our interests quite nicely.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_1">
			<Text>It's come to my attention that I may have bullied {@1_MinorCivName}, which is under your protection. You do not put their needs above mine, I hope.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_BULLIED_YOUR_MINOR_2">
			<Text>I've been informed that my armies have taken tribute from {@1_MinorCivName}, a city-state under your protection. I assure you, this was quite unintentional, and I hope that this does not serve to drive us apart.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SAME_POLICIES_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>Warm salutations to you wise leader! I'm pleased to see you also have chosen to follow the path of Freedom. The free world will be stronger with one more nation to help us all fight against oppression!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SAME_POLICIES_ORDER_1">
			<Text>Greetings comrade! I'm pleased to see you also have chosen to follow the path of Order. Perhaps we can find some opportunities to aid each other during our empires' next 5-Year Plans!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SAME_POLICIES_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>Welcome great emperor! I'm pleased to see you have also chosen to follow the path of Autocracy. May we work together to ensure that only the very strongest nations survive to achieve true greatness!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_HOSTILE_1">
			<Text>How desperate are you to try and steal the secrets of our development? We've got nothing to hide, but that doesn't mean we will tolerate stealing!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_FRIENDLY_1">
			<Text>I am willing to overlook your recent theft of one of my technological secrets with a solemn promise that it won't happen again.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you agreed to stop this petty thieving.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_CAUGHT_YOUR_SPY_BAD_1">
			<Text>And to think I'd called you compañero once.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_STOP_SPYING_YES_1">
			<Text>As you request, our agents will not conduct operations in your territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_STOP_SPYING_NO_1">
			<Text>Our agents help keep our civilization safe from all threats, including you. They operate as we need them to, for the wellbeing of our society.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_WARNED_ABOUT_INTRIGUE_1">
			<Text>Thank you for bringing this {@1_CivAdjective} plot to our attention. With this warning, we will be ready for whatever they may try. Your generous aid will be remembered.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_DECEPTION_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is plotting against you. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_ARMY_SNEAK_ATTACK_KNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is currently marching an army to sneak attack your city of {2_CityName}. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_ARMY_SNEAK_ATTACK_UNKNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} is currently marching an army your way in a sneak attack. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_AMPHIBIOUS_SNEAK_ATTACK_KNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} embarked an army with naval escorts to sneak attack your city of {2_CityName}. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_SHARE_INTRIGUE_AMPHIBIOUS_SNEAK_ATTACK_UNKNOWN_CITY_1">
			<Text>Our spies have uncovered that {1_PlayerName} embarked an army with naval escorts in a sneak attack against your civilization. We hope that you will share any intrigue your agents discover with us.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_KILLED_YOUR_SPY_1">
			<Text>We killed your spy as it was trying to steal from us. We are always alert for those who seek to undermine the progress of our people, you know.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_KILLED_MY_SPY_1">
			<Text>I regret any confusion caused by our late agent's recent activity. Please let any hostile feelings rest with the deceased operative.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CONFRONT_YOU_KILLED_MY_SPY_1">
			<Text>I know why you've come here. I've made some faulty decisions and I'm willing to take the blame for it.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SUSPECT_YOU_OF_SPYING_1">
			<Text>I'm willing to share the vision of the future I'm building for all the people. That does not mean, however, I'm willing to tolerate any theft of our discoveries. Hope I've made this clear.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SUSPECT_YOU_OF_SPYING_2">
			<Text>There's rumours, many rumours, of your agents roaming my lands. This does not bode well for either of us, so I'd suggest to cease any subversive actions you might have planned against my nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_STOP_CONVERSIONS_1">
			<Text>We have taken notice of the religious conversions you are undertaking inside our empire. Are you trying to undermine my peaceful revolution through religious means?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_HUMAN_KILLED_MY_SPY_UNFORGIVEN_1">
			<Text>Fair enough. I'm willing to take the blame</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_HUMAN_KILLED_MY_SPY_FORGIVEN_1">
			<Text>Let us make a moment of silence for he who has fallen, and let's not talk more on the subject.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_GOOD_1">
			<Text>I'm glad you agreed to end this proselytizing.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_BAD_1">
			<Text>Sooner or later you'll learn how intrusive religion can get when it amasses enough power.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_AGREE_1">
			<Text>As you wish, our missionaries will no longer share the one true faith with the people in your cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_CONVERSIONS_DISAGREE_1">
			<Text>In spite of your protests, your citizens will continue to be enlightened by our missionaries, even though you damn your own people to live in ignorance.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_1">
			<Text>So, are you ready to capitulate yet and let us leave in peace?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_2">
			<Text>I think we've made clear the people's power. I'm willing to hear your terms.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_GREETING_WILL_ACCEPT_SURRENDER_3">
			<Text>You really underestimated the power of the people united, didn't you. I'm ready to talk peace talks.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_LIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>We were very pleased to hear your recent proposal to the {1_LeagueName}.  It seems that our goals are aligned.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_LIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} suits our interests quite nicely.  You have our sincere gratitude.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_DISLIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} is a blatant displayal of interventionism against the project I'm working on.  I shall not tolerate such attacks against the people's government.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_DISLIKE_HUMAN_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>I found your proposal to the {1_LeagueName} a subtle attack against my people.  Surely there is a better way to resolve our differences than petty politics.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Thanks to the help of your delegates, our recent proposal to the {1_LeagueName} was successful.  We look forward to your continued support, and will try to return the favor.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Our proposal to the {1_LeagueName} succeeded, with the support of your delegation.  I'm glad to know you support our crazy project.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_FOILED_OUR_PROPOSAL_1">
			<Text>Your delegation has deliberately undermining chilean efforths during the {1_LeagueName}.  I shall not tolerate this.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_FOILED_OUR_PROPOSAL_2">
			<Text>Our proposal to the {1_LeagueName} was defeated at the hands of your delegates.  We shall not support anyone who works against our Cyberbolivarian project.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_SUPPORTED_OUR_HOSTING_1">
			<Text>We thank you for entrusting the World Congress to our capable leadership.  I expect great things to come in the {1_LeagueName}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Responses to player -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>We'll see about that.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HOSTILE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Yes, that's right.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_WE_BULLIED_MINOR_BAD_1">
			<Text>I remain confident that my decision was the best for my people and my nation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_HUMAN_BULLIED_MINOR_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Very well. I'll be monitoring the situation.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_TRADE_CANT_MATCH_OFFER_1">
			<Text>We are not willing to offer you enough to make this a fair trade.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_TRADE_CANT_MATCH_OFFER_2">
			<Text>I personally believe in fair trade and I fear nothing we can offer would result in such a deal for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGINGX_1">
			<Text>We've noticed that you've been looking for cultural artifacts within our borders. This needs to stop.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGING_DISAGREE_1">
			<Text>Somebody's got to rescue those precious cultural artifacts.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_STOP_DIGGING_AGREE_1">
			<Text>I see the error on my ways, you're beholden to your own memory as we are to ours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_DIGGING_BAD_1">
			<Text>I can't but feel this is a direct affront to the people of my nation, and myself...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_RESPONSE_HUMAN_STOP_DIGGING_GOOD_1">
			<Text>Thank you for respecting the legacy of my people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DIPLO_DISCUSS_DONT_STOP_DIGGING">
			<Text>Someone shall remember the lower classes of the world. And if you don't...</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_DIPLO_DISCUSS_STOP_DIGGING">
			<Text>We only want to rescue the memory of the people, even those not in our lands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>The people of my nation have started clamoring for liberty and saying the government I've built is oppresive. The one I built for the people! Maybe I've finally seen the error of my ways.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_ORDER_1">
			<Text>Your obsession with order and quiet has permeated my society. Seems like I'll have to enact some changes around here.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_AI_BY_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>So your forcing your ideology on us with your strongarm tactics. Yet, I can see the value of a strong ally. Maybe I should adopt a variant of your ideology after all?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>Your people are clamoring for freedom. The revolution must be done through peaceful and democratic means. Freedom is the only way!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_ORDER_1">
			<Text>The workers, the people of your nation live downtrodden in an unrepresentative state. Order must be imposed in your civilization!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_CIVIL_RESISTANCE_ON_HUMAN_BY_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>Your people are getting manipulated by imperialistic complots. They need a strong, centralized government to guide them. Autocracy is the way.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SWITCHED_TO_FREEDOM_1">
			<Text>We must not sacrifice the liberties and rights we've granted to our citizens. Our revolution can be, must be, enacted through the path of Freedom. Glad you can join me in this journey.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SWITCHED_TO_ORDER_1">
			<Text>We fight for the revolution of the people compañero! Welcome to the true way of the future comrade, welcome to the Order ideology!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_SWITCHED_TO_AUTOCRACY_1">
			<Text>Sometimes hard choices have to be made fellow leader. Freedom and Order have both taken their toll, but if what you want is true success and wellbeing for your people, you must centralize. Autocracy is the way.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE_INFLUENTIAL_ON_HUMAN_1">
			<Text>I see that the culture of my nation has become very popular in your country. Hopefully you get what's the actual meaning of the word compañero now!</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>