<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- I was generated by Protroid's Leader.xml Generator! -->
<GameData>
	<Leaders>
		<Row>
			<Type>LEADER_ALLENDE</Type>
			<Description>TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE</Description>
			<CivilopediaTag>TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE</CivilopediaTag>
			<ArtDefineTag>Allende_Leaderscene.xml</ArtDefineTag>
			<VictoryCompetitiveness>8</VictoryCompetitiveness>
			<WonderCompetitiveness>7</WonderCompetitiveness>
			<MinorCivCompetitiveness>6</MinorCivCompetitiveness>
			<Boldness>7</Boldness>
			<DiploBalance>5</DiploBalance>
			<WarmongerHate>9</WarmongerHate>
			<WorkAgainstWillingness>3</WorkAgainstWillingness>
			<WorkWithWillingness>7</WorkWithWillingness>
			<DoFWillingness>9</DoFWillingness>
			<Loyalty>8</Loyalty>
			<Neediness>8</Neediness>
			<Forgiveness>7</Forgiveness>
			<Chattiness>6</Chattiness>
			<Meanness>4</Meanness>
			<PortraitIndex>1</PortraitIndex>
			<IconAtlas>CIV_COLOR_ATLAS_ALLENDE</IconAtlas>
		</Row>
	</Leaders>
	<Leader_MajorCivApproachBiases>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_WAR</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>3</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_HOSTILE</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>4</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_DECEPTIVE</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>2</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_GUARDED</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>4</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_AFRAID</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>6</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_FRIENDLY</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>8</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MajorCivApproachType>MAJOR_CIV_APPROACH_NEUTRAL</MajorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>5</Bias>
		</Row>
	</Leader_MajorCivApproachBiases>
	<Leader_MinorCivApproachBiases>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_IGNORE</MinorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>4</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_FRIENDLY</MinorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>7</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_PROTECTIVE</MinorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>8</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_CONQUEST</MinorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>2</Bias>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<MinorCivApproachType>MINOR_CIV_APPROACH_BULLY</MinorCivApproachType>
			<Bias>1</Bias>
		</Row>
	</Leader_MinorCivApproachBiases>
	<Leader_Flavors>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_OFFENSE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>4</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_DEFENSE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_CITY_DEFENSE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>5</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_MILITARY_TRAINING</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>4</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_RECON</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>5</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_RANGED</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_MOBILE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>8</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL_RECON</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL_GROWTH</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_NAVAL_TILE_IMPROVEMENT</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>9</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_AIR</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_EXPANSION</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>5</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_GROWTH</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>8</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_TILE_IMPROVEMENT</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_INFRASTRUCTURE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>9</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_PRODUCTION</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_GOLD</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>4</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_SCIENCE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_CULTURE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>10</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_HAPPINESS</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_GREAT_PEOPLE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>9</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_WONDER</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_RELIGION</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>4</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_DIPLOMACY</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>8</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_SPACESHIP</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_WATER_CONNECTION</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_NUKE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>5</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_USE_NUKE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>6</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_ANTIAIR</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>4</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_AIR_CARRIER</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>1</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_ESPIONAGE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_ARCHAEOLOGY</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>8</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_LAND_TRADE_ROUTE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>5</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_SEA_TRADE_ROUTE</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_TRADE_ORIGIN</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>7</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_I_TRADE_DESTINATION</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>8</Flavor>
		</Row>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<FlavorType>FLAVOR_AIRLIFT</FlavorType>
			<Flavor>10</Flavor>
		</Row>
	</Leader_Flavors>
	<Leader_Traits>
		<Row>
			<LeaderType>LEADER_ALLENDE</LeaderType>
			<TraitType>TRAIT_PROGRESS_WITHOUT_CONSESSIONS</TraitType>
		</Row>
	</Leader_Traits>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALLENDE">
			<Text>Salvador Allende</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Salvador Guillermo Allende Gossens was a Chilean physician and politician, known as the first Marxist to become president of a Latin American country through open elections.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Early Life</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>Allende was born on 26 June 1908 in Santiago de Chile. He was the son of Salvador Allende Castro and Laura Gossens Uribe. Allende's family belonged to the Chilean upper middle class and had a long tradition of political involvement in progressive and liberal causes. His grandfather was a prominent physician and a social reformist who founded one of the first secular schools in Chile. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Allende attended high school at the Liceo Eduardo de la Barra in Valparaíso. As a teenager, his main intellectual and political influence came from the shoe-maker Juan De Marchi, an Italian-born anarchist. Allende was a talented athlete in his youth, being a member of the Everton de Viña del Mar sports club (named after the more famous English football club of the same name), where he is said to have excelled at the long jump. Allende then graduated with a medical degree in 1933 from the University of Chile. During his time at medical school Allende was influenced by Professor Max Westenhofer, a German pathologist who stressed on the social determinants of disease and social medicine.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Political Involvement Before Presidency</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Allende co-founded a section of the Socialist Party of Chile in Valparaiso and became its chairman. In 1938, Allende was in charge of the electoral campaign of the Popular Front headed by Pedro Aguirre Cerda.[12] The Popular Front's slogan was "Bread, a Roof and Work!" After its electoral victory, he became Minister of Health in the Reformist Popular Front government which was dominated by the Radicals. While serving in this position, Allende was responsible for the passage of a wide range of progressive social reforms, including safety laws protecting workers in the factories, higher pensions for widows, maternity care, and free lunch programmes for schoolchildren. Following President Aguirre Cerda's death in 1941, he was again elected deputy while the Popular Front was renamed Democratic Alliance. During the Fifties, Allende introduced legislation that established the Chilean national health service, the first program in the Americas to guarantee universal health care. He became president of the Chilean Senate in 1966. His three unsuccessful bids for the presidency (in the 1952, 1958 and 1964 elections) prompted Allende to joke that his epitaph would be "Here lies the next President of Chile." In 1952, as candidate for the Frente de Acción Popular (Popular Action Front, FRAP), he obtained only 5.4% of the votes, partly due to a division within socialist ranks over support for Carlos Ibáñez. In 1958, again as the FRAP candidate, Allende obtained 28.5% of the vote. This time, his defeat was attributed to votes lost to the populist Antonio Zamorano. His three unsuccessful bids for the presidency (in the 1952, 1958 and 1964 elections) prompted Allende to joke that his epitaph would be "Here lies the next President of Chile." In 1952, as candidate for the Frente de Acción Popular (Popular Action Front, FRAP), he obtained only 5.4% of the votes, partly due to a division within socialist ranks over support for Carlos Ibáñez. In 1958, again as the FRAP candidate, Allende obtained 28.5% of the vote. This time, his defeat was attributed to votes lost to the populist Antonio Zamorano.His three unsuccessful bids for the presidency (in the 1952, 1958 and 1964 elections) prompted Allende to joke that his epitaph would be "Here lies the next President of Chile." In 1952, as candidate for the Frente de Acción Popular (Popular Action Front, FRAP), he obtained only 5.4% of the votes, partly due to a division within socialist ranks over support for Carlos Ibáñez. In 1958, again as the FRAP candidate, Allende obtained 28.5% of the vote. This time, his defeat was attributed to votes lost to the populist Antonio Zamorano.His three unsuccessful bids for the presidency (in the 1952, 1958 and 1964 elections) prompted Allende to joke that his epitaph would be "Here lies the next President of Chile." In 1952, as candidate for the Frente de Acción Popular (Popular Action Front, FRAP), he obtained only 5.4% of the votes, partly due to a division within socialist ranks over support for Carlos Ibáñez. In 1958, again as the FRAP candidate, Allende obtained 28.5% of the vote. This time, his defeat was attributed to votes lost to the populist Antonio Zamorano.His three unsuccessful bids for the presidency (in the 1952, 1958 and 1964 elections) prompted Allende to joke that his epitaph would be "Here lies the next President of Chile." In 1952, as candidate for the Frente de Acción Popular (Popular Action Front, FRAP), he obtained only 5.4% of the votes, partly due to a division within socialist ranks over support for Carlos Ibáñez. In 1958, again as the FRAP candidate, Allende obtained 28.5% of the vote. This time, his defeat was attributed to votes lost to the populist Antonio Zamorano. His three unsuccessful bids for the presidency (in the 1952, 1958 and 1964 elections) prompted Allende to joke that his epitaph would be "Here lies the next President of Chile." In 1952, as candidate for the Frente de Acción Popular (Popular Action Front, FRAP), he obtained only 5.4% of the votes, partly due to a division within socialist ranks over support for Carlos Ibáñez. In 1958, again as the FRAP candidate, Allende obtained 28.5% of the vote. This time, his defeat was attributed to votes lost to the populist Antonio Zamorano. Declassified documents show that from 1962 through 1964, the CIA spent a total of $2.6 million to finance the campaign of Eduardo Frei and spent $3 million in anti-Allende propaganda "to scare voters away from Allende's FRAP coalition". The CIA considered its role in the victory of Frei a great success.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Presidency and Death</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Upon assuming power, Allende began to carry out his platform of implementing a socialist programme called La vía chilena al socialismo ("the Chilean Path to Socialism"). This included nationalization of large-scale industries (notably copper mining and banking), and government administration of the health care system, educational system, a programme of free milk for children in the schools and shanty towns of Chile, and an expansion of the land seizure and redistribution already begun under his predecessor Eduardo Frei Montalva,who had nationalized between one-fifth and one-quarter of all the properties listed for takeover. Allende also intended to improve the socio-economic welfare of Chile's poorest citizens; a key element was to provide employment, either in the new nationalized enterprises or on public work projects.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Allende’s first step in early 1971 was to raise minimum wages (in real terms) for blue-collar workers by 37%–41% and 8%–10% for white-collar workers. Educational, food, and housing assistance was significantly expanded, with public-housing starts going up twelvefold and eligibility for free milk extended from age 6 to age 15. A year later, blue-collar wages were raised by 27% in real terms and white-collar wages became fully indexed.[44] Price controls were also set up, while the Allende Government introduced a system of distribution networks through various agencies (including local committees on supply and prices) to ensure that the new rules were adhered to by shopkeepers.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Particularly in rural areas, the Allende Government launched a campaign against illiteracy, while adult education programs expanded, together with educational opportunities for workers. From 1971 through to 1973, enrollments in kindergarten, primary, secondary, and postsecondary schools all increased. The Allende Government encouraged more doctors to begin their practices in rural and low-income urban areas, and built additional hospitals, maternity clinics, and especially neighborhood health centers that remained open longer hours to serve the poor. Improved sanitation and housing facilities for low-income neighborhoods also equalized health care benefits, while hospital councils and local health councils were established in neighborhood health centers as a means of democratizing the administration of health policies. These councils gave central government civil servants, local government officials, health service employees, and community workers the right to review budgetary decisions.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Allende government also sought to bring the arts (both serious and popular) to the mass of the Chilean population by funding a number of cultural endeavours. With eighteen-year-olds and illiterates now granted the right to vote, mass participation in decision-making was encouraged by the Allende government, with traditional hierarchical structures now challenged by socialist egalitarianism. The Allende Government was able to draw upon the idealism of its supporters, with teams of "Allendistas" travelling into the countryside and shanty towns to perform volunteer work. The Allende Government also worked to transform Chilean popular culture through formal changes to school curriculum and through broader cultural education initiatives, such as state-sponsored music festivals and tours of Chilean folklorists and nueva canción musicians. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Social spending was dramatically increased, particularly for housing, education, and health, while a major effort was made to redistribute wealth to poorer Chileans. As a result of new initiatives in nutrition and health, together with higher wages, many poorer Chileans were able to feed themselves and clothe themselves better than they had been able to before. Public access to the social security system was increased, while state benefits such as family allowances were raised significantly. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] Allende also undertook Project Cybersyn, a system of networked telex machines and computers. Cybersyn was developed by British cybernetics expert Stafford Beer. The network was supposed to transmit data from factories to the government in Santiago, allowing for economic planning in real time. [NEWLINE][NEWLINE] n August 1973, a constitutional crisis occurred, and the Supreme Court of Chile publicly complained about the inability of Allende government to enforce the law of the land. On 22 August, the Chamber of Deputies (with the Christian Democrats uniting with the National Party) accused the government of unconstitutional acts through Allende's refusal to promulgate constitutional amendments, already approved by the Chamber, which would have prevented his government from continuing his massive nationalization plan and called upon the military to enforce constitutional order. On 26 May 1973, the Supreme Court of Chile unanimously denounced the Allende government's disruption of the legality of the nation in its failure to uphold judicial decisions, because of its continual refusal to permit police execution of judicial decisions contrary to the government's own measures. In early September 1973, Allende floated the idea of resolving the constitutional crisis with a plebiscite. His speech outlining such a solution was scheduled for September 11, but he was never able to deliver it. On September 11, 1973, the Chilean military, aided by the United States and its Central Intelligence Agency CIA, staged a coup against Allende. Allende gave his farewell speech to Chileans on live radio, speaking of himself in the past tense, of his love for Chile and of his deep faith in its future. He stated that his commitment to Chile did not allow him to take an easy way out, and he would not be used as a propaganda tool by those he called "traitors" (he refused an offer of safe passage), clearly implying he intended to fight to the end.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Judgement of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Memorials to Allende include a statue in front of the Palacio de la Moneda. The placement of the statue was not without controversy, as it is located facing the eastern edge of the Plaza de la Ciudadanía, this plaza containing memorials to a number of Chilean heroes. However, the statue is not located in the plaza, but rather on a surrounding sidewalk and facing an entrance to the plaza. Another monument has been built in Montreal Canada and the tourist port of Managua in Nicaragua is also named after him. A great wealth of documentaries and movies have been created around his life, as well as numerous books, plays, songs and even a beetle species. Allende is often seen as a Martyr figure, a man who fought for his ideals and the  well-being of the less fortunate, but whose allies and particularly his political enemies finally led to his untimely demise. He his, in the end, a symbol of the victims of the Cold War and foreign intervention in Latin America.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIALEADER_ALLENDE_LIVED">
			<Text>1908 - 1973</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>
