<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Language_en_US>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_US_BRANDENBURG_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_US_BRANDENBURG_DESC">
			<Text>Margraviate of Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_US_BRANDENBURG_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The story of Brandenburg's meteoric rise from a hastily assembled march on the edge of christendom, to the foremost state of German politics is so interesting chiefly because it didn't rely on luck or a wealth of natural resources - not on surprise marriages, accidental discoveries or convenient placement. It relied almosty entirely on grit, discipline and hard, hard work. Brandenburg's armies propelled the tiny march to the forefront of European politics, eventually taking the title of 'Prussia' and unifying the German states into an Empire that would tear Europe to pieces (albeit, it did tear itself apart in the process, but its all still mighty impressive)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Geography</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_2">
			<Text>The landscape of present-day Brandenburg is very much the product of glaciation. Most of the state consists of a sandy plain that is interspersed with numerous fertile areas and stretches of pine and fir forests. Because of its sandy soils, it was formerly popularly known as the “sandbox of the Holy Roman Empire.” It is, however, traversed by tributaries of the Elbe and Oder rivers and boasts more than 3,000 lakes. About half of the state’s area is used for agriculture, and roughly another one-third of the region is covered by forests. The Lower Oder Valley National Park, established in 1995 in the northeasternmost part of Brandenburg, is part of a joint Polish-German effort to help preserve the region’s distinctive flora and fauna. Ironically, the ecology of the region benefited from decades of the relative economic neglect of the area. The state lies wholly within the North European Plain and has a moderate climate, determined both by maritime influences, which predominate in areas to the west, and by continental influences, which affect the east.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Early Inhabitants</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_3">
			<Text>The earliest known inhabitants of Brandenburg were the Germanic Semnones tribe, a branch of the larger Suebi peoples. Little is known about them, though it is thought that they may have been absorbed into the Alemanii confederation in th late 3rd century AD. The Semnones probably worshipped an early form of the religion that would grow into Odin worship - Tacitus describes a custom involving a Grove of Fetters in which chained adherents would conduct human sacrifice and walk around the grove until collapsing, at which point it was illegal to help the adherent to his feet. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] During the great migrations, the Semonones were replaced by Polabian Slavs - referred to as Wends in the historic sources. Though the Slavs were dominated and steadily germanised by the Saxons and Danes about the 9th and 10th century, they remained politically independent and culturally separate from their neighbours. Despite the establishment of many Germanic states, a massive revolt in 993 forced the Germans out and reestablished Slavic dominance in the region. Despite the newfound independence, the Slavs faced enormous pressure from Polish and Danish incursions. Noticing the weakness of the Wendish states, the German Emperor Lothar granted Albert I 'The Bear' the title 'Margrave of the North' and commanded him to christianise and colonise Brandenburg starting in 1106.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Taming of Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_4">
			<Text>By the early 12th century, the Archbishoprics of Bremen, Magdeburg and Gniezno sought the conversion of the pagan Slavs to Christianity through peaceful means: notable missionaries included Vicelin, Norbert of Xanten, and Otto of Bamberg (sent to Pomerania by Bolesław III Wrymouth of Poland). Lacking support from the Salian dynasty of the Holy Roman Empire, secular Saxon princes seeking Slavic territory found themselves in a military stalemate with their adversaries. Christians, especially Saxons from Holstein, and pagans raided each other across the Limes Saxonicus, usually for tribute. Despite this, the peaceful approach yielded some minor successes; in 1124 and 1128, the Pomeranians and Lutici were baptised, respectively. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] Eventually however, the peace broke down and a crusade was called against the heathen slavs. The fall of Edessa in 1144 shocked Christendom, causing Pope Eugenius III and St. Bernard of Clairvaux to preach a Second Crusade to reinforce Outremer. While many south Germans volunteered to crusade in the Middle East, the north German Saxons were reluctant. They told Bernard of their desire to campaign against the Slavs at a Reichstag meeting in Frankfurt on 13 March 1147. Approving of the Saxons' plan, pope Eugenius issued a papal bull known as the Divina dispensatione on 13 April; there was to be no difference between the spiritual rewards of the different crusaders. Those who volunteered to crusade against the Slavic pagans were primarily Danes, Saxons, and Poles, although there were also some Bohemians. The German monarchy took no part in the crusade, which was led by Saxon families such as the Ascanians, Wettin, and Schauenburgers. Papal legate Anselm of Havelberg was placed in overall command. With bloody victories on 11 June 1157, Albert the Bear was able to reconquer Brandenburg and found a new lordship. Because he already held the title of margrave of the North, Albert styled himself as Margrave of Brandenburg (Adelbertus Dei gratia marchio in Brandenborch) on 3 October 1157, thereby beginning the Margraviate of Brandenburg. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] After Albert's death in 1170, his son succeeded him as Otto I, Margrave of Brandenburg. The Ascanians pursued a policy of expanding to the east and the northeast with the goal of connecting their territories through Pomerania to the Baltic Sea. This policy brought them into conflict with the Kingdom of Denmark. After the Battle of Bornhöved (1227), Margrave John I staked his claim to Pomerania, receiving it as a fief from Emperor Frederick II in 1231. The middle of the 13th century was a time of important developments for the Ascanian House, as it won Stettin (Szczecin) and the Uckermark (1250), although the former was later lost to the Duchy of Pomerania. Henry II, the last Ascanian margrave, died in 1320. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] Eventually, the Luxembourgs, eager to secure a new electorate under their control to increase their control of the empire, purchased the March of Brandenburg for 500,000 guilders and declared it the Electorate of Brandenburg. Though the Luxembourgs neglected this territory, the local nobility increased in power, resulting in a fairly powerful internal situation by the time the Luxembourgs collapsed and the state was granted to the House of Hohenzollern, who would hold it as their primary posession until 1918.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Brandenburg and the Reformation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Brandenburg accepted the reformation in 1539 and the Hohenzollern became determined to expand their power base as much as possible through both conquest and marriage. A series of devestating wars with Pommerania and Sweden brought eastern Pommerania into Brandenburg's control and a series of strategic alliances and marriages brough Cleves and Prussia into the fold (albeit with Prussia remaining a Polish fief, requiring the electors to pay tribute to the Polish King). Despite her precarious position in the thirty years war, on the edge of lutheran territory and spread across a series of unconnected territories, Brandenburg was able to secure significant territory in the peace of westphalia, including western Pommerania.  In the second half of the 17th century, Frederick William, the "Great Elector", developed Brandenburg-Prussia into a major power. The state constructed Brandenburg's first navy (Kurbrandenburgische Marine), leading to short-lived colonies at Arguin, the Brandenburger Gold Coast, and Saint Thomas. The electors succeeded in acquiring full sovereignty over Prussia in the treaties of Wehlau and Bromberg in 1657.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Kingdom of Prussia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_6">
			<Text>
				In return for aiding Emperor Leopold I during the War of the Spanish Succession, Frederick William's son, Frederick III, was allowed to elevate Prussia to the status of a kingdom. On 18 January 1701, Frederick crowned himself Frederick I, King in Prussia. Prussia, unlike Brandenburg, lay outside the Holy Roman Empire, within which only the emperor and the ruler of Bohemia could call themselves king. As king was a more prestigious title than prince-elector, the territories of the Hohenzollerns became known as the Kingdom of Prussia, although their power base remained in Brandenburg.  [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE]  Legally, Brandenburg was still part of the Holy Roman Empire, ruled by the Hohenzollerns in personal union with the Prussian kingdom over which they were fully sovereign. For this reason, the Hohenzollerns continued to use the additional title of Elector of Brandenburg for the remainder of the empire's run. However, by this time the emperor's authority over the empire had become merely nominal. The various territories of the empire acted more or less as de facto sovereign states, and only acknowledged the emperor's overlordship over them in a formal way. For this reason, Brandenburg soon came to be treated as de facto part of the Prussian kingdom rather than a separate entity.  [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE]  From 1701 to 1946, Brandenburg's history was largely that of the state of Prussia, which established itself as a major power in Europe during the 18th century. King Frederick William I of Prussia, the "Soldier-King", modernized the Prussian Army, while his son Frederick the Great achieved glory and infamy with the Silesian Wars and Partitions of Poland. The feudal designation of the Margraviate of Brandenburg ended with the dissolution of the Holy Roman Empire in 1806, which made the Hohenzollerns de jure as well as de facto sovereigns over it. It was replaced with the Province of Brandenburg in 1815 following the Napoleonic Wars. Brandenburg, along with the rest of Prussia, became part of the German Empire in 1871 during the Prussian-led unification of Germany.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Germany and Onwards</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5PEDIA_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT_7">
			<Text>
				Brandenburg remained the core of the Kingdom of Prussia, and it was the site of the kingdom's capitals, Berlin and Potsdam. When Prussia was subdivided into provinces in 1815, the territory of the Margraviate of Brandenburg became the Province of Brandenburg, again subdivided into the government regions of Frankfurt and Potsdam. In 1881, the City of Berlin was separated from the Province of Brandenburg. However, industrial towns ringing Berlin lay within Brandenburg, and the growth of the region's industrial economy brought an increase in the population of the province. The Province of Brandenburg had an area of 39,039 km2 (15,073 sq mi) and a population of 2.6 million (1925). After World War II, the Neumark, the part of Brandenburg east of the Oder-Neisse Line, was transferred to Poland; and its native German population expelled. The remainder of the province became a state in the Soviet Zone of occupation in Germany when Prussia was dissolved in 1947. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] Since the foundation of East Germany in 1949 Brandenburg formed one of its component states. The State of Brandenburg was completely dissolved in 1952 by the Socialist government of East Germany, doing away with all component states. The East German government then divided Brandenburg among several Bezirke or districts. (See Administrative division of the German Democratic Republic). Most of Brandenburg lay within the Bezirke of Cottbus, Frankfurt, or Potsdam, but parts of the former province passed to the Schwerin, Neubrandenburg and Magdeburg districts (town Havelberg). East Germany relied heavily on lignite (the lowest grade of coal) as an energy source, and lignite strip mines marred areas of southeastern Brandenburg. The industrial towns surrounding Berlin were important to the East German economy, while rural Brandenburg remained mainly agricultural. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE]  The present State of Brandenburg was re-established on 3 October 1990 upon German reunification. The newly elected Landtag of Brandenburg first met on 26 October 1990.As in other former parts of East Germany, the lack of modern infrastructure and exposure to West Germany's competitive market economy brought widespread unemployment and economic difficulty. In the recent years, however, Brandenburg's infrastructure has been modernized and unemployment has slowly declined. 
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- City Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_1">
			<Text>Berlin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_2">
			<Text>Potsdam</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_3">
			<Text>Königsberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_4">
			<Text>Cottbus</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_5">
			<Text>Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_6">
			<Text>Frankfurt </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_7">
			<Text>Oranienburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_8">
			<Text>Falkensee</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_9">
			<Text>Kleve</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_10">
			<Text>Allenstein</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_11">
			<Text>Eberswalde</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_12">
			<Text>Bernau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_13">
			<Text>Königs Wusterhausen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_14">
			<Text>Spree</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_15">
			<Text>Neuruppin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_16">
			<Text>Neuenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_17">
			<Text>Essen</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_18">
			<Text>Heilsberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_19">
			<Text>Braunsberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_20">
			<Text>Magdeburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_21">
			<Text>Preussisch-Eylau</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_22">
			<Text>Kustrin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_23">
			<Text>Ludwigsfelde</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_24">
			<Text>Hennigsdorf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_25">
			<Text>Finsterwalde</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_26">
			<Text>Wittenberge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CITY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_27">
			<Text>Strausberg</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Spy Names -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_9">
			<Text>Grossman</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_8">
			<Text>Mielke</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_7">
			<Text>Munsinger</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_6">
			<Text>Wolf</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_5">
			<Text>Schwarz</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_4">
			<Text>Croissant</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_3">
			<Text>Jokisalo</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_2">
			<Text>Rusi</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_1">
			<Text>Dorschel</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_SPY_NAME_US_BRANDENBURG_0">
			<Text>Bunke</Text>
			<Gender>feminine</Gender>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_LEADER_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_DESC">
			<Text>Frederick William I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Frederick William I, German Friedrich Wilhelm I (born August 14, 1688, Berlin—died May 31, 1740, Potsdam, Prussia), was the second Prussian king, who transformed his country from a second-rate power into the efficient and prosperous state that his son and successor, Frederick II the Great, made a major military power on the Continent.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_HEADING_2">
			<Text>The Prince</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TEXT_2">
			<Text>
				Frederick William was born on August 14, 1688, a few months after the death of his grandfather, the Great Elector, after whom he was named. While he was still a small child, his 1st governess, Marthe de Montbail, was frightened out of her wits by his strange behaviour. Once, obstinately refusing to spit out a silver shoe buckle in his mouth, 4-year-old Frederick William swallowed it, either accidentally, or for spite; a physician finally got it out of him. On another occasion, the young Prince threatened to let himself fall 3 stories out of the window unless his governess let him have his way. Ordered to put on a gold brocade dressing gown one morning, little Frederick William threw it into the fire. He was just as obstinate when it came to his studies. The only things he liked as a boy were drilling soldiers and economics. He saved his pocket money to form a company of cadets whom he drilled himself. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] Frederick William's father, Frederick I (1657-1713), was the first King of Prussia. Although he was the newest and the least important of all European Kings, he modelled himself upon the most important, Louis XIV "The Sun King" of France. Frederick copied him slavishly, and - although he loved Frederick William's mother dearly - he took a mistress because he thought it the correct thing for a monarch to do. Loving all forms of pomp and the outward display of riches, his finances were always in a disastrous state. Young Frederick William, however, was very different. In 1711, he presented his father with evidence of financial  mismanagement and the Prime Minister was sacked. When Frederick I died two years later, Frederick William gave him a magnificent funeral and then started to reduce the Royal expenses drastically.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_HEADING_3">
			<Text>The King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Like everyone else, Frederick William paid the consumer taxt he himself had imposed, and no candles were left burning at court. He lived frugally and worked hard and tirelessly for the welfare of his people. He encouraged farming, reclaimed marshes, stored grain in good times and sold it in bad times. He dictated a manual of Regulations for State Officials, containing 35 chapters and 297 paragraphs in which every public servant in Prussia could find his duties precisely set out. A minister or councillor failing to attend a committee meeting would lose six months' pay. If he absented himself a second time, he would be discharged from the Royal service. No inspections were to take place during the ploughing season or the harvest, when the farmers would have no time to spare. The manual was supplemented by further instructions drawn up in person by Frederick William, prescribing methods of ploughing, erecting earthworks as a protection against flooding, and hunting wolves. Market women should not sit idle at their stalls but were to busy themselves knitting stockings. Any parson preaching for over one hour would be fined. Frederick William tore what he considered "extravagant finery" off the clothes of females in the street and he used to discipline idle building workers in person. It is said that he once gave chase in the street to an escaping pickpocket. Having caught him, the King asked why he had tried to run away. When the man replied that he was afraid of him, Frederick William hit him with his stick and roared: "Miserable wretch! You shall love me!" [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] At times, he was acutely mentally disturbed and his temper became completely uncontrollable. The most frequent victim of his outbursts was his son Fritz. Whenever they happened to meet, in private or in public, Frederick William would suddenly seize him by the throat and throw him to the ground, force him to kiss his boots and beg forgiveness. Then he would say: "If my father had treated me like this, I would have put an end to my life long ago. But you have no courage." Fritz complained to his sister Wilhelmine: "Every day here we go through the most unutterable scenes. I am so tired of it all. I would rather beg my bread than go on living like this." When Fritz attempted to flee with his best friend and likely lover, Hermann Von katt, his father had the boy executed and forced Fritz to watch - remarking that he should have killed Fritz as well.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_HEADING_4">
			<Text>The Soldier</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Frederick William had a passion for all things military. He gave Prussia an enormous army; one in every nine men in Prussia was a soldier and another 40000 men were foreign mercenaries. Prince Leopold of Anhalt-Dessau (1676-1747, to the right), a remarkable soldier and strategist, helped to turn the army into a first-class fighting machine. He attached bayonets to the outside of the muskets and replaced the wooden ramrod with one made of iron, which was more reliable enabling faster loading of muskets and faster charging after firing. In addition, the "Old Dessauer"  invented the marching step; marching in formation made an uncanny impression on foreigners used to the uncoordinated movements of their own troops. The discipline in Prussia's army was high due to the quality of the officers. Frederick William did not sell commissions to the highest bidder, as was custom, but gave them to members of the aristocracy strictly according to merit. In addition, the King believed in harsh discipline with flogging and executions as punishments for misbehaviour. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE]  Prussia supported Austria in a military campaign in 1734 and Frederick William, although troubled by gout, visited the men in the field. He had always taken pride in living with them as an ordinary officer, but the chaos prevailing in the Austrian army made him nearly sick with rage. As a result of the emotional stress he got heart trouble and acute attacks of dropsy and gout. His face took on a bluish-red colour, he had trouble breathing and speaking and was feverish. He could not walk or sleep; his legs were painful and hideously swollen up. He had spasms in the stomach, pains in the chest and a burning sensation in his abdomen. The doctors despaired and Frederick William prepared Fritz to take over the reigns of government, but within a few weeks he recovered sufficiently to be able to ride a horse, beat his servants and fulminate against his son. Still, he had been permanently weakened by his illness.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_HEADING_5">
			<Text>The Legacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Near the end of his life, Frederick William had become extremely fat with a weight of 123 kg. He was a short man with a big head on a short neck and his belly had increased to a width of 225 cm. Dropsy made his body swell even more and he was forced to use a wheel chair. As a diversion he liked to paint and he used to sign his paintings with "In tormentis pinxit" (painted in pain). During his final illness, Fritz suggested summoning an eminent doctor, but Frederick William retorted that his own physician could kill him without assistance. He was constantly tortured by horrible pains, dropsy and gout. In March 1740 he suffered from a "constant burning sensation and cruel pains in the intestines". In May he gave precise instructions for his funeral. Early in the morning of May 31, Frederick William had himself wheeled into the Queen's apartments and said to her: "Get up! I am going to die today." Then he was wheeled back to his own room and ordered the horses to be brought out of the Royal stables in front of his window. Hours passed while Frederick William gradually got worse and died. He was succeeded by his son, Fritz, who became known as Frederick the Great. [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] Frederick inherited his fathers enormous military and went on to smash the conventional European powers in a series of conflicts, rising Prussia to one of the greatest powers on the continent. Though Old Fritz was a truly remarkeable man and a brilliant strategist, it is hard to argue that any of his accomplishments would have been possible without the state his father had built. Because of this, Frederick William was largely responsible for the rise of Prussia and thus the eventual unification of Germany. Despite being irritable, gouty and truly hellish to his son Fritz, Prussia owes its status to this bizarre man. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_LIVED">
			<Text>1688 - 1740</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_NAME">
			<Text>Friedrich Wilhelm I</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Margrave of Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TITLES_2">
			<Text>King in Prussia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TITLES_1">
			<Text>Margrave of Brandenburg</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVILOPEDIA_LEADERS_US_FREDERICK_WILLIAM_TITLES_3">
			<Text>Soldier King</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DAWN_OF_MAN_US_BRANDENBURG_TEXT">
			<Text>Margrave, King, Soldier - by any name we greet thee, Frederick William I of Brandenburg. You lead the lands of Brandenburg-Prussia - a small North German state in a sea of small, insignificant nations. Yet, against this, Brandenburg came to dominate the region through its famously potent military and prudent rulers. Upon your ascendence, you sold the horses, jewels and furniture of your fathers reign to enrich the state and invested it back into the military and judicial systems - intending to spend more of your tenure squatting in military camps than basking in opulent palaces. True to this initial commitment you built the Prussian army into the most formidable in Germany, using it to secure Brandenburg's interests in wars with Sweden and Great Britain. Upon your death, Brandenburg had ascended from a minor march in the pantheon of German duchies, marches and principalities into one of central Europe's foremost powers. With this gift, your descendents went on to form the mighty Prussian kingdom which dominated German poltics for centuries, eventually unifying the German people into a mighty Empire.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Mighty Soldier-King, the people of your nation cry out for your firm leadership - for a gun in their hands and a marching song upon their lips. Can you be a king with the courage to stand at the head of Europe's greatest weapon, and a margrave with the strength to turn that weapon on those who deserve it? Can you throw aside decadence and profligacy in exchange for blood and steel? Can you build a civilisation to stand the test of time?  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_US_BRANDENBURG_SHORT">
			<Text>Union of Black and Scarlet</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_US_BRANDENBURG">
			<Text>Adopting [ICON_CULTURE] Policies hurries the [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production of units and grants bonus [ICON_MOVES] Movement to all units for five turns. Units generate [ICON_CULTURE] culture equal to their [ICON_WAR] experience when trained.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_GIANTS">
			<Text>Potsdam Giant</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_GIANTS_CIVILOPEDIA">
			<Text>The Potsdam Giants, affectionately nicknamed the Lange Kerls or 'Tall Guys' in Germany, were a regiment of taller than average Prussian soldiers which fought for Brandenburg-Prussia from 1675 until disbanded in 1806. Though founded by prince Frederick I of Prussia, the regiment became an important part of Frederick-William's reign. He collected the tallest men from all over the country - the minimum height required was 6 feet, well above average for the time. (The King himself was only about 5'2") As the King's obsession grew, foreign nations worked out that they could encourage friendly relations by sending their tallest soldiers to Germany for Frederick-William's private collection. Soldiers from Russia, Ireland, Turkey, Austria and Germany all served in the regiment, united only by their abnormal stature. The King adored his regiment of giants - he would paint them from memory, demand to see them march when he felt ill, showed them off whenever new people came to Brandenburg and even got them a trained bear to march with them. The usually strict and indifferent man admitted the seriousness of his love to a French ambassador, saying "The most beautiful girl or woman in the world would be a matter of indifference to me, but tall soldiers—they are my weakness." [NEWLINE] [NEWLINE] Frederick I, Frederick-Wilhelm's son, didn't love the regiment quite as much, shrinking the regiment and distributing most of its more talented soldiers to other units. When the Lange Kerls surrendered in 1806 to napoleonic forces, they were disbanded and this bizarre anecdote of Prussian military history came to an end.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BRANDENBURG_UA">
			<Text>Maneuver Warfare</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_GIANTS_HELP">
			<Text>Grants combat strength bonuses to nearby units based off of its level</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_GIANTS">
			<Text>Lange Kerls</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_US_BRANDENBURG_UA_HELP">
			<Text>Extra Movement and Ignores Movement Point Terrain Costs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_GIANTS_HELP">
			<Text>The Potsdam Giant grants a 5% combat boost to adjacent units after its first promotion, rising to 15% after its third and 25% after its fifth. Level 5 and above Giants may be expended in cities to permenantly boost the experience of units trained there.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_US_GIANTS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Potsdam Giant, unlike most unique units, is fairly ordinary until its first promotion - after which it grants a small boost to nearby units. The Giant really begins to excel as it climbs the promotion tree, potentially granting an enormous 25% boost to nearby units once promoted enough. Once your giants are ready to retire, expend them in cities to permenantly increase units experience, which means more culture from the UA! Make sure to keep your giants in the thick of it to maximise their experience gain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KANTONE">
			<Text>Kantone</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KANTONE_PEDIA">
			<Text>The Canton System (German: Kantonsystem or Kantonssystem) or Canton Regulation (Kantonreglement) was a system of recruitment used by the Prussian army between 1733 and 1813. The country was divided into recruiting districts called cantons (Kantone), and each canton was the responsibility of a regiment. The system was a Prussian distinctive. Every male was from the youngest possible age enrolled in the army, and by 1740, the end of Frederick-Wilhelms reign, the Prussian army, with a strength of 3.6% of the total population, was proportionately the largest in Europe. The new system replaced coercive recruiting, which in turn replaced the hiring of undependable and expensive mercenary forces. It allowed the army to double from 38,000 to 76,000, making it the fourth largest in Europe, and it linked the local population more closely to the royal government. The system demonstrated its worth in a number of conflicts such as the Great Northern War, in which the tiny Brandenburg was able to annex Pommerania from Sweden, and even more decisively, under Frederick I. By fielding a more professional, standing army, Prussia was able to punch way, way above its weight in military - sucessfully warring her former hegemon Austria in numerous successful conflicts which expanded Prussian influence and territory. Despite this, the system was gradually replaced after the abolition of serfdom in 1807 and the rise of volunteer armies made it obselete. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KANTONE_HELP">
			<Text>Yields 5 additional experience per finished social policy tree. While producing a military unit, the Kantone also grants a slight culture and production boost.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KANTONE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Kantone reinforces the Soldier-Kings cycle of policies and warfare by granting bonus culture when training a unit and extra experience for finished policy trees. The Kantone allows you to ignore culture buildings to continue unit production, without losing out on culture generation. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_US_PRUSSIA_DESC">
			<Text>Kingdom of Brandenburg-Prussia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_US_PRUSSIA_SHORT_DESC">
			<Text>Brandenburg-Prussia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_US_PRUSSIA_ADJECTIVE">
			<Text>Prussian</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_US_BRANDENBURG_PRUSSIA">
			<Text>Proclaim the Kingdom in Prussia</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_US_BRANDENBURG_PRUSSIA_DESC">
			<Text>
				Though the March of Brandenburg is an ancient and noble title, Kings and Emperors have been heard sniggering at our title of 'Margrave'. Luckily, some of the Kingdoms we've conquered have King titles just lying around - by crowning ourselves with one of these titles, we'll finally be accorded the prestige and respect of a King![NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Requirement/Restrictions:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Player must be Brandenburg (Friedrich Wilhelm I)
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must hold at least one foreign [ICON_CAPITAL] Capital
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May only be enacted once per game
				[NEWLINE]Costs:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]{1_Faith} [ICON_GOLD] Gold
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]2 [ICON_MAGISTRATES] Magistrates
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]A [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age begins
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Become known as 'Brandenburg-Prussia'
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Barracks, Armouries and Military Bases yield an additional +50% [ICON_WAR] Experience to trained units, plus 1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_US_BRANDENBURG_PRUSSIA_DESC_ENACTED">
			<Text>
				Though the March of Brandenburg is an ancient and noble title, Kings and Emperors have been heard sniggering at our title of 'Margrave'. Luckily, some of the Kingdoms we've conquered have King titles just lying around - by crowning ourselves with one of these titles, we'll finally be accorded the prestige and respect of a King![NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]A [ICON_GOLDEN_AGE] Golden Age begins
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Become known as 'Brandenburg-Prussia'
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Kantones, Armouries and Military Bases yield an additional +50% [ICON_WAR] Experience to trained units, plus 1 [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_US_BRANDENBURG_LAWS">
			<Text>Recite the Manual of Regulations for State Officials</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_US_BRANDENBURG_LAWS_DESC">
			<Text>
				Our state officials are responsible for so much of our society - they administer our laws, represent us on the world stage and control our economy. Thus, nomatter how good we make these laws, foreign deals and economic regulations, they will always be beholden to the whims of these few men. By dictating a new manual for how officials should behave, administering our fine nation should be much easier.[NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Requirement/Restrictions:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Player must be the Brandenburg (Friedrich Wilhelm I)
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Must hold at least two foreign [ICON_CAPITAL] Capitals
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]May only be enacted once per game
				[NEWLINE]Costs:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]{1_Num} [ICON_CULTURE] Culture
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Courthouses are built [ICON_PRODUCTION] 50% faster
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive 2 magistrates.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_DECISIONS_US_BRANDENBURG_LAWS_ENACTED_DESC">
			<Text>
				Our state officials are responsible for so much of our society - they administer our laws, represent us on the world stage and control our economy. Thus, nomatter how good we make these laws, foreign deals and economic regulations, they will always be beholden to the whims of these few men. By dictating a new manual for how officials should behave, administering our fine nation should be much easier.[NEWLINE]
				[NEWLINE]Rewards:
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Courthouses are built [ICON_PRODUCTION] 50% faster
				[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET]Receive 2 magistrates.
			</Text>
		</Row>
			<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_WORLD_EVENT_US_BRANDENBURG_PRUSSIA">
				<Text>Frederick William Declares Himself King in Prussia!</Text>
			</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_LEGISLATURE_NAME_CIVILIZATION_US_BRANDENBURG">
			<Text>Großer Generalstab</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_JFD_HEAD_OF_GOVERNMENT_TITLE_CIVILIZATION_US_BRANDENBURG">
			<Text>Generalfeldmarschall</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>